
    The Daily Dispatch: November 1, 1860.  [Electronic resource]   Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant   Creation of machine-readable version:  digital Divide Data  Creation of digital images:  digital Divide Data  Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup:  digital Divide Data    ca. XXX kilobytes   University of Richmond Library  Richmond, Virginia  Nw_richtimesd_018_105  
© 2004 by the University of Richmond.  
Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/       
Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project    page images have been included from the microfilm version.  images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical Resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135.  Ddd note: shipped: 2004_08_19_ddd_url.      The Daily Dispatch: November 1, 1860.  Richmond Dispatch          
   4 pages.   by Cowardin &amp; Hammersley.  Richmond  November 1, 186018.105       microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi. : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm.        
Imls Civil War Newspaper Project.    
the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access.         Library of Congress subject Headings,  21st edition, 1998       1860    English  Latin  French   
  
 
 
Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond       August, 2004   Corrector  Andrew Rouner, of the University of Richmond Library   
Text validation, generation of authority lists, final tagging.     
   
 
 


 Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume 18, Number 105, page 1.      Daily Dispatch    Vol. Xviii — no.105  Richmond, Va.  Thursday, November 1, 1860 Price one cent   
 
Richmond Dispatch by Cowardin &amp; Hammersley. 


the Daily Dispatch is served to subscribers at six and A Quarter cents per week, payable to the Carrier weekly.

Price for mailing, $4 a year, or $2.50 for six months, in advance. 


the Semi-Weekly Dispatch is issued every Tuesday and Friday at $2.00, in advance. 


the Weekly Dispatch is issued every Friday, and mailed to subscribers at $1 per annum.  
 
Richmond Dispatch 


 
 
Terms of Advertising. 
1 square, 1 day,$0.501 square, 5 days,$1.00 
1 square, 2 days$0.751 square, 5 days,$1.75 
1 square 3 days$1.001 square, 12 days,$3.00 
1 square 4 days$1.361 square, 1 month,$5.00  


Larger advertisements in exact properties. 


Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged 50 cents per square of eight lines for the first insertion, and 25 cents for each continuance     
 
 
 
Thursday Morning......nov.

1, 1860. 
 
Correspondence of the Richmond Dispatch. 
 
 


Greenville--census returns--educational institutions --Theological Seminary--Virginia Students--Court --political Speaking--"minute men"--curious Relic --Sunday School--Governor's Proclamation, &amp;c.,&amp;c.   


Greenville, S. C.,Oct. 29, 1860.  


 This beautiful town, as many of your readers are aware, is, in point of population, the third place of importance in South Carolina.

It is situated in the North western part of the State, in sight of the Blue Ridge mountains, and has long been a place of summer resort for the inhabitants of the sea — board.

The States of North Carolina, Tennessee, and Georgia, are but a few miles distant.

It is accessible by railroad, via Columbia, to all portions of country East of the Blue Ridge, and will shortly be brought into an intimate section with the West, by the Rabun Gap Railroad, now in process of construction.-- There is already a daily stage line to Greenville.

Tennessee, on the East Tennessee and Virginia Railroad, a distance of one hundred miles.  


 The census returns, which are being completed, show that the population of the town proper, is between 2,900 and 3,000, leaving out a few families whose census has not yet been taken.

The value of real estate and personal property is $5,400,000; church property $64, Within the corporation limits there are  dwellings.

During the past year there have been but 43 deaths.  


Greenville is highly favored for its educational privileges.

Some 100 students are in attendance on the lectures at Furman University, one of the first literary institutions of the South.

The flourishing Female Institute has about 80 pupils.  


 Here, too, is located the Southern Baptist Theological Seminary.

The second session of the Seminary opened on the first of this month.

Though so recently established, there still matriculates, 9 of whom are from Virginia, as follows: J. R. Bagby, of Powhatan; J. F. Deans, of Norfolk county; J. S. Brown, of Ambers; P. H. Cowherd, of Louisa; J. B. Taylor, Jr., of Richmond city; J. F. Hardwicke of Pennsylvania; C. H. Ryland, of King &amp; Queen; H. E. Hatcher, of Bedford, and W. D. Harkes, of Buckingham.

Two of the Professors are widely known and loved in Virginia, viz; Rev. Messrs. B. Manly, Jr., D. D.,  of Richmond, and J. A. Broadus, D. D., formerly of Charlottesville.

The first named gentleman is Professor of "Biblical Introduction and Interpretation of the Old Testament." Dr. Broadus is Professor of "Interpretation of the New Testament, and Preparation and Delivery of Sermons." The chair of "Systematic Theology, Polemic Theology and A Apologetics," is ably filled by Rev. J. P. Boyce, D. D. Rev. Dr. Wm. Williams, formerly of Georgia, is Professor of "Church History, Church Government and Pastoral ." Besides the Library of the Seminary, the private libraries of the Professors amount to over 10,000 volumes.  


 The regular term of the Court of Common Pleas for this District is now in session, his Honor D. L. Wardlaw presiding.

The only case of much interest on the issue docket, is that involving the validity of the will of Lawrence Brock, deceased.

Last Tuesday, during the morning recess of Court, Hons.

Messrs. Orr and Ashmore addressed the people of the District on the great political questions of the day.  


 C. L. Orr said that he had no hope of the defeat of Lincoln for the Presidency; that, in the event of his election, the South could not consistently with honor and safety remain in the Union.

He would counsel no hasty action on the part of the State.

South Carolina should not withdraw alone.

His opinion was that Commissioners should be appointed to go to and consult with other States, and ascertain the course they intended to pursue under the circumstances, so that there might be convert of action.  


 Col. Ashmore traced Lincoln's political character for the last twenty years, and showed conclusively that Lincoln recognized and practiced the "higher law" doctrine of the Abolition party.

The prime object of the Republican party was nothing less than the entire extinction of the peculiar institution of the Southern States.

The South should put herself into position for resistance, and when the time for resistance comes, she should resist even unto death.  


 Steps are being taken here, as, indeed, in many portions of the State, for the organization of a company of "minute men."  


 A rare curiosity was shown to me on yesterday, by Mr. Lanneau, an artist, of Greenville.

It was an original portrait of General Washington, taken in the General's camp by a German artist, on the back of his knapsack.

The painting, though of course a rude and somewhat imperfect one, is very much like Sterling's celebrated painting of Washington.  


 Your religious readers will be interested to know that one of the largest Sabbath schools in the State flourishes here, in connection with the Baptist Church.

It numbers between two and three hundred scholars, and is under the superintendence of C. J. Elford, a prominent lawyer of this section.   
 
Correspondence of the Richmond Dispatch.Storm in Southwestern Virginia.  Lynchburg, Oct. 31.  


 We have been visited with very heavy rains during the past two or three days. In the mountains west of this place the rain has fallen in torrents, resulting in serious damage to the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad.

On Pea Creek Mountain, 12 miles west of  Central Depot, two bridges have been washed away.-- Other washes of minor importance have also taken place.

This morning a train arrived here from the west, being the first since day before yesterday, and this made no connection west of Newbern.  


 [It will be seen by a telegraphic dispatch from our correspondent, in our telegraph column, that the damage is much greater than estimated in the above letter.]   
 
Another royal marriage. 


 --The London Court Journal, has announced the coming betrothal of her Majesty's second daughter, the Princess Alice, to Prince Louis, of Hesse Darmstadt, a nephew of the reigning Grand Duke.

This union is only to be noted in a political sense, in as much as it will cement still more strongly the close alliance already existing between the royal families of Great Britain and Prussia, the bridegroom elect being, through his mother, cousin German to the King and to the Prince Regent of the latter Kingdom.

Hesse Darmstadt is by no means the smallest of the many German principalities.

Its area is 3,760 square miles; the population, eight years since, numbered 854,000; the army upwards of 10,000 men; the chief cities are Darmstadt and Mayence; the chief rivers the Rhine and the Neckar.

The personal qualifications of this young couple belong to the realm of gossip, which we do not desire to aid in extending beyond the enormous limits that it has recently attained.

But we may add that if in years -- 23 and 18 -- the pair will be fairly mated, so also is the match a suitable one in another respect.

We should scarcely care to see the fortunes of a daughter of England linked with those of Absolutism.

Hesse Darmstadt is a constitutional monarchy.--N. Y. Albion.   
 
The Battle of Lake Erie. 


 -- Bancroft is writing for the New York Ledger an account of "Oliver Hazard Perry and the Battle of Lake Erie." The number for this week recounts the events of the contest previous to Perry's leaving the Lawrence, when "the shrieks of the wounded and the crash of timbers shattered by cannon balls, were still heard; but its own fire grew fainter and fainter; one gun after another was dismounted.--Death had the mastery: the carnage was unparalleled in naval warfare; more than four-fifths of the effective officers and men on board were killed or disabled by wounds; the deck, in spite of the layer of sand, was slippery with blood, which ran down the sides of the ship the wounded and the dead lay thickly strewn everywhere around.

To fire the last gun, Perry himself assisted.

At last every gun in the ship's battery on the enemy's side was dismounted, every brace and bowline was shot away; the vessel became unmanageable, in spite of the zeal of the commander and the great exertions of the Sailing Master.

And still Perry did not despair, but had an eye which could look through the cloud. "   
 
Utah. 


 --Advices from Utah are to October 5. Hon. W. H. Hooper, delegate to Congress, accompanied by his wife, had left Salt Lake City for Washington, and with him had departed the last of the Mormon missionaries for the States and Europe.

Among the missionaries were three of the "Twelve Apostles" -- Orson Pratt, Erastus Snow, and George Q. Cannon -- the first two destined for the States, and the last for England.

Five of the Twelve are now absent among the "Gentiles," working for the cause of Mormonism.

An Agricultural Fair had been held at Provo, which had been attended with considerable success, and another was in progress in Salt Lake City.

More Indian hostilities are reported in the northern part of the Territory.

A party of emigrants, numbering about twenty, had been attacked, and had lost all their wagons and stock before assistance could reach them.

The party had arrived at Salt Lake City, under escort of United States troops, in a destitute condition.   
 
Killed. 


 --James Brooks, baggage master on the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad, was killed near Murfreesboro', Tenn., on the 26th ult. He was standing on the top of a car as the train passed beneath a bridge, when his head struck the lower beam of the bridge, and he was instantly killed.    
 
Fast life in New York. 


 During the past week the police have had in charge several important swindling cases in New York, which involve the loss of several thousands of dollars, but as yet have only succeeded in arresting one of the alleged operators, who, it seems, has succeeded in obtaining about five thousand dollars from a respectable house in Pine street. The alleged party accused of the swindle is a young man named Wm. Hurry, Jr., note broker.

It seems that he is charged by the firm of Quick &amp; L'Hommedien, dealers in mercantile notes and foreign exchange, with having, on Friday last, called upon them — having previously done business with them — and inquired if they had an $8,000 note that they wanted to sell, remarking that he could dispose of a note of the said amount, as he had a customer in waiting.  


 Mr. L'Hommedien replied that he had, and gave Hurry an $8,000 note.

Hurry, it is alleged, took it, and, saying he would return in about twenty minutes, left the office.

He, however, failed to return; and it is alleged that, after disposing of the note, he procured a draft on the Bank of the Republic for the full amount, proceeded direct to the bank, drew the amount in cash, and left.

His not returning created some little suspicion on the part of Messrs.Quick &amp; L'Hommedien, and on the following day, not being able to ascertain Hurry's whereabouts, they proceeded before Justice Welsh, where a complaint was made against him.  


 Hurry, the same afternoon, from his own story, finding himself the holder of this large sum of money, concluded to visit some of our leading gambling saloons and try his luck at the game of faro.

His first step was to dive into the establishment corner of Broadway and Fulton street, where a day game is always kept going, and after betting several times he lost about $3,000. He then took a look into a sporting house in Ann street, where, after passing an hour, he lost $200. In company with a friend, he then proceeded to a first class restaurant, and, after enjoying a costly supper, started out again for the gambling table.

It being early in the evening, a short visit was made to the sweat — board kept at the corner of Broadway and Prince street, where he was so fortunate as to win $1,000. Thinking that he had done pretty well, be concluded to try another house, and accordingly made a stop at an establishment corner of Prince and Mercer streets, where, at the game of faro, he lost $1,400.  


 Hurry, on Saturday evening, again sallied forth on a visit to his old haunts, visiting a gambling house, corner of Twelfth street and Broadway, where they soon relieved him of five hundred dollars, and at another, corner of Broadway and Eighth street, he lost the like amount.

Sunday night he again made a tour around town, visiting a place on Broadway, where he was fortunate in winning about one thousand five hundred dollars. He also visited another of the gambling halls, where he remained until near 4 o'clock Monday morning, gaining about five hundred dollars.  


 On Monday Mr. L'Hommedien called upon Mr. Chris. V. Hogan.

of the detective force, and made him acquainted with the facts, and requested him to work up the case, and if possible to arrest Hurry.

Mr. Hogan accordingly set to work, and, ascertaining that Mr. Hurry had been a visitor at the above places, concluded that he had an accomplice with him.--He succeeded in finding a beautiful team that the young gentleman had obtained, with a view of sporting about in, and finally traced him to the above hotel, where he arrested him yesterday afternoon.

Hurry, when confronted by the detective seemed greatly surprised, believing that he had evaded all pursuit of the officers.

He was taken to the police head-quarters.

About four thousand dollars of the money has been recovered by the officer.--Hurry is about twenty-eight years age, and is very respectably connected.-- New York Paper   
 
Proposed American Military visit to England. 


 --Company E, of the Ninth Regiment of New York, has raised $10,000 towards $30,000, the sum necessary to carry them to England and back.

The company authorized a letter to be written to Lord Palmerston, asking if an American volunteer company bearing arms would be permitted to land in England, and to this letter the following reply has been received:  
   10 Downing St.,London, Oct. 12, 1860. Sir  


 --I have the honor to acknowledge, by desire of Lord Palmerston, the receipt of your communication of the 31st August last.  


 Lord Palmerston directs me, in reply, to inform you that her Majesty's government, as well as the whole British nation, would feel very great pleasure at a friendly visit from any portion of the people of the United States, but that it would not be consistent with the laws of the United Kingdom that a body of armed men, organized as a military body, and not being subjects of the British Sovereign, should land in the United Kingdom and move about therein.  


 Lord Palmerston, however, would remark that if any of the member of the corps which you mention were to come over to England in the summer of next year, bringing with them their rifles, for the purpose of entering into competition at the annual rifle shooting meeting, there can be no doubt that they would be most heartily welcomed.

I have the honor to be, sir, your most obedient servant.   Evelyn  Ashley. J. B. Coppinger, Adjutant Ninth Reg't.    
 
Gen. Houston and Mexico. 


 --A letter from Texas, written by a Virginia officer of the K. G. C.'s to the Norfolk Argus, says that organization is laboring under unexpected difficulties effecting their plans, which, however, they expect to overcome.

He adds:   


Gen. Houston, with whom Gen. Bickley and myself had a conference this morning, not only assured us, but he promised the people of San Antonio, last week, in a public speech, that he should again take the held and cross the Rio Grande with the largest possible force of Texans and other volunteers against Vera Cruz.-- Affairs on the orders in this State, in Mexico and throughout the South, are certainly assuming a critical position, and you need not be surprised to learn at any time within the next six weeks, or two months, that soldiers will swarming on both banks of the Rio Grande, struggling for the country which furnishes the only outlet to the institutions of the South.    
 
Smoke from Gas-Lights. 


 --It is pretty generally supposed that the smoking of ceilings is occasioned by impurity  the gas; whereas, in this case, there is no ection between the deposition of soot and the quality of the gas. The evil ar there from the flame being raised so high that some of its forked points give out smoke, or more frequently from a careless mode of lighting.

If, when lighting the lamps, the stop cock be opened suddenly, and a burst of gas be permitted to escape before the match be applied to light it, then a strong puff follows the lighting of each burner, and a cloud of smoke rises to the ceiling.

This, in many houses and shops, is repeated daily, and the inevitable consequence is a blackened ceiling.

In some houses, the glasses are taken off and wiped every day, and before they are put on again the match is applied to the tip of the burner, and the stop-cock cautiously opened, so that no more gas escapes than is sufficient to make a ring of blue flame; the glasses being then put on quite straight, the stop-cocks are gently turned, until the flames stand out at three inches high.

When this mode of management is pursued, few chimney-glasses will be broken, and the ceilings will not be blackened for years.   
 
Over-worked women. 


 --An over — worked woman is always a sad sight; sadder a great deal than an over-worked man, because she is so much more fertile in capacities of suffering than a man. She has so many varieties of headache, sometimes as if Joel were driving the nail that killed Sisera into her temples, sometimes letting her work fall with half her brain, while the other half throbs as if it would go to pieces; sometimes tightening round the brows as if her cap bands were Luke's iron crown; and then her neuralgias, and her back aches, and her fits of depression, in which she thinks she is nothing, and less than nothing, and those paroxysms which men speak slightingly of as hysterical convulsions, that is all, only not commonly fatal ones; so many trials which belong to her fine and mobile structure, that she is always entitled to pity when she is placed in conditions which develops her nervous tendencies.--   Dr. O. W. Helmes.   
 
The Meteorological Congress. 


 --The departure of Lt. Maury for England, has been announced.

M. Quetelet, the perpetual secretary of the French Academy, says that the enterprise proposed by the United States, under the direction of Lieut. Maury, of a Meteorological Congress, will be accomplished on a large scale.

Very distinguished men are disposed to attend.

He is about to visit England on account of it. The general Congress of Vienna has charged him with the duty of making up a general programme for meteorological observations all over the globe.

Unity of views is necessary in these observations.

Thirty nations have assented to it, and several are already at work.

Science has thus accomplished a confederation of nations which politics has attempted in vain.   
 
 


 It is perfectly natural that when men kick the bucket they should turn pail.    
 
The election Fraud in Philadelphia--Conviction. 
 
 


 -- the conviction of Wm. Birely, a Judge of Elections, in Philadelphia, on Tuesday, of forging the returns so as to defeat Lehman, the Democratic candidate for Congress, was published yesterday.

The Bulletin, of Tuesday afternoon, says:    


 The case was concluded yesterday.

At half past 2 o'clock the jury took charge of the case and retired, and at three o'clock no verdict having been agreed upon, the Court adjourned.

For a long while after the Court adjourned the immense crowd, which had been in attendance during the day, lingered in the neighborhood of the State-House, discussing the probable issue of the trial.

Bets were made as to the verdict, and the length of punishment to be meted out in case of a conviction.

During the evening numerous rumors prevailed in the lower part of the city in regard to the rendition of a verdict.

This, of course, was not true, but credit was given to the story from the fact that Mr. Birely had been arrested at seven o'clock, and locked up in the Fifth Ward Station-House until near ten o'clock, when Mr. Cassidy succeeded in procuring his release by an order from Judge Thompson.--The difficulty originated from the fact that the officers of Court made a mistake as to the bail of the defendant.

The individual who was at first taken to be the one was considered worthless, and hence the warrant of arrest.

It was subsequently discovered that the bail was perfectly reliable.  


 This morning the Court-room was again densely packed, and when the jury appeared and took their places in the box the excitement reached fever heat.

As Mr. Sharkie was about to lake the verdict, Mr. Brewster, one of the counsel for the defendant, arose and said on behalf of Mr. Birely, he objected to the reception of a sealed verdict.

The Act of Assembly made this punishment infamous, and upon the grade of punishment this was a felony, and consequently there could be no separation of a jury without the consent of the prisoner's counsel.

Mr. Brewster asked the Judge to make a note of their objection.--The verdict was then taken.

It was "guilty."  


 Mr. Brewster then asked the Court to defer action on the verdict until Saturday, and in the mean while if there was any question as to the bail, it might be increased to any amount.

Judge Thompson said that under the peculiar circumstances of this case, he could not take bail.    
 
Dixie. 


 --The most famous thing now in America is "Dixie." The forests of Arostook and the gulches of California are equally familiar with its jingle; by the shores of the Chesapeake, and by the pictured rocks of Lake Superior it soundeth.

An amusing anecdote is told, which happened lately at a St. Louis theatre:   


 The orchestra played "Dixie," when the curtain rose and the play began.

But the audience would not listen.

The cry of "Dixie" ran through the house from pit to gallery, completely drowning the voice of the actor.--He made several ineffectual attempts to be heard, and left the stage.

The old manager appeared, flushed with anger, and, in an excited voice, exclaimed: "Gentlemen, what means all this ill-mannered confusion !-- What do you want?" Immediately a hundred voices cried out "Dixie." "Well, you can't have it. "You've had 'Dixie' once tonight, and you'll have 'Dixie' no more." He retired to the green-room, and the actor again appeared.

But it was no use. A deafening shout for "Dixie" met him from the audience, and, after stammering and stuttering for a few moments, he left the stage.

The curtain dropped, the orchestra played "Dixie," and the play progressed without further interruption.    
 
The world Does move. 


 --Here are a few curious points in the news by the Asia:   


 Universal suffrage is given to the people of Naples.

They are requested to vote by ballot, yea or nay, upon the question of a union of all the Italian States, with Victor Emanuel as constitutional king.  


 A serious proposition is made to the Pope to sell out or commute.

An attempt is being made to carry out About's idea of a palace and a garden for the Holy Father.  


 One of the old Bourbons writes to the London Times and claims the throne of Spain.

A Bourbon appealing to the world through a free press is one of the wonders of the age.  


 Garibaldi takes a railway train as a conveyance to the scene where he fights against another Bourbon, and opposes a Colt's revolver to the old-fashioned stiletto.    
 
Cleaning the Bottoms of Iron ships. 


 --The expense and inconvenience which attend the taking out of ships on every occasion when the bottom becomes foul, gives value to any contrivance by which the process of cleaning can be performed while the vessel is afloat, in harbor or at sea. The apparatus which has lately been brought forward to meet the want so long felt, consists of eight rectangular pieces of cork wood, eighteen inches long, ten inches wide, and seven inches deep.

Each of these corks is covered with a board, fastened with iron bands, on the top of which are fixed nine knives, which move, six parallel and three at right angles, while the machine is in motion.

The boxes are hauled under the ship's keel, and are worked by five or six men. By this means a vessel whose keel is one hundred and eighteen feet can be thoroughly cleaned of barnacles in half a day. The apparatus has been practically tasted in Amsterdam, and found to work well.

By the use of mechanical power, it could, no doubt, be rendered more effective.   
 
Billiard Tournament. 


 --The Billiard Tournament continues to excite great interest, and the room of Mr. Lynch, in Fourteenth street, where it is held, is daily crowded to its utmost capacity by gentlemen who feel an interest in the game.

The games yesterday were first between Messrs. Kavanagh and White.--Mr. White was beaten by 132 points, the highest run in the game being 53, which was made by Mr. Kavanagh, who is a cool and graceful player.

The second game, between Messrs. Tieman and Lynch, was one of the closest and best con of any thus far played.

Mr. Lynch led off in some splendid runs, ranging from 74 to 16, but towards the close of the game his hasty but good-- natured antagonist was shined up, and when the game was even within a single point, made a splendid run of 85, and was proclaimed the victor.

On Wednesday Messrs. Kavanagh and Tieman will play, and as the prize cue undoubtedly lies between them, much interest is felt as to the result,--On Thursday Mr. Phelan will play a game of 500 points with the winner.-- N. Y. Letter.   
 
Negro Suffrage to be Tested in Congress. 


 --In the Sixteenth Congressional District of Ohio, Cutler, Republican, was elected by sixty-four majority over Jewett, Democrat.

In a large number of precincts negroes voted the Republican ticket, and in consequence the Democratic candidate was defeated.

The Marietta Republican gives the number of negroes voting in several precincts.--enough to decide the result — and intimates that the election will be contested.

As the Constitution of the State provides that no one shall vote if he is not a white citizen of the United States, all persons of negro blood are disqualified from voting.

This is a plain proposition, which the House of Representatives affirmed, in the contested election case of Vallandigbam vs. Campbell, two years ago!   
 
Railroad accident. 


 --On Tuesday last, the up freight train on the Norfolk and Petersburg Railroad, with a passenger car attached, ran off the track about six miles this side of Suffolk, and two or three cars were precipitated down an embankment.

Ex-Gov. Wise and several other gentlemen were aboard, on their way to a barbecue in Isle of Wight county, but no person sustained any damage.

The momentum was so great at the time of the occurrence, that the train ran 800 yards after the breakage took place, striking 300 of the splice joints and tending some of the heavy iron rails.

Fortunately, the coupling broke and the passenger can was not injured.

The accident caused damage to the extent of about $500.   
 
Supposed recovery of the body of Mrs. Lumsden. 


 --The Chicago Press notices the recovery of a number of bodies supposed to be victims of the Lady Elgin disaster.

One of these bodies is believed to be that of Mrs. Lumsden, wife of the late Col. F. A. Lumsden, of New Orleans.

The description of this body is as follows:  


 Five feet two to four inches in height.

On the body a plain cotton skirt and a portion of a chemise.

On the fingers of the left hand were several diamond rings.

Upper teeth all gone, as if they had been a false set and had been lost out. The second body is believed to be that of Mrs. Wm. Garth, of Paris, Ky. , for the recovery of which a reward of $1,000 was offered by the relatives of the family.    
 
Burned to death. 


 --Two children of Ed. Wooster, of Falls Village, Conn., were burned to death last week.

The mother left the house for a short time, and locked in three children, who, while playing, accidentally set the house on fire, and became so frightened that they went to bed in a chamber ever the fire.

When the fire was discovered one end of the house was mostly burnt, and one of the children was found dead and a second so badly burned that it died the same evening.   
 
Homespun. 


 -- One of the features of a late fair at Atlanta, Ga, was the appearance on the grounds of twentypupils of a school with them teachers, all clothed in Georgia homespun.    
 
The Captor of Guadalajara --Sufferings of the Besiegers. 


 --The city of Guadalajara, Mexico, held by Miramon's forces, was captured on the 11th, by the Liberal party.

The N. O. Picayune says:   


 Guadalajara is the second city of the Republic, rich and prosperous, and has been defended with great obstinacy.

It has long been, moreover, the principal stronghold of the reactionists in that part of the Republic, and its capture is believed to open the way direct to the capital.

Our files abound in most touching letters from the besieged city, from which it would appear, as might indeed have been expected, that the suffering of the people was very great.

We learn, indeed, from a letter of General Ortega himself, that on the 1st inst.the suffering had become so great that the fire upon the city was suspended for a space of three hours, that women and children might leave the town.

How many actually left we are not informed, but it would appear that the number was small.

In all probability the poor people knew not what to do, and there for the space of at least twenty days, they remained huddled together in the centre of the town, farthest removed from the shots of the besiegers, suffering each hour discomforts and anxieties which must have been worse than death itself.   


The correspondent of the N. O. Delta, writing on the 15th inst.from the city of Mexico, gives the following additional particulars of the suffering of the people at Guadalajara:   


 A deed of horror has come to my knowledge which surpasses anything of the kind that has ever been heard of: " A poor woman, with the view of favoring the escape of her husband, who had been forcibly taken as a soldier, went to the quarter where he was confined, taking with her some female apparel in which to disguise him. The unfortunate pair were discovered while endeavoring to make their escape, and three hundred lashes were ordered by the Miramon commandant to be administered to each.

The poor woman was enceinte; she received the three hundred lashes, gave birth to a child, and died in the most excruciating agonies."   
 
The Cold Dollars. 


 --As much has recently been said in public prints about the recoining of gold dollars into pieces of larger denominations, it may be stated that orders have been issued from the Treasury Department, in two special cases only, and then a representation that the smaller coins occasion much inconvenience in the receipts and disbursements; for no sooner are they paid out than they are again returned in business transactions, there appearing to be a redundancy of them among the commercial classes.

The Assistant Treasurer at New York has, for the greater facility in counting, authorized to have about two millions of them re-coined, and the Assistant Treasurer at St. Louis, upward of one hundred and fifty thousand, for similar reasons.

This re-coinage, however, applies to the original or earlier issues, which, it is known, are smaller in circumference and thicker than the latter and superior coin.

Of the former, there are now nine millions, and of the latter six, millions in circulation.   
 
 


Patents were issued last week to J. W. Barnes, of Murfreesboro', N. C., for improvement in attaching horses to two-wheeled vehicles; Wm. A. Dudley, of Petersburg, Va., for improvement in apparatus for removing calculi; Murdock Murchison, of Denmark, Tenn., for improvement in cotton presses; N. A. Patterson, of Kingston, Tenn., for improvement in cotton gins; Michael E. Ruderal, of Shelby, N. C., for improvement in machines for cutting stalks; N. B. Webster and Robert W. Young, of Portsmouth, Va., for improvement in the prevention of the incrustation of steam boilers, and Richard B. Wright, of Norfolk, Va., for improved ventilator for railroad cars.   
 
Marine disaster. 


 --A mackerel schooner, from Gloucester, Mass., was recently rundown by a steamer in a dense fog, near Cape Canso, and, after floating two days waterlogged, seven of the crew were washed overboard.

The remaining nine took a boat, which capsized, and two men were devoured by sharks.

The remaining seven recovered the boat, and two more died of exhaustion.

The survivors were rescued by a Portuguese vessel and carried to St. Domingo, where the American Consul treated them kindly and would send them home.

No names are given.   
 
Large receipts of Silver in England. 


 --The steamer Farmanian, arrived at Southampton, England, on the 1st of the month, had on board $5,662,000 in silver from the West Indies and Mexico.

It was contained in 2,168 packages, was landed in seven hours, and deposited in 36 railway wagons, drawn by two engines.

At London it was transferred to 36 street wagons, and was drawn by upwards of one hundred horses.

It took seven hours to receive the whole in the vaults of the Bank of England.   
 
The Turf. 


 --The races at the New Market Course, near Petersburg, Va., commenced Tuesday.

The first race was a sweepstakes for three year olds, two mile heats, $200 entrance; entries, John Belcher's b. c. Waccamaw by Red Eye, O. P. Hare's c. f. Tupsy by Boston, and F. M. Hall's c. c. Eugene by Revenue.

It was won by Eugene — time 3:58; 4:05. The second race was a match between O. P. Hare's b. c. Builion by Revenue, and Gen. Green's b. c. Albion, for $500 aside, two mile heats.

It was won by Bullion in 4:03; 4:07.   
 
Sentenced for life. 


 --In the Court of Over and Terminer at New York, Monday, Adam Jaeger, a tailor, convicted of the murder of Wm. Pebble, was sentenced to imprisonment for life.

Edward Hagdon, for the murder of John Cunningham, shared the same rate.

Both crimes were committed in quarrels, and resulted from the practice of carrying the knife.

Patrick Hennessy, fifty years of age, was sentenced to ten years imprisonment for firing his own store in order to obtain the insurance.   
 
Awful accident. 


 --On Saturday last John Hardon, the proprietor of the "Morgan Steam Saw--Mill," about three miles from Georgetown, Del., was superintending the operations of a circular saw. By some means his foot slipped, throwing him directly in contact with the saw, which passed through his body in a few revolutions, severing the upper half from the lower, and throwing the heart, liver and entrails of the unfortunate man in all directions over the mill.   
 
How to examine eggs. 


 --M. Labiche, a chemist, at Louviers, has found an easy way of discovering whether eggs are sound or not. He makes a solution of chloride of sodium (common salt) of a specific gravity represented by 1,040 (water being 1,000.) If an egg, thrown into this solution, sinks to the bottom, it is fresh enough to be boiled in the shell; it does not sink quite to the bottom, it is still fit to be eaten, but not under that form; and if it swims on the surface, it is decidedly spoilt.   
 
Universal Negro Suffrage. 


 --At the next election in New York, a vote is to be taken upon the question of extending to colored voters the same rights which are now exercised by the whites.

Under the constitution of that State, as at present, the colored voter is required to possess real estate worth $250, to have been three years a citizen of the State, and one year resident in the district where he votes.   
 
Lo, the poor African. 


 --The politicians are making a practical use of Sambo in Philadelphia.

It appears that of the fund contributed to aid the Black Republicans in the Pennsylvania election, $15,000 was collected from the negroes of that city.

The subscription list was headed by a negro lumberman for $1,000, followed by an oysterman and a salt maker of the same complexion for $500 each.   
 
Arrival of the California Express. 


 --The California Pony Express, with San Francisco dates to the 17th, has arrived.

The returns of the Pennsylvania election were anxiously expected.

In the event of the Democrats having been defeated, the Republicans anticipate carrying California. Mr. Baker, United States Senator of Oregon, was stumping that State for Mr. Lincoln.   
 
Heavy suit for damages against Cortina. 


 --We learn from the Rio Grande Sentinel that a civil suit has been brought against the notorious Juan N. Cortina by Robert S. Shears, in which the latter claims $30,000 damages for injuries sustained in being shot and wounded in Brownsville by the Mexican "filibuster," during the troubles on the Rio Grande a year ago.   
 
To be launched. 


 --The ship Virginia Dare will be launched in Baltimore on Saturday next.

Tonnage 900.

The vessel is intended for the line between Richmond and England.   
 
A Tribute to merit 


 --Editors of Dispatch: Mr. Walter C. Freeman, the well known painter of this city, having just finished the thorough painting of the Exchange Hotel, inside and out, under contract with the stockholders, it is but just that they should express their high gratification at the skill and taste displayed by him in executing an extensive a contract, no less than their commendation of him as a faithful workman and reliable gentleman.

The Hotel has been painted in artistic style from basement to attic, and since the conclusion of the job has had the praise of all its friends and patrons coming from the four quarters of the globe, as well as those of the Ballard House, which also received the renovating touch of Mr. Freeman's elastic brushes.

It is deemed but an act of simple justice to him to say to the public that he has proved himself capable of performing the most difficult job (as proved by the above instance,) in a satisfactory and able manner. (*)many Stockholders.     
 
Local matters. 
 
Supreme Court of Appeals--Totty's case. 


 --The application for a writ of habeas corpus  on behalf of William D. Totty, convicted in Judge Lyons' Court of murder in the first degree, and sentenced to be hanged on Saturday next, has been considered by the Court of Appeals, and its judgment was pronounced yesterday.

The application necessarily involved the question as to the constitutionality of the act creating that Court, and the writ prayed for was denied, all the Judges of the Court of Appeals being of opinion that it was within the competency of the General Assembly to create the new Hustings Court, and that the act for that purpose was free from any constitutional objection.   
 
Larceny. 


 --John, a slave, was arraigned before the Mayor yesterday, on a charge of stealing a piece of calico from his master, Joseph Rosenbaum.

As John acknowledged the theft, but little time was occupied in disposing of his case, and he was sentenced to thirty lashes.

The calico was left with Mary Cooper, a free negro woman, living in the basement of Ann Stevenson's house, in "Solitude," and she was punished for receiving the stolen goods.

Virginia Turner and Harriet Hellum, two white women boarding with Ann Stevenson, were also up on the charge of receiving the calico, but the evidence being insufficient, they were set at liberty.   
 
The Agricultural Fair. 


 --The receipts for tickets at the late Agricultural Fair, amounted to about $5,400. We have not ascertained the total amount of tickets and certificates of membership, but suppose it will not fail short of $10,000. Thus we have a proof of the successful result of the exhibition.

It has exceeded that of any previous Fair, and the anticipation of its friends have been fully realized.

If there were any who were deterred from coming, through expectations of a failure, we hope that they will not be thus influenced hereafter.  


 The meeting of the Executive Committee of the Central Society, announced for yesterday, did not take place.   
 
Consecration. 


 --The Chapel of St. Paul's, on 5th, between Canal and Byrd streets, was consecrated yesterday, according to the beautiful ritual of the Episcopal Church.

The venerable Bishop Meade officiated, assisted by several clergymen.

The consecration sermon was preached by the Rev. Mr. Gatewood, rector of the chapel, and the congregation manifested a very deep interest in the words of truth that fell from the speaker's lips.--This chapel, the seats in which are free to all, has been erected through the efforts of the society of St. Paul's Church, and it will, we doubt not, become the means of accomplishing much good.   
 
Owners of Slaves. 


 --It appears from returns in possession of the Auditor of Public Accounts that there are at the present time, in Virginia, 53,456 slave owners over 24 years of age. This is about one-fourth of the entire portion of the population who have arrived at years of maturity.

The statement refutes the oft-repeated assertion of the Northern journals that a comparatively small proportion of the inhabitants of Virginia are interested in the institution of slavery.

The irrepressible conflict will find the Old Dominion ready to defend slavery, in which she is so materially concerned.   
 
Theatre. 


 --Notwithstanding the rain on Tuesday night, the attendance at the Theatre was quite large, and included a good many ladies.

The bright, particular star of the evening, Miss Caroline Richings, sang several charming songs, and played with her usual vivacity.

Mr. Richings performed well, as he always does.

Several new pieces are in preparation, one of which, a pretty domestic sketch entitled the "Household Fairy," will be produced to-night.

The play of "Home, Sweet Home," will also be repeated.

As recreation is necessary to relieve the human mind of its cares, we know of no place we can more highly recommend for the purpose than the Theatre, while Mr. Richings and his accomplished daughter are there.   
 
Thanksgiving day. 


 --In accordance with the rubric of the Episcopal Prayer Book which requires that, where no day of Thanksgiving is appointed by the civil authorities, the first day of November shall be observed by that Church as a Day of Thanksgiving, it will be so observed by the Episcopal Church in this and other States, where no day has been appointed by the Governor.

There will be divine service in this city at St. James' Church.

This day is also appointed by the Presbyterian (O. S.) Synod of Virginia for prayer and fasting.   
 
Topheavy. 


 --John Gorman, the sailor who promised to leave the city two or three days ago, again appeared before the mayor yesterday for drunkenness, and was committed in default of surety.

John H. Singer, who represented that he came from Powhatan county, where he dug wells and fixed water arrangements generally, was up for getting more whiskey aboard than he could conveniently carry.

The Mayor advised him to go back to his water-works, which he promised to do, and departed.   
 
Respite of Totty. 


 -- We are informed that Governor Letcher has granted a respite to Wm. D. Totty, until the 9th of November.

The consideration that the prisoner needed time to prepare for his doom, was sufficient to induce the Executive to consent to an extension of the period for a few days.

Since his sentence, Totty has been visited by Rev. Messrs. Boggs and Duncan, from whose counsel, it is hoped, he will derive the benefit so essential to a man standing on the brink of eternity.   
 
Dangerous occupation. 


 --The men employed in slating the steeple of the new Broad Street Church, were yesterday at work near the top, about 180 feet from the ground.

They have a small scaffolding, which they raise by ropes as they proceed upward, and pursue their occupation at this "dizzy height" with as much unconcern, apparently, as if their feet rested on terra firma.

It requires nerve, however, such as few possess.   
 
The stolen valice. 


 --The negro boy Harrison, charged with stealing A. A. White's valice, at the St. Charles Hotel, was before the Mayor yesterday, when a message came that the wrong darkey had been arrested.

Harrison, who was somewhat surprised at the arrest, declares that he "don't know nuthin' about de bodice," and from all accounts, the negro who pointed him out to the officer made a mistake.   
 
U. S. Prisoners. 


 --The crew of the slaver Storm-King, thirteen in number, captured on the coast of Africa, will be brought to this city in a day or two from Norfolk, to await their trial in the Federal Court.

As the city jail is pretty well filled up, it is probable that the county jail will have to be resorted to for the safe-keeping of these prisoners.   
 
Music. 


 --The Armory Band yesterday went about the streets in two wagons, and entertained the citizens with some very good music.

As there was no placard announcing the "show" or a race to come off, we take it for granted that the Band was giving a concert gratis, for which, in behalf of the public, we return thanks.   
 
Resignation. 


 --Capt. Charles Dimmock has resigned the post of Secretary and Treasurer of the Central Agricultural Society, the duties of which he has discharged to the entire satisfaction of everybody concerned.

By his energy and industry he has contributed much to the success of the Society.   
 
List of Premiums. 


 --We publish to-day the list of premiums awarded by the Virginia Mechanics' Institute announced at the closing exhibition, last night.

The hall will be open to-day, and depositors are requested to remove their articles as soon as possible, as the place is wanted for concerts.   
 
Commissioned. 


 -- M. M. Lipscomb was yesterday commissioned by Gov. Letcher as a 1st Lieutenant in the 19th Regiment, 2d Brigade, 4th Division Virginia Militia. Lieut. Lipscomb has had experience in military matters, and holds himself ready at all times to give the Commonwealth the benefit thereof.   
 
Accident. 


 --Mr. Charles Miller, who was employed in running the steam engine at the Mechanics' Institute, had the middle finger of his left hand cut off by the machine on Tuesday night.   
 
Circuit Court. 


 --The fall term of Judge Meredith's Court will commence to-day.

The most prominent criminal case to be tried during the term is that of Melton, whose sentence was reversed by the Court of Appeals.   
 
Fined 


 -- E. V. Menzie, for making an unlawful assault upon Henry, a stave, the property of John A. Relvin, was yesterday fined $10 by the Mayor.  


 Patrick Woodward, for an assault upon B. Gottlieb, in the First Market, was fined $10.   
 
Political. 


 --A discussion will take place tonight at Metropolitan Hall, between James Lyons and John H. Gilmer, Esqs.

The Bell and Everett party will be addressed in their Club House by Hon. John S. Pendleton, of Culpeper county.   
 
The Code 


 --The revised Code of Virginia, prepared by Col. Munford under the authority of the last Legislature, has been printed, and will, we are informed, be ready for delivery to-day.   
 
Correction. 


 --The embroidered shirt (not skirt, as misprinted,) stolen from the Mechanics Institute on Monday night, was owned by Mrs. Thos. Hiltzheimer.    
 
List of Premiumsawarded at the Seventh Annual exhibitionof theVirginia Mechanics' Institute,which closed on the night of the 31st Oct., 1860. 
 
Class no. 1.--Inventions. 


 To Burger &amp; Bros., for Circular Saw Grinding and Polishing Machine, Gold Medal.  


 To DeBow, for the "Union Press," invented by himself and manufactured by P. Rahm, Silver Medal.  


 To N. L. Babcock, for Breach Loading Rifle, Silver Medal.  


 To Curors' patent Farm Gate, First-Class Diploma.  


 To Wm. H. Tappey, of Petersburg, for improvement in Tobacco Screws, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 2.-- Stoves, Ranges, &amp;c. 


 To A. Snyder, for collection of Stoves, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To F Heffley, for Tin-Ware, &amp;c., Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Chas. D. Yale &amp;Co., for Stoves, &amp;c., First-Class Diploma.  


 To J. W. M. Keil, for Stoves, &amp;c., First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 3--Agricultural Implements.. 


 To Geo. Watt &amp;Co., for Surface Plow, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To P. H. Starke, for Straw and Vegetable Cutter and Sub-soil Plow, Silver Medal.  


 To A. S. Maddox, for Bee Hive, First-Class Diploma.  


 To H. M. Smith, for a Farm Mill, First-Class Diploma.  


 To same, for his Straw Cutter, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Jno. W. Cardwell &amp; Co., for Buck-Eye Reaper, Certificate of Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 4.-- Steam Engines, &amp;c.  


 To Ettenger &amp; Edmond, for Steam Fire Engine, Gold Medal.  


 To Ettenger &amp; Edmond, for Portable Engine, Certificate of Gold Medal.  


 To same, for Caloric Engine, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To J Gilson, of N. Y., for Steam Gauge, First-Class Diploma.  


 To W. M. Keesee, (an apprentice boy,) for Miniature High Pressure Horizontal Steam Engine, Silver Medal.  


 To C. Bradly, for Miniature Vertical Steam Engine, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Register &amp; Webb, of Baltimore, for case of Steam Gauges, Whistles, Oil Cooks, and Globe Valves, exhibited by Messrs. Williams &amp; Elliott, Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 5.-- Sewing Machines.  


 To Wheeler &amp; Wilson's Sewing Machines, Silver Medal.  


 To the Lester Manufacturing Company, for Sewing Machines, First-Class Diploma.  


 To Grover &amp; Baker's Sewing Machines, First Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 6.-- Lithographing, Drawing and Grecian Paintings. 


 To E. Crellen for specimens of Lithographic Drawings, First-Class Diploma.  


 To Hover &amp; Ludwig for specimens of Lithographs, Second-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 7-- Bookbinding. 


 To West &amp; Johnston, Silver Medal.  


 To J. W. Randolph, Certificate of Silver Medal, having received a Sliver Medal at a previous exhibition.   
 
Class no. 8.-- Embroidery on Cambric, Linen, &amp;c. 


 To Miss E. T. Gouldin.

for a worked Skirt and Dress, First-Class Premium, $3.  


 To Mrs. S. E. Child, for Infant's Dress.

Second-Class Premium, $2.  


 To Miss M. Barnes, for Infant's Skirt, Third-Class Premium, $1.   
 
Class no. 9. 


 -- Embroidery on Worsted and Silk.  


 To a Pupil of St. Joseph's Academy, for Silk Embroiders, First-Class Premium, $3.  


 To Miss L Pizzini, for an Ottoman Cover, Second Class Premium, $2.  


 To Mrs. J. C. Vass, for Infant's Skirt, Third-Class Premium, $1.   
 
Class no. 10.-- Worsted Embroidery, Tufted and Braid Work. 


 To Miss Gilliam, for Chair-Cover, First-Class Premium, $3.  


 To Mrs. Anderson, for Chair-Cover, Second-Class Premium, 2.00.  


 To Mrs. E. B. Carter, for Chair-Cover, Third-Class Premium.

1.00.   
 
Class no. 11.-- Worsted and Cotton Crochet Work. 


 To Miss Carter, for Crochet Collar, First-Class Premium, $3.00.  


 To Miss N. R. Roper, for Crochet Trimming, Second Class Premium, 2.00.  


 To Miss L. C. Temple, for eight Mats, Third-Class Premium, 1.00.   
 
Class no. 12.-- Knitting, Netting, Tatting and Tape Work. 


 To Miss Ann Eliza Base, for Tatting Collar, First--Class Premium, $3.00.  


 To Miss R. Yancey, for an Afghan, Second--Class Premium.

2.00.  
 To Mrs. M. F. Harrison, for four pair Knit Hose, Third--Class Premium, 1.00   
 
Class no. 13.-- Lace and transferred Work. 


 To Miss E. A. O'Brien, for a fine Muslin Dollar, First-Class Premium.

$3.  
 To Mrs. E. J. Motley, for a Skirt, Second-Class Premium, 2.00.  


 To Miss Keyser, for an Infant's Skirt, Third-Class Premium, 1.00   
 
Class no. 14.-- Plain Sewing. 


 To Miss M. Rennie, for an Infant's Dress, First--Class Premium, $3.  


 To Mrs. J. C. Burton, for Gent's Shirt, Second--Class Premium.

2.00.   
 
Class no. 15.-- Bead, Shell, Seed, and Burr Work. 


 To Mrs. Thos.

J Evans, for Shell Vase, First--Class Premium, $3.  


 To Mrs. Wm. L. Pendleton, for Frame and Rustic Work, Second--Class Premium, 2.00.  


 To Miss A. Ehrhart, for Book Shelf, made of Beads, Third--Class Premium, 1.00.   
 
Class no. 16.-- Fancy Articles. 


 To Mrs. E. C. Pollard, for a Shuck Hat, $3.  


 To Mrs. M. A. Harrison, of Fairfax, for three Green Osier Ha, 2.00.  


 To C. Bolton, for seven Willow Baskets, 3.00.  


 To Mrs. S. H. Burton, for two vases of Crystallized Flowers, 3.00.  


 To Mrs. Louisa Mitchell, for Paper Flowers, 3.00.  


 To R. D. Sanxay, for beautiful collection of Virgin a Shells, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 17.-- Feather, Wax, Grass, Hair and 


 Paper Work.  


 To Mrs. W. J. Boyd, for a vase of Wax Flowers, First-Class Premium, $3.  


 To Miss Mary Rennie, for Feather Fly-Brush.

Second-Class Premium, 2.00.  


 To Miss N. B. Macfarland, for Hair Chains, Third-Class Premium, 1.00.   
 
Class no. 18-- Domestic Rugs and Carpets. 


 To Mrs. Krebb  for Domestic Rugs, First-Class Premium, $3.  


 To Mrs. Henry Jones, for a Domestic Carpet, Second-Class Premium.

2.00.  
 To Mrs. Dr. T. B. Anderson, for a Carpet, Third-Class Premium, 1.00.   
 
Class no. 19.-- Bed Quilts and Counterpanes. 


 To Mrs. R. A. Mao, for the best Quilt, made on Wheeler &amp; Wilson's sewing machine, $5.  


 To Mrs. Margaret Young, for a white Counterpane, by hand $3.  


 To Mrs. E. J. Hawkins, for second best ditto, $2.   
 
Class no. 20.-- Boots, Shoes,--c. 


 To A. Hill &amp;Co., Certificate of Gold Medal.  


 To John E Beck&amp;Co., of Fredericksburg, for the best Negroes' Brogans and Heavy Shoes, First-Class Diploma.  


 To C. S. Wharton &amp;Co., for Lasts, Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 21.-- Furniture. 


 To E. Gathright, Silver Medal.  


 To J. Edwards Woodbridge, a boy of only sixteen years, for a Bureau, made without instruction.

Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 22. 


 -- Bread, Cakes, Pastry,&amp;c.  


 To Miss E. B. Starke, for Butter Cake, $3.  


 To Mrs. W, Slade, for Sponge Cake, $2.  


 To Mrs. E. B. Sence, for best Bread, $2.  


 To Mrs. Dornio, for second best Bread, $1.   
 
Class no. 23.-- Wines, Cordials, &amp;c. 


 To Mrs. Priddy, for Blackberry Bounce, $3.00.  


 To Mrs. T. B. Stark, for Brandy Peaches, 2.00.  


 To Mrs. L. C. Binford, for Grape Wine, 1.00.   
 
Class.

No. 24.-- Preserves, Fruits, Jellies, &amp;c. 


 To Mrs. J. M. Perdue, for Preserved Peaches, $3.00.  


 To Miss Macon, for Sweetmeats, 2.00.  


 To Mrs. Gaines, for Watermelon Jelly, 1.00.   
 
Class no. 25.-- Pickles, Catsups, Sauces, &amp;c. 


 To Mrs. Ragland, for Yellow Pickle, $3.00.  


 o Mrs. P. W. Harwood, for Pickled Peaches, 2.00.  


 To Mrs. Pilkinton, for Tomato Catsup, 1.00.   
 
Class no. 26.-- Chewing and Smoking Tobacco, 


 Snuff, &amp;c.,  


 To Christian &amp; Lea, for Manufactured Tobacco, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Hart &amp; Hunt.

ditto, First-Class Diploma.  


 To John H. Johnson, for Smoking Tobacco, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To J. Morris &amp;Co., for Snuff, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 27.-- Photographs, Daguerreotypes, Engravings,&amp;c. 


 To G. W. Minnis, for finest display of Photographs, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Smith &amp; Vannerson, for second best Specimens, First-Class Diploma.  


 To Rees&amp;Co., for third best do., Second-Class Diploma.  


 To Albert L. West, for the best Architectural Drawings, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 28.-- Oil Paintings. 


 To Mrs. S. D. Chapin, for the best Oil Painting on exhibition, $3.   
 
Class no. 29.-- Musical Instruments. 


 To E. G. Wright, for Silver Bugle, Silver Medal.  


 To Earnest Gable, for Piano Forte, Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 30.-- Machinists' and other Tools. 


 To L. F. Peyronett, for one case of Machinists' Tools, made by exhibitor, Silver Medal.  


 To Lau &amp;Shuman, for Files, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Boyle &amp; Gamble, for best Circular Saws and also best Tenon and Panel Saws, Silver Medal.  


 To Burger &amp; Bros., for Circular, Rip and Cross-Cutting Saws, Silver Medal.  


 To Berry Grube, for Cross — Cut Saw, Silver Medal.  


 To A. Bridges &amp;Co., of New York, for Punching and Cutting Machines.

Railroad Machinery and Car Findings, Silver Medal.  


 To Jos. R. Anderson &amp;Co., Tredegar Works, for Railroad Chairs, Spikes, &amp;c., Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 31.-- Silver Plating, Copper Work and Locks. 


 To Jas. J. Campbell, for Silver Plating, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To W. W. Snead, for case of Locks, Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 32.-- Carpenter and Coopers' Work. 


 To W. F. Simms, for Mouldings and Newel Post, Silver Medal.  


 To M. M. Hemaworth, for Runlets, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 33.-- Fancy Leather Work. 


 To Miss Calligan, for Leather Frame Work, First-Class Premium, $3.   
 
Class no. 34.-- Millinery. 


 To Madame Fauche, for one case of Bonnets, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 35.-- Worsted Pictures. 


 To a pupil of St. Joseph's Academy, for one Picture, First-Class Premium, $3.   
 
Class no. 36.-- Honey, Butter and Soups. 


 To Mrs. Henry Jones, for Beef Tallow and Turkey Oil Soaps, $3.  


 To Mrs. Mary E. Garnett, for plate of fresh Butter, $3.   
 
Class no. 37.-- Inventions and Machinery not included in other classes. 


 To W. F. Simms, for Jig Saw, Certificate of Silver Medal.   


 To J. R. Aiken, for Knitting Machine, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Beauchamp &amp; Saunders, for Washing Machine, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 38.-- Type-Casting and Mitering Machine. 


 To Walker &amp; Pelouze, for Type Foundry, First-Class Diploma.  


 To same, for Mitering Machine, Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 39.-- Carriages, Buggies, &amp;c. 


 To Geo. A. Ainslie, for Buggy and Carriage, Certificate of Silver Medal.  


 To Williams &amp; Elliott, for Carriage Makers Supplies, First Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 40.-- Flour. 


To H. S. Holliday, for superior Family Flour, First--Class Diploma.  
 
Class no. 41.-- Flour. 


 To Knowles &amp; Walford, of Richmond, for Specimens of Carbonized India Rubber Goods, manufactured by the Hayward Co.

of Massachusetts, First-Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 42.-- Mathematical Instruments. 


 To G. H. Whitescarver, for Calculating Protractor and Engineering Compass and Trigonometrical Calculator, invented by himself, First-Class Diploma.  


 To J. M Lilly, for Engineering Compass, First-Class Diploma.  
 
Class no. 43.-- Woolen Goods. 


 To Manchester Cotton and Woolen Company, for heavy all wool Fulled Cloths, Silver Medal.  


 To Crenshaw Woolen Company, for superior all wool Blankets, Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 44.-- Saddles, &amp;c. 


 C. Johnson, of Jackson, Miss., for Ladies Saddle, admirably made, and of a beautiful pattern, a Silver Medal.   
 
Class no. 45.-- Sewing Machine Work. 


 To Wheeler &amp; Wilson, for superior specimens of work executed on their Machine, First-Class Diploma.  


 Lester Manufacturing Company, to specimens of work on their Machine, Second Class Diploma.   
 
Class no. 46.-- Miscellaneous. 


 To J. K. Sedgwick, a lad 12 years old, for Specimens of Penmanship, Gold Pen.  


 To Robert Elliott, of Hanover, for Paving Bricks.

First-Class Diploma.  


 To Wm Baker &amp;Co, for Fancy Glass Blowing, a Silver Medal.  


 To H. M. Smith, for a Well Fixture, First Class Diploma.  


 To J. Powers, for Pressed Bricks, First Class Diploma.  


 To F. Dusch, for Porter, Ale and Mineral Water, First Class Diploma.  


 To Asa Snyder, for Patent Metallic Window Blinds, burglar and fire proof, First Class Diploma.  


 To Chas. Ford, for display of Preserves, Pickles, Wines, Sauces, &amp;c., First Class Diploma.  


 To Mrs Yarrington, for Rheumatic Mixture, First Class Diploma.     
 
Special notice 
 
Second supply of splendidSilks, Dress Goods, &amp;c.Watkins &amp; Ficklen,Wholesale and Retail Dealers inDry Goods.159 Main street, Richmond. 


 We have selected with great care, and are receiving by various arrivals our second supply of superior  


Dry Goods  
 For Autumn and Winter Sales — among which will  


be found the  


choicest Dress Silks, Velours, Merinos,  


Poplins and Delaines,  


 in all the New Shades and combinations, viz:  
 
 
Fuchsia, Black and Gold,  
Magenta, Black and Fuchsia,  
Solferino, Black and Chintz.

 
Marguerite, Magenta and Gold,  
Mauve, Blue and Gold,  
and  
Peach Bloom, Marguerite and Magenta.

  
 Our collection of these rare and beautiful goods, forms one of the most select and tasteful assortments we have ever offered.  


 In Traveling and Medium Dress Goods we have a fresh and handsome variety.  


 In Embroideries, we have the Large Pointed and Patti Lace Collars, lapping in front.

Also, new Lace Sets; White and Colored Embroidered Hdkfs ; Lace Berthas, &amp;c.  


 In Cloaks and Mantillas, of our own Manufacture — In Velvet, Silk, Black and Colored Cloths, in the Arab, Opera and Zouave style, and other Paris patterns, our assortment is complete, and in prices defy competition. Orders for any style of Wrapping executed at a few hours' notice.  


 New Kid Gloves, in various shades, with scolloped wristlets, a choice novelty.  


 Kid Gauntlets, Figured Velvet tops.  
 Our stock of Super Ingrain, three--Ply and Tapestry Carpets and Rugs, in new designs, has just been replenished, and offers inducements in quality and price.  


 To our supply of  


 White Goods.  
 Irish Linens,  
 Table Damasks,  
 Curtain Goods,  
 Linen Sheetings,  
 Bleaches Long Cloths,  


 Cloths, Cassimeres and Vestings,  


 Satinets, for Factories.  


 Va. Fulled Cloths,  
 Blankets,  


 Brown Cottons,  
 Oznaburgs and  


 Linseys,  


 We invite the especial attention of all cash and prompt credit buyers, assuring the closest and most discriminating that they will find unusual advantages in our terms and prices.  


Wholesale Buyers also supplied on the best terms, and prices guaranteed.  


 Watkins &amp; Ficklen.  


 N. B --A splendid assortment of Dress and Cloak Trimmings, in all the new colors.  


 oc 22--ts W. &amp; F.   
 
Rheumatism!

Rheumatism!! 


Rheumatism Cured by  


 Hampton's Tincture!  


Rheumatism--Captain Canot.  


Rheumatism — Inflammatory, James Smith.  


Rheumatism — Had it 15 years, F. Donnelly.  


Rheumatism — Had it 10 years, Stephen Taylor.  


Rheumatism — Had it 11 years, A. Kitchen.  


Rheumatism — Had it 7 years, Robert Gault.  


Rheumatism — Had it 38 years, E. Bogwell.  


 if you have A Cough,  


 take Hampton's Tincture.  


 if you have Dyspepsia.  


 take Hampton's Tincture.  


 if you have Bronchitis,  


 take Hampton's Tincture.  


 if you are all Weakness,  


 take Hampton's Tincture.  


 if you have Headache,  


 take Hampton's Tincture.  


C all and get pamphlets and see cures.  


 Sold by Purcell, Ladd &amp; Co., Richmond; by Dr. Cooke, Fredericksburg: by all the Druggists in Petersburg: by Mortimer &amp; Mowbray, Baltimore; and by Druggists and Shopkeepers everywhere.

$1 per bottle; six bottles,  


 $5 oc 6--d&amp;cwts   
 
"a Dollar Saved is a Dollar Gained."the people's Savings Bank,ofRichmond, Va. 


Office --11th street, nearly opposite Goddin's Hall.  


 
 
Members: 
R. H. Dibrell,D. Von Groning,J. H. Hatcher,  
R. O. Haskins,J. W. Atkinson,B. Trueheart,  
C. E. Whitlock,L. H. Frayser,R. L. Williams,  
J. L. Apperson,R. T. Taylor,John Blair,  
J. H. Greener,R. A. Mayo,A. Bodeker,  
J. L. Ligon.F. W. Roddey,L. Libby,  
R. M. Stevenson,J. H. Montague,Chas. Talbott,  
B. J. Johnson,W. H. Bowcock,T. M. Alfriend.  
B. H. Nash, H. Dibrell, Pres't;  
. J. Johnson, Sec'y;  
Thos. M. Alfriend, Cashier.    


 Capital...$75,000.  


 whole Joint Fund Pledged for Deposits.  


 This Bank of the People, in which the working men, as well as the men of means, may deposit all their scare funds with perfect safety, and receive interest thereon at the rate of 6 per cent, per annum for 6 months or over, and 5 per cent, for less periods, continues to receive deposits, in large or small sums.

The undersigned, as Cashier, will issue certificates from 9 A. M. to 6 P. M. daily.  


 oc 4--1m Thos. M. Alfriend.

Cashier.   
 
Hostetter's Stomach Bitters. 


 --The thousands who use this great medicine for the cure of Dyspepsia and Liver Complaint and the diseases complicated with or arising from them, are requested to take notice that vile counterfeits of this Celebrated Invigorant have been issued in the South and West, and may eventually and their way into many parts of the Union.

We hope, therefore, that all purchasers of the preparation will examine the label on the bottle, where a facsimile of the proprietors' signature should appear, and also the bottle itself, which should have the words Dr. J. Hostetter's Stomach Bitters blown in the glass, and stamped on the cap covering the cork.

We also will, after January 1st, 1860, put an additional steel engraving with our note of hand attached, which to counterfeit in a felony.

Hostetter &amp; Smith.  


 For sale by Druggists and dealers generally everywhere.

oc 1--1m   
 
All Medicines should be prepared by a regular Physician. 


Dr. J. S. Rose's Cough Syrup, for Coughs, Colds, Hoarseness, Bronchitis, and that lion of diseases, Consumption.

Price 50 cts.and $1.  


Dr. J. S. Rose's Buchu Compound, for all diseases of the Kidneys and Bladder.

This preparation is a positive cure.

Price 50 cts.  


Dr. J. S. Rose's Pain Curer, for Rheumatism.

Cholic, Cramps, Pains in the Stomach or Bowels, Pains in the Back or Limbs.

Price, 12, 25 and 50 cts.  


Dr. J. S. Rose's Alternative Syrup, or blood Purifier, for the cure of Scrofula, old Eruptions, Chronic Diseases, Ulcers, Sores Swelled Neck, Biles, and all diseases arising from an impure state of the blood.

Price $1.  


 Sold by Druggists, and by  


 Warren L. Waring,  
 ja 21--1v 107 Broad st., Agent for Richmond.   
 
Leeches!

Leeches!! Leeches!!! 


 --I have just received, by Adams' Express, a lot of fresh Swedish Leeches, the very best, and large size, which will be applied upon the most reasonable terms.  


 P. S.--Cupping and Leeching promptly attended to. I can be found at all hours of the day at the Hair Dressing Room, under the American Hotel, (entrance on 11th street,) and at night at the corner of Leigh and 19th streets.  


 ap 12--ts R. C. Hobson.   
 
Baths, Baths, Baths.Hot, Cold and Shower Baths, 


 can be had daily, from 6 o'clock A. M., until 10 P. M., at the American Hair Cutting, Shaving, Shampooing and Bathing Saloon, under the American Hotel, entrance on 11th street, Single Bath 25 cts.; or five tickets for $1.   
 
To Medical students. 


 --Dissecting Cases of various styles and prices, for sale very cheap at Edward T. Robinson's,  


 sc#--2m 4th and Franklin sts.   
 
Bacon. 


 --10 hhds, Prime Bacon Shoulders for sale by Massie &amp; Pleasants,      
 
 


 Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume 18, Number 105, 2.    
 
Richmond Dispatch. 
 
Thursday Morning......nov.

1 1860. 
 
European Inconsistency. 


 The people of America, in that natural sympathy which they feel with the people of all countries, who are struggling to shake off alleged oppression, should not permit their enthusiasm to blind them to certain developments of the Italian contest, which afford a striking illustration of the real respect attached to principles of international law and national rights and independence by those who are most loudly prating of them, and who are eternally denouncing this country as a nest of filibusters and land pirates.

The fact that adventurous and roving spirits have gone occasionally from the United States to embark in such enterprises as those of Lopez and Walker, have been made the groundwork of the most sweeping abuse and denunciation of our whole country by the European press, and an English naval commander has played the part of policeman and handed Walker over to the executioner for his filibustering forays in Central America.

Whilst this abusive and bloody measure is meted out to our countrymen, Garibaldi is cheered on to the echo in his filibustering descent upon Italy, supplied by Sardinia, a Power at peace with Naples, with arms and soldiers, and backed up by English volunteers, who, no doubt, have done the hardest part of his fighting.

And all this has been enthusiastically applauded by the same public sentiment which denounces as pirates worthy of the gallows, and hands over to the executioner, such men as William Walker, who, what ever his faults, was a man of as much courage and talent, and engaged in quite as fair and practicable an enterprise as Garibaldi. But this is not all. Here is a significant item by the Canadian's advices: The Patriot says that ":Garibaldi has thanked the seamen of the English ship Renown, who served the Garibaldian guns on the 1st of October!

The men were that day on leave of absence." Observe the fact that whilst one English man-of-war is delivering one filibuster 10 death in the West, another is landing her men to fight the battles of a filibuster in the East.

Whether Garibaldi be a filibuster or not, makes no difference in this outrage upon national right and justice.

England is at peace with Naples, and the landing of trained artillerists from a British ship-of-war, to work the batteries of an enemy of Naples, is a flagrant act of treachery and injustice, which it will be idle to evade by the pitiful and unworthy pretext already prepared for the occasion, that the men were on leave of absence and acting for themselves!

Every one knows that they never could have obtained that leave of absence, under the circumstances of the times and place, without a design that they should take part in the contest, and that they would never have dared to take that part except with the assurance that it was agreeable to the wishes of their officers.

What would be said of a United States ship-of-war in Mexico, or Central or South America, if her officers should permit her men to land and work the guns in the battles of a faction in those countries endeavoring to overthrow the government Certainly, we should never hear the last of it, and would probably be threatened with European intervention to make us respect the rights of others.

We have no sympathy with European despotism; we should rejoice to see all Italy capable of being free; we loathe and detest oppression in all its varying forms; but even if the King of Naples be as great a tyrant as he is represented, does England pretend that oppression and despotism in one country justifies the interference of another?

This would be a new principle of international law, and one which, if well founded, she should hasten to apply to Turkey, Russia, Austria and Prussia, her faithful friends and allies.

Nay, more; if she should presume, as she dare not, to set up any such nonsensical apology as a vindication at the bar of public opinion, how would she relish its application to herself in the case of Ireland.--Suppose that impoverished and oppressed people, who have suffered at the hands of England a thousand fold more than the people of Italy have suffered from any of their rulers, should again revolt, as they have often revolted what would she think of an Irish Garibaldi? Let the gallows on which Robert Emmett and other patriots suffered answer!

And how would she regard the volunteering of Frenchmen, Italians and Americans under this Irish Garibaldi's banner; and what would she think of a French or American national vessel which should land its men, under pretence of a day's leave of absence, to work the guns of the rebels and batter down her strongest fortifications?

Yet this is precisely her own course towards the friendly power of Naples.

Let our countrymen remember these facts, and avail themselves of them for future reference, when we receive our periodical lectures from the London press on the forays which a few adventurers and misguided men, whom there is no power in our government or people to restrain, sometimes make from our shores.  


 There is also another fact which we wish our countrymen to bear in mind, that they may know how to appreciate the justice of the abuse which Europeans so persistently and audaciously heap upon the United States, in connexion with an alleged disposition of our Government as well as people to intervene in the affairs of neighboring and friendly States.

The accusation is equally groundless and malignant; but what is the example they set us?

The intervention by Sardinia in Naples, Sicily, and the States of the Church, is one of the most flagrant acts of national wrong and injustice recorded in the annals of history.

The Constitutional justly says that between the invasion of Garibaldi and of Sardinia there is a great difference; the one, himself a Roman, comes to lead the disaffected of his countrymen in their struggle against an unpopular government; but Sardinian invasion constitutes a direct intervention of one regularly constituted State in the affairs of another independent State.

Strange to say, Sardinian invasion took place without any declaration of war, the representative of the King of Naples still being at Turin!

Count Cavour gave it to be understood that the invasion by the Sardinian troops was principally directed against the influence of Garibaldi; now it has become evident that they go to aid him.-- We repeat, let Americans bear these facts in mind, and they will understand that when Europe calumniates the United States on account of its alleged contempt of the principles of international right and justice, it is not because Europe respects these principles, but because she hates our country, and is as malignant as she is corrupt, hypocritical and false.   
 
Capt. Hugh Nelson page. 


 --In our issue of Monday last, we copied a paragraph referring to the services of this gallant Virginian, who is one of the few survivors of the battle of Lake Erie--and for whose noble bearing upon that glorious occasion his native State honored him with a magnificent sword.

Capt. Page, though a resident of the city of Portsmouth, was born in the county of Caroline.--He was not under the command of Captain Elliot, as erroneously stated, but served on board the Tygress, commanded by Lt. Conkling.   
 
Death of an U. S. Army officer. 


 --Brevet Brigadier Gen. Clark, Commander of the Department of California, died in San Francisco on the 17th ult., of chronic diarrhŒa, after an illness of two week.

He has served in the U. S. Army since 1812, was through the war in Mexico, and was promoted to the distinguished position occupied at the time of his death for meritorious conduct at the siege of Vera Cruz.   
 
Death of a naval officer. 


 --Lieut. John T. Barraud, of the U. S. Navy, died at Portsmouth, Va., very suddenly, Sunday night.--He was a native of this State, and entered the service in 1841 as a midshipman.

He was stationed at the Gosport Navy-Yard.   
 
Export of Cotton to Mexico. 


 --The San Antonio Ledger, of the 18th, says:  


 "Not a day passes that we fail to note in our streets one or more trains of Mexican carts, varying in number from six to twelve or fifteen, laden with cotton going to the Rio Grande."    
 
The times are changed. 


 In the course of conversation a few days since, a gentleman observed to us that he had been overhauling an old file of newspapers, in one of which he found the arrival of the Duke of Kent, father of the present Queen Victoria, at Boston, announced without the flourish of a single trumpet.

It was while he was Governor General of Canada, (we believe that was the office he held while in America,) and must therefore have been somewhere about the cross of the last century.

The royal visitor quietly took up his quarters with the British Consul, and attracted no sort of attention and remark, beyond a short newspaper paragraph or two.

Our friend entered into a train of reflections suggested by the contest between this species of reception and the series of ovations which sprung up as if by magic in the footsteps of his descendant, when he lately visited our shores.

It was very great, it must be owned, and yet it was not at all strange.  


 The Duke of Kent was but a King's son — the fourth in point of birth, and therefore a very distant expectant of the crown.

Between him and the throne, lay three others, big, burly, life-like, in the flower of life, the oldest not being forty years of age. Who could expect that young man to outlive all those sons of Anak, the gigantic George, the gigantic Frederick, and the gigantic William? In point of fact, though the youngest, he was the first of the four to die. But who could have guessed, that a child of his, even, would ever succeed to the throne of his ancestors?

All these young giants might marry according to law--one of them actually was married, and the Princess Charlotte was already born.--The chance of Kent, and his posterity, therefore, was beautifully small — like the small end of nothing whittled down, to use a phrase said to have originated with old Ben Hardin--so small that it was scarcely visible, and might be said, almost, not to have existed at all. Now, Lord Brougham tells us, that while the Prince Regent was carrying on his prosecution of his wife — endeavoring to get her decapitated by his Parliament — the people were stirred against him to such a degree of intensity, that had a tolerably popular Prince of the blood offered himself as an aspirant for the crown, he would infallibly have overset the older brother.

For many years before that trial — ever since he had been Regent indeed — he had passed along the same street every day, in his carriage, and had scarcely been noticed.

Yet no sooner had he been crowned, than the poor Queen and all her wrongs were forgotten, and the same people who had scarcely raised their eyes to look at the chariot and livery of the Regent, could scarcely be kept off the chariot and livery of the King.

Yet it was the same chariot, the same equipage, and the same man. So great is the difference between him who is merely a King's son, and him who is King in his own person.  


 Now, it is probable that the Prince of Wales in a very few years will pass through London without attracting more notice than his granduncle did when he was Regent, and that he will stir up the loyalty of John Bull afresh when be becomes King.

John has seen so many Kings and Queens that he cares not to look upon royalty in prospect. But Brother Jonathan, while he cares nothing for a man who is only a King's son, with no prospect of being King himself, satiates his curiosity by gazing upon the undoubted heir of royalty.

He never saw before a man who was certain to be King, if he only fulfilled the condition of outliving his mother.

This is the nearest approach he can make to seeing a King, and he makes the most of his opportunity.  


 The relative situation of the two countries (England and America,) was at the time (1799,) very different from their present relations.

We had then hardly recovered from the heartburning which the war of independence had produced.

But a few years before, the English had come from Canada, built forts within our borders, and instigated the Indians to make war upon us. So we thought, at least, and there seems to be little cause for distrusting our suspicions.

That war-loving Minister, the younger Pitt, was at the head of affairs, and it seems to have been a principle with him never to ask for anything in a civil manner, but to knock the man down first, and take what he wanted.

"Britannia ruled the waves" at that time, with a vengeance.

"Nelson was then Britannia's God of War," and he ruled the waves with a will.

He, and the Minister, and all their subordinates and understrappers, naval, military and judicial, firmly believed that no other nation upon the face of the earth had any rights of their own, and that all the privileges they enjoyed were so many grants from Great Britain, to be resumed at her own good pleasure.

Innumerable causes of quarrel necessarily sprung up with our neighbors across the Canadian line, as well as with John Bullon the ocean.

We looked upon them as they have always looked upon the French since the wars of Edward III., five centuries ago; that is to say, we regarded them as our natural enemies; and forty-five years of peace have not entirely eradicated that impression.

It is hardly wonderful, then, that the arrival of the Duke of Kent created no extraordinary sensation in Boston.

A few old Tory families, of pre-revolutionary times, were still in existence.--Doubtless these paid their duty to him, whom they considered the son of their lawful sovereign.

But the body of the people would have considered it, no doubt, unpatriotic, anti-republican, and derogatory to their character, for independent opinion and manly bearing.   
 
Suicide. 


 --Mrs. James Watkins, residing near Alexandria, Va., committed suicide on the 29th ult. by taking strychnine.

The deceased had been for some time in a very low-spirited state of mind, had been heard to make threats against her own life, and at different times had purchased laudanum with a view to self-destruction.   
 
Death of a reporter. 


 --Dr. Marcus T. C. Gould, at one time the only short-hand reporter in the United States, died in Beaver county, Pa., last week.

He had made and lost many fortunes, not the smallest of which went down in the great morus multicaulus speculation, of which he was the head and front.   
 
Dead. 


 --Mr. John Vine Hall, a writer of religions books, died on the 22d ult., at Worcester, Eng, aged 87 years. He was the father of Rev. Newman Hall, a somewhat noted dissenting preacher of London, and of Capt. Vine Hall, late of the Great Eastern.   
 
Too Late. 


 --Among the private bequests made by the late Hon. Jonathan Phillips, of Massachusetts, was one of five thousand dollars to the late Horace Mann, whose death before that of the late testator renders the donation of no effect.   
 
Chicago Items. 


 --Lill &amp; Diversis' brewery, at Chicago, was damaged by fire Monday night, to the amount of $12,000. The loss is covered by insurance.

Dr. Wm. B. Eagan, an old and respected citizen of the same city, died Monday morning.   
 
Old people. 


 --In Sampson county, N. C., the census taker has listed Joel Hall, who is 105 years old, and both deaf and blind.

A negro woman in the same county died a few days since, aged 108 years.   
 
A discovery. 


 --At Council Bluffs, Iowa, the startling discovery has just been made that Frank Bates, a young, dashing, popular, lady fascinating dry goods clerk, is a — girl!   
 
 


 Jno. Tappan, one of the oldest merchants of Boston, broke his arm on the 27th ultimo, by a fall caused by entangling his feet in a lady's hoops, on the sidewalk.  


 Tea has been received in New York from Japan.

It can be furnished at a lower cost than China teas of a corresponding grade.  


 A fire at Albany, Ga. on the 27th ult., destroyed Byington's Hotel, Hill's stables, and several other buildings.  


 The French government has interdicted subscription for a sword to be presented to General de Lamoriclere.  


 Hon. A. R. Boteler, of Virginia, spoke at a Union mass meeting in New York, Monday night.  


 One penny a day will buy food in China sufficient to able a man to "live comfortably."   
 
Photographs and Ambrotypes 


 in every style and size known in the art, can be had at Rees' Mammoth Gallery, 145 Main street, Eagle Square, equal in quality, and as low in price as they can be obtained in New York or elsewhere.--Babies beautifully taken by Rees' instantaneous process.

oc 30--3t.   
 
Special notice. 


 --A regular monthly meeting of the Richmond Granite Stone Cutters' Association will be held at Schads Hall, on Saturday Evening, Nov. 3d.  


 The roll will be called at half past 7. and any member failing to answer to his name, will be fined.  


 no 1--3t* Lawrence MacCABEabe, Sec'y.    
 
Married, 


On Tuesday evening. the 30th ult. at St. Peters' Cathedral, Richmond.

Va. by the Rt. Rev. J. McGill, Mr. Jno. W. Burrow.

of Norfolk, to Miss Anastasia, daughter of N. Devereux, Esq., of the former city.  


 Norfolk and Portsmouth papers please copy.   
 
Died. 


Yesterday morning, Oct. 31st. at 9 o'clock, in this city, James W. only child of Jos. W. and Eliza A. Barlow.

aged 3 years and 18 days.  


 His funeral will take place from St. Peter's Cathedral, at 2 o'clock this afternoon.

The friends and acquaintances of the family, and those of Mrs. A. B. Wells, are invited to attend without further notice.    
 
Political notices. 
 
Speaking at theClub House.this Thursday Evening. Nov. 1st. 


 Hon. John S. Pendleton. of Culpeper county, will address the people at the Club House to night, commencing at 7½ o'clock.  


 Virginia can scarcely boast a more gifted orator or more gallant defender of the South, and no man will regret having heard his address of this evening.

Let the ladies enliven the occasion with their presence.

W. M. Elliott.  
 no 1--1t President.   
 
Monroe Ward — Breckinridge and Lane. 


 --A called meeting of the Vigilance Committee of this Ward will be held this (Thursday) evening, at 71/2 o'clock, at Saunders' Hall. Thos. T. Cropper, Esq., with address the meeting, and we hope that all who wish to see Virginia go, as she always has gone, for "Truth, Justice and her Constitutional Rights." will rally around her State-Rights banner, upon the eve of this, the greatest national contest.

The citizens generally of all parties, of this and Madison Ward, are invited to attend.  


 Samuel D. Denoon, Pres't.  
 Wm. R. Todd,Sec'y. no 1--1t*   
 
Union Electoral Ticket.State of Virginia.the Union, the Constitution, and the Enforcementof the laws.for President,John Bell, of Tennessee.for Vice--President,Edward Everett, of Massachusetts. 
 
Electors: 
Dist.

1st. L. H. Chandler, of Norfolk City.  
Dist.

2d.

Travis Epes, of Nottoway.

 
Dist. 3d. Thos. Bruce.

of Halifax.

 
Dist. 4th. John T. Thornton.

of P. Edward.  
Dist.

5th. Jas. F. Johnson, of Bedford.

 
Dist. 6th.

Marmaduke Johnson, of Richmond City.  
Dist.

7th. Lemuel J. Bowden, of Wmsburg.

 
Dist. 8th.

Joseph Christian, of Middlesex.

 
Dist. 9th. B. H. Shackelford.

of Fauquier.

 
Dist. 10th.

And W. E. Kennedy, of Jefferson.

 
Dist. 11th. Francis T. Anderson, of Rockbridge.

 
Dist. 12th. W. R. Staples, of Montgomery.

 
Dist. 13th.

Walter Preston, of Washing'n.  
Dist.

14th. J. J. Jackson. Jr., of Wood.

 
Dist. 15th. A. B. Caldwell, of Ohio.

  
 Election, Tuesday, 6th November.  


 oc 31--4t   
 
Discussion at Metropolitan Hall 


 --Messrs. J. H. Gilmer and James Lyons will discuss the political issues of the campaign, at Metropolitan Hall, on Thursday evening, November 1st.--Mr. Gilmer to open in a speech of one hour and a half. Mr. Lyons to follow in same time.

Each half an hour in reply.

Discussion to commence at 7 o'clock precisely.

By order of the  


 oc 31--2t* Committee.   
 
Democratic rally in Sidney. 


 --The Democratic Elector for Henrico county, Jno. B. Young, Esq., and other distinguished speakers will address the National Democracy at Tanner's Hall, Sidney on Friday evening next, 2d November.  


 oc31 — 3t*   
 
Notice. 


 --Trains for the Grand Encampment at the Central Fair Grounds, commencing on Thursday next, 8th inst., will be run constantly throughout the days to suit the convenience of persons desiring to visit it.  


 Fare--ten cents each way.  


 Samuel Ruth.

Supt. Trans.  
 Office R., F. &amp; P. R. R. Co., Richmond, Nov. 1.  


 no 1--ts   
 
U. S. Mail Steamship Jamestown, for New York, via Norfolk. 


 --The Steamship Jamestown, Capt. Thos. Skinner, will leave here at 4 o'clock P. M., Friday, the 2d inst.  


 Passage to New York, meals and state-room included, $10. Steerage passage only $5.  


 Passage to Norfolk same as by the river boats.  


 Freight received to-day, (Thursday,) and up to the hour of 1 o'clock P. M. Friday.  


 Consignees are requested to send for their goods to-day.  


 Freight for Boston taken at moderate rates and forwarded with dispatch.  


 Tickets and berths secured at our office, or on board the ship.

Ludlam &amp; Watson.  


 No more hogsheads received than those already engaged.

[no 1--2t] L. &amp; W.   
 
For New York. 


 --First Vessel Virginia line of Richmond and New York Packets.--The fast sailing regular racket Schooner Crenshaw. Capt. W. R. Moss.

having the greater portion of her cargo engaged, will have quick dispatch.

For balance of freight, apply to  


 no 1--3t David &amp; Wm. Currie.   
 
For Boston 


 --First Vessel — Richmond and Boston line of Packets.--The regular packet Schr S. R. Allen, Captain C. Baker, Jr., having the greater portion of her cargo engaged and going on board, will have quick dispatch.

For balance of freight, apply to David &amp; Wm. Currie.  


 no 1--4t   
 
Jenny Lind has arrived, 


 not the songstress, but the New Bagatelle Table.

New Game, New Style, and New Rules.

Everybody invited to come and see it at "the Hall," Bank street. The best of Ales, Wines and Liquors.  


 no 1--3t   
 
For sale 


 --A Durham Cow, fresh to the pail.

T. B. Starke.  
 no 1--3t Cor. Main and 13th sts.   
 
For sale 


 --A good.

Mule and Dray.

with or without a driver, for the balance of the year.

Any one wishing to purchase, will call at the freight office of the Richmond.

Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company.

no 1--3t   
 
For sale. 


 --I have for sale two No. 1 Mules, warranted sound, and warrant them to work in any harness.  


 no 1--2t Valentine Heckler, Jr.   
 
For sale 


 --A very fine Bay Horse.

five years old, sound, and all right; drives well in single or double harness.

Apply at Blankinship &amp; Johnson's  


 no 1--6t Stables, Franklin st.   
 
For Rent 


 --A House on 7th street, between Cary and Canal, suitable for a factory or work shop.

Apply to  


 no 1--ts J. H. Poindexter.    
 
 
 
Hdq'rs Chesterfield Lt.Dragoons, Co. "a" 23d.

Reg'tVirginia volunteers,Manchester, October 31st, 1860. 


 Parade in Manchester (at the Town Hall.) on Wednesday, 7th inst., at 1 o'clock P. M., fully equipped, with arms and accoutrements in order for inspection, prepared to go into encampment.

Each trooper will provide two blankets, two shirts, two pair socks, two towels, one curry comb and brush.

By rules of the encampment each six men will be allowed one servant.

A baggage-wagon will be furnished to carry the baggage.

The roll will be called punctually at the hour mentioned above it is desired that every member should be present.   By order of Capt. Cox.  no 1--td Wm. H.  Brander, Jr., 1st Serg't.   
 
Comp'y "K," 1st Reg. Va. Vols.Richmond, Nov. 1st, 1860. 


Attend a Regular Drill this (Thursday） evening.

at Military Hall, at 8 o'clock.   By order of the Captain.  no 1--1t F. W.  Hagemeyer. 1st Serg't.    
 
 
Notice to Stockholders. 


 --I would call particular attention to the following resolution adopted by the stockholders of the Roanoke Valley Railroad Company, at their annual meeting on the 18th inst.:   


 "Resolved, That thirty days notice be given, by advertisement, to delinquent stockholders in the Keysville Extension, that unless the balance due on their subscriptions be paid to the Treasurer within thirty days, then their stock will be sold at public auction to the highest bidder, after thirty days notice by advertisement, to raise the balance remaining unpaid on their stock; but in reference to all conditional subscriptions, the Board of Directors shall discriminate as to the propriety or policy of so advertising."  


 A copy from the minutes.  


 E. A. Williams, Treasurer.  
 Clarksville, Va. Oct. 25, 1860.

no 1--2awlm   
 
More New Goods,by last Steamer. 


 Samuel M. Price &amp; Co. have just received--  


 Elegant New Dress Silks.  


 Dress Goods, in every variety.  


 New style Cloaks and Arabs.  


 New Shawls.  


 They offer Great bargains still in--  


 Rich Dress Silks.  
 Silk Robes.  
 Delaine Robes, many of them at half cost.  


 They offer also--  


 New Cassimeres, of Southern manufacture, North Carolina goods, which received the premium at the State Fair.  


 Georgia Cassimeres, for men and boys' wear, &amp;c. no 1 ts   
 
Mission Books. 


 J. W. Randolph has for sale an assortment of Catholic Prayer and other Books, among which are:  


 The Mission Book, Golden Manual, Gate of Heaven, Key of Heaven, Garden of the Soul.

Ursuline Manual, Spirit of Prayer, Pocket Manual of Prayers, Path to Paradise, Butler's Lives of the Saints, Cobbett's History of the Reformation, Gerald Griffin's Works, Fathers of the Desert, Reeves' Bible History, Protestant and Catholic Civilization, Faber's Works, Brownson's Essays, Life of Christ, Bibles and Testaments, small and large sizes; German, French and Spanish Prayer Books.

no 1--1t   
 
Dress-making.Mrs M. A. Fisher 


 Would most respectfully inform the ladies of Richmond and vicinity, that she is prepared to execute Dress-making in all its various and most approved styles.

She is in regular receipt of all the latest fashions, and will endeavor, by strict attention, to please those who may favor her with their patronage.  


 Residence--1st street, between Marshall and Clay. no 1--3t   
 
Bricks for sale. 


 --We have about one Million of burnt and unburnt merchantable Bricks, which we will sell in lots to suit buyers, delivered on board of vessel in Petersburg or Richmond, on application, on liberal terms.

We can also furnish any quality and quantity of Building Sand.

Apply to  


 Scott &amp; Siggins,  


 no 1--1t Petersburg, Va.     
 
Marine Intelligence.Port of Richmond, October 31.high Water this day (Thursday) 5½ o'clock. 
 
Arrived. 


Schr. Mansion, Bromwell, Baltimore, lumber.

Jas. Gunn.  
 Schr. Josephine, Waterbury, Albany, lathe, Dunlin &amp; Co.  


 Schr. William and John, Jones, Philadelphia, coal, Crenshaw &amp; Co.  


 Schr. Ambition, Philadelphia, coal, Crenshaw &amp; Co.  


 Schr. Emma Jane, Norfolk, oyster shells, J. C. Atlee.  


 Sailed.  
 Brig Emery, (Br.,) King, Halifax, flour, Haxall., Crenshaw &amp; Co.  


 Schr. Wm. Severe, Brooks, Baltimore, mdze., W. D. Colquitt &amp; Co.  


 Schr. White Squall, Howe, down the river, light.  


 Schr. Georgianna, Langdon, down the river, light.   
 
 


New York, Oct. 29.--Cl'd schr. Margaret.

Petersburg. Arr'd schr. Sea Lion, Portsmouth.  


 Alexandria, Oct. 30.--Arr'd, schr. John C. Henry.

Richmond.  
 Liverpool, Oct. 12.--Entered out, ship Triumph, Murphy, City Point.  


 Bristol. Oct. 27.--Cl'd, schr. Frances Ann, Portsmouth, Va.  


 Baltimore. Oct. 30.--Cl'd, schr. Dorothy Haines, Norfolk.  


 Philadelphia, Oct. 30.--Cl'd, steamship Virginia, Richmond; schrs.

Nattie D., do.; Eliza, Norfolk.    
 
Special notices. 
 
Lumber Card. 


 --Eugene Carrington having purchased the stock of Lumber of the late Edward E. Dudley.

will continue the business at the old yard, corner Franklin and 19th streets, where he will be happy to serve the old customers of Mr. Dudley and the public generally.

Stock on hand--White Pine. Yellow Pine, Flooring, Walnut, Cherry.

Ash Mahogany, Maple, Button Wood, Lathes, Shingles, &amp;c. Eugene Carrington.  


 no 1--dlm Corner Franklin and 19th sts.   
 
Premium Beef. 


 --Robertson &amp; Grills sold to Mark A. Tyndall, of the Second Market, five Cattle, owned and fattened by Francis Bell, of Pulaski county.

These Cattle averaged in weight 2,035 lbs., all of which were awarded premiums at the State Agricultural Fair, recently held near this city.

These Cattle were the only premium bullocks sold in this market.

no 1--3t   
 
Winter style Ladies' Dress Hats. 


 -- Mrs. G. C. Allen will exhibit at her Show-Rooms.

on Friday next, the 2d November another fresh supply of Ladies' Winter Hats.  


 no 1--3t   
 
Baker's Premium Bitters. 
   Henrico County, Oct. 1, 1860.  E. Baker, Esq.: Dear Sir  


 --My wife has been suffering with Dyspepsia and Nervous Affection for several years, during which time she was as ill as possible to be alive; all hopes of life, by her physician, as well as by her relatives and friends, were blasted.

Finally, she commenced, in small quantities, the use of Baker's Premium Bitters, which, in the course of eight weeks. (by daily using them.) restored her to perfect health.

I am equally gratified to state that my child, about eight years old, was long suffering with the DiarrhŒa, attended daily by an able physician, without giving any relief; but the use of one bottle of these Inestimable Bitters restored him entirely to health and vigor.

It is my firm opinion, substantiated by that of my family physician's, that Baker's Premium Bitters is the best medicine new before the public for the above-mentioned diseases.   Yours. most truly,P. W.  J.  Quarles.   
 
 


 These Bitters can be had of all the Druggists in this city, and at every respectable Drug Store in the State.

Orders filled promptly by addressing.  


 E. Baker. Proprietor.  
 oc 30--ts Richmond, Va.    
 
The First Regiment Hat. 


 --This beautiful style Hat has been gotten up expressly (by the subscriber) for the city retail trade.

It can only be had at Binford's Hat Store, 82 Main street. The National Guard Hat, together with all the latest styles, can be had also at this establishment.  


 F. Binford,  
 oc 27--1w Opposite Morris' Bookstore.   
 
1860.--Fall and Winter Goods.--1860.Great Rush for bargains.Tremendous Excitement. 


 Having received a fresh supply of all kinds of Dress Goods, Domestics, Boots and Shoes, we are now enabled to suit every one who will favor us with a call.

As regards prices, we feel confident we cannot be beaten, as we have bought some of the cheapest Goods ever brought to this market.  


 Linen Hdkfs. at 6¼c., worth 12½c.  


Blankets at $2 per pair, cheap at $3.  


 Bosoms at 12½c, cheap at 25  


 Ladies' Morocco Bootees at $1 a $1.25, sold every where at $1.50.  


 Hoop Skirts from 25 up.  


 And everything usually kept in a Dry Goods store, at prices guaranteed to please.

Country merchants would do well to give us a call and examine our stock, before purchasing elsewhere.  


 Wertheimer &amp; Lowenberg.  


 oc 25--1m No. 25 Main street.   
 
Colt's celebrated Five Shooters.-- 


 --Army, Navy, and Pocket sizes, on hand and for sale by James Walsh.  


Gun Importer.  


 oc 22--1m 7 doors above St. Charles Hotel.   
 
John W. Garlick.Apothecary and Druggist.Market place, Franklin st., 


 Keeps constantly on hand a large supply of Drugs, Medicines.

Paints, Burning Fluid, Kerosine Oil., Paint Brushes, Hair Brushes, Cloth Brushes, Toilet Articles, Perfumery, Fancy Goods, &amp;c., &amp;c.   
 
New and beautifulFall and Winter Goods! 


 The subscriber would respectfully announce to his friends and the public generally, that he is now receiving a large and beautiful stock of  


Fall and Winter Goods,  


 Selected with great care, and at prices that will enable him to sell unusually low, for cash.  


 My stock consists in  


Ladies' Dress Goods,  
 In great variety and all the newest designs.  


 In Gents' wear, a splendid assortment of  


 Cloths, Cassimeres,  


 Velvet and Silk Vestings.  


 Neck Ties, Merino Shirts.  
 Drawers, &amp;c.  


 Also. a large and attractive stock of Heavy Goods, of every grade, for negro clothing.  


 Fine Bed Blankets.  


 Negro Blankets.  
 And every other article usually kept in a first--class Dry Goods House.  


 Call and examine for yourselves.  


 John L. Smither.  
 oc 24--2m No. 29 Main street.    
 
Servants for Hire &amp; sale. 
 
Cook for Hire 


 --For the balance of the year, an experienced and accomplished Cook, without encumbrance.

Apply immediately to  


 no 1--ts Wm. T. King.   
 
For Hire. 


 --A woman.

with a young child, who is a superior Cook, Washer and Ironer.--Also, a likely Boy, about 16 years old. for the balance of the year.

Ro. B. Lyne.  
 Agent for Hiring out Negroes.

Renting out  


 Houses, &amp;c. Office, Metropolitan Hall.  


 oc 31--3t   
 
A no. 1 Carpenter for sale. 


 --We have for private sale, a likely Negro man, 30 years of age, who is a No. 1 Carpenter; of good moral character, and sold for no fault.  


 Apply to Pulliam &amp; Co.,  


 oc 18--ts Odd Fellows' Hall, Franklin st.   
 
Cook for sale. 


 --We have for sale a young Negro woman, aged twenty years, she is an A No. 1 Bread, Meat and Pastry Cook, and good Washer and Ironer.  


 Pulliam &amp; Co., Aucts.,  


 se 15--ts Odd Fellows' Hall, Franklin st.    
 
 
 
Tobacco Agency. 


 --The subscribers have in store a very large stock of Chewing and Smoking Tobacco.

of the most approved brands.

which they offer to the trade at very low rates, the larger portion at less than manufacturers' prices.

Among our assortment may be found Thomas' "Virgin." "Golden Sceptre." "Jewel of Ophir," "Unique," "Light Pressed," "El Dorado" and "Orinoco" brands; D. B. &amp; N W Harris' "People's Favorite," "John Smith, " "Menemone," "Magnolia," "Apricot," "Luxury of the People," "Ambrosial," "Louisa Betle," "Filibuster," "Jockey Club," "Millefleur," and Sumner &amp; Co.'s brands; R. T. Gooch's "Granite Leaf" and "Louisa Bride;" W. H. Payne &amp; Co.'s "Olive Branch and Union;" Harris, Spicer &amp; Harris' "Diamond" brand; White &amp; Lovelace's "Gold Leaf." and various other celebrated brands of fine and common Tobacco, to which we invite the attention of buyers.

For sale low  Geo. J. Sumner &amp; Co.,  


oc 31--2w Iron Front Buildings.  
 
100 half bbls.

Of Wood's North Carolina Family Roe Herrings. 


 5 bbls. Wood's N. C. Family Cut Herrings.  


 20 bbls. N. Carolina No. 1SHA.  


 40 bbls. North Carolina No. 1 Family Gross Herrings.  


 300 lbs. Mountain Buck Wheat, something very nice.  


 50 bags Frost's Buck Wheat.  


 10 tubs very superior fresh Butter.  


 For sale by Robt. A. E. Dabney.  


 Family Grocer, corner Broad and 7th sts.,  


 oc 31--4t Opposite the Theatre.   
 
Ladies'Gentlemen's,girls' andBoys'Merino Shirtsand Drawers, 


 of every size and quality, can always be found at Courtney's Hosiery establishment, four doors above the Theatre.

oc 31--6t   
 
$50 reward. 


 --Stolen from the Exhibition of the Virginia Mechanics' Institute, A Gold Eagle of the carnage of 1795; also, A Diamond Ring, both valued as family relics.

The above reward will be paid, and no questions asked.

on their return.

Jas. D. Browne.  
 oc 31--3t Chairman of Ex.-Com.   
 
 


100 bbls. Extra Coffee Sugar. in store and for sale by  


 oc 31--3t Wm. Taylor.   
 
 


100 Bags New Buckwheat, just received and for sale by  


 oc 31--3t Wm. Taylor.   
 
 


25 Bels., justly celebrated "Dew Drop" Whiskey, just received by  


 oc 31--3t Wm. Taylor.   
 
 


50 Kegs Prime Goshen Butter, receiving and for sale by  


 oc 31--3t Wm. Taylor.   
 
 


100 Boxes Prime Cutting Cheese, receiving and for sale by  


 oc 31--3t Wm. Taylor.   
 
 


Bacon Sides, Shoulders, Hams, and Breast Pieces--For sale by  


 oc 31--3t Wm. Taylor.   
 
 


Cement. 2,000 bbls. James River and Rosendale Cement, and 200 bbls. Calcined Plaster for sale by Bridgford &amp; Co.     
 
Lost and Strayed 
 
Taken up 


 --Last Saturday week, Oct. 20th, a light sorrel Horse, about middle size, with a small white spot on his right side, and left hind foot white, and a small wart between his fore legs, and we suppose him to be about three years old. Benj. M. Leake.  


Three miles above Richmond.  


no 1--d1t&amp;cwlt Just above Short pump.   
 
Lost — Strayed or stolen 


--From the residence of Jos. Longinotti, Jr., on Saturday evening last a white Setter Puppy, 4 months old, with yellow ears, and several yellow spots on his body.

He comes readily to the name of "Carlow." A liberal reward will be paid for his delivery at my residence.

on 17th street, between Grace and Broad sts., or left at this office.  


 no 1--3t Jos. Longinotti. Jr.   
 
Found 


 --On Wednesday.

Oct. 24th. at the Fair grounds, an Oval Breast Pin. containing hair and initials on back.

The owner can have the same by proving property and paying for this advertisement.

O. H. Dennis, Dyer.  
 no 1--1t Opposite Met. Hall.

Franklin st.   
 
Lost 


 --On Sunday afternoon, between St. James' Church and Rev. Mr. Peterkin's. a small Oval Breast Pin containing hair, and having on the back the initials "M. B. P." The finder will please leave it at Mr. Peterkin's, on Leigh street. oc 31--2t   
 
Lost 


 --A Gold Locket, in the shape of a book, with the likeness of a little girl on one side and some hair on the other, for which the finder will be reasonably rewarded upon leaving the same at this office.

oc 31--3t   
 
Lost 


 --ten Dollars reward.--Lost, yesterday, somewhere between the Columbian Hotel and Church Hill, or between Church Hill and Rocket's, or on the Dock, a Pearl Porte-Monnaie, containing two ten dollar Virginia Bank Notes, and two ten dollar Gold Pieces and some receipts.

The finder will receive the above reward by returning the same to this office.  


 oc 30--3t   
 
Lost 


 --Five Dollars reward — On 16th street, between Marshall and Broad. a Gold Buckle, with a belt attached to it. The finder will receive the above reward by leaving it at this office.

oc 30--3t   
 
Strayed 


 --From my promises, on Thursday, 25th inst., a Gray Mare.

She is nearly blind in one eye; was bought of Mr. Burnett, of New Kent.

For her return or any information that will lead to her recovery.

I will give a suitable reward.

by calling at Timothy Kersey's Grocery, in Port Mayo, below Richmond.  


 oc 30--3t Thos. O. Connors.   
 
Lost 


 --On Sunday morning, from 6th street, a small, liver-colored Pointer Puppy, with four white feet, white breast, and tip of tail marked with white.

A liberal reward will be given for his return to this office.

oc 30--3t    
 
Wants. 
 
Wanted. 


 --A good body-maker and Wheelwright may find employment by applying at the Blacksmith Shop on the corner of Marshall and 17th streets.  


 Also — All the work that can be had such as Horse Shoeing and Wagon Building.

Repairing of all kinds done with neatness and dispatch.

[no 1--3t] R. O. Sterling.   
 
Wanted. 


 --I would like to purchase some three of four sets of Horse Trappings.

Any one that belonged to the Governor's Guard, and wishes to dispose of them, can do so by calling at this office.

no 1--1t   
 
Wanted 


 --A lady qualified to give instruction in the English Branches and Music on the Piano.

The highest testimonials required.

Address "Box 49." Staunton, Va. no 1--6t   
 
Wanted 


 --situation — By a young man, as Salesman in a Dry Goods, Book, Clothing, first-class Grocery store, or as Clerk in some office.

Having had some years' experience in the above kinds of mercantile business, can come well recommended from other employers and business men of Richmond.

He will be found faithful, willing, and always at his post.

Salary not so much of an object at present as a permanent situation.

Any one wishing the services of such, will please address, stating where an interview may be had. Edw'd S. Baker.  


 oc 31--2t Richmond, Va.   
 
Wanted 


 --By a boy, 16 years of age, a situation to Learn A Trade — is a strong, able boy, willing to make himself useful.

Please address, "Henry C.," through the Post-Office, for three days. oc 31--2t   
 
Wanted 


 --immediately--Three hundred Bands to make Coats, Pants and Vests.

Apply at the Clothing Manufactory of  


 oc 31--1w Kent, Paine &amp; Co.   
 
Wanted 


 --By a young man, who is a fast fair and legible penman, some Copying, Posting or Writing of any kind to do, to which he is willing to devote from three to four hours at night.

Address "A B C," Box 314, Richmond Post-Office.

oc 30--6t.   
 
Wanted 


 --Purchasers for a second hand Top Buggy and an open Buggy, and one Phaeton.

Must be sold this day.  


 John Does.  


 oc 29--6t Next to cor. Broad and 9th sts.   
 
Wanted 


 --By a young Lady, who can teach Music, French and English, a situation as a Governess, or in a private school.

Good references can be given.

For particulars.

address Miss "M. L. W.," Guiney's Depot, Caroline co., Virginia.

oc 23--9t   
 
Wanted 


 --Three or four first--rate Boat men. To good workmen constant employment and the best wages will be given.

Call at once on John C. Page, Jr.,  


 oc 19--ts 93 Main street.   
 
Wanted 


 --Land Warrants and Land Script — For which the market price will be paid in cash, by George Bagby,  


 oc 19--1m Two doors below American Hotel.   
 
Wanted 


 --immediately--Two first-rate Tin and Sheet-Iron Workmen.

Apply at the Stove Store of Geo. Starrett.  


 oc 16--ts Governor st.   
 
Wanted 


 --immediately--One or two good Tinners, to whom good wages will be paid.

None but practical, sober and industrious hands need apply.

F. Heffley,  
oc 8--ts 32 Main street.  
 
Wanted 


 --Every lady and gentleman to hunt up their old soiled Fall Clothing, and have them made as good as new, by King &amp; Son, the Premium Scourers, on 10th street, between Main and Cary. We also re-dress old Velvets and Velvet Ribbons, Trimmings, &amp;c.; Black Laces, Veils, Lace Collars, Sleeves, and Lace Curtains in fact, all and every kind of Wearing Apparel, &amp;c., that is soiled and out order — saving many a dollar to our patrons, otherwise overlooked.

oc 3--1m   
 
Wanted 


 --Everybody to call at my store and purchase one of those beautiful little Medals or Charms, giving a correct likeness of Bell and Everett.

Price 25 cents. Sent by mail to any address on receipt of 28 cents. Clubs supplied at reduced rates.  


 Agents Wanted.  


 A. E. Graham, Brand Cutter,  


 Shockoe Slip, Next door to Columbian Hotel,  


 se 1--3m Richmond, Va.   
 
Wanted 


 --To solicit a call from all persons in want of Trunks, at the Richmond Trunk Factory, where I am extensively manufacturing every style, from the common up to the most superior Iron Frame.

All Leather Trunks, Ladies' French Trunks. &amp;c. All sold at manufacturers' prices, at No. 54 Main st., in Saddle and Harness Store, with Wm. Salmon  


Trunks Repaired.  


 se 26--3m James Knotts.   
 
London Dock Brandy, Pure LondonDock Brandy. &amp;c. 


 Whiskeys — Bumgardner's. Summerdean, Abney's, Richardson's Flask's, Sherman, Wm. Wallace's, Tuscaloosa, Monongahela, Peter Hanger's, and Common  


 Scotch and Irish Whiskey.  


 Brandy — Jas. Hennessey, Otard.

Dupuy &amp; Co., Pinet, Castilon &amp; Co., Sazarac, Vieux Cognac, and Jules Robin brands.  


 Pure Virginia Apple and Peach Brandy.  


 Jamaica Rum.  
 Madeira, Port, and Sherry Wines.  


 Pure old Holland Gin.  


 Also--Champagne Wines of all brands and grades.

For sale, wholesale and retail, by  


 J. S. Robertson, next to cor. of  


 oc 27--1m Governor and Franklin sts.   
 
Fresh Butter. 


 --I have made arrangements with some of the principal dairy men of Orange county, New York, and of the Delaware Valley, Maryland, and of the Virginia Farmers West of the Blue Ridge to keep me supplied during the Winter and Spring, with their best fresh Butter.

Through these arrangements I can always keep on hand a superior article of fresh Butter, and will be enable to keep families supplied at a low price.

For sale.

whole sale and retail, by J. S. Robertson.  


 oc 26--d1m Next cor. Franklin and Gov'r sts.   
 
Guns — Guns — Guns. 


 --I have in store a large and very complete stock of Guns; also, Smith &amp; Wesson's seven-Shooters; Sharpe's very small four-Shooters; Colt's, Allen's, and many other Pistols, of the best makers; Sporting Goods and Ammunition, of all kinds; all of which will be sold at the lowest possible prices.

An examination of my stock is respectfully solicited.

T. W. Tignor,  
 Gun-Maker, Main street, below the Market.  


 oc 24--1m   
 
The undersigned 


 may be found on Cary street, next door above A. E. Moore, and prepared to pay highest cash price for Wood.

Fruits, Flaxseed, Ginseng, Wax, and Seneca Root.

All country Produce sold at highest rates for cash.  


 oc 30--3t G. R. Peake.   
 
Soap!

Soap!! 


 600 boxes old Dominion Soap.  


 50 boxes superior Palm Soap.  


 50 boxes Family Soap.  


 For sale by Chas. T. Wortham &amp; Co.  


 oc 30--4t   
 
Oil Cake, Oil Meal. 


 --Just received a small lot of this Food, which is largely used in England and the North for feeding stock.  


 Blair &amp; Harvie.  


 oc 30--5t Corner of Cary and 11th sts.   
 
City made Brogues 


 --4000 pair. Also,  


 French Calf skin.  


 Sole, Russet, and  


 Wax Leather.  
 For sale by N. Devereux.  


 oc 20--1m 136 Cary street.   
 
 


For Rent--A fine Wood or Coal Yard, adjoining Wm. Gray's store, on the Canal, near the Armory.

It will hold fifty thousand bushels coal.

Possession given the 1st January next.--Apply to [oc 29--1m] Wm. Gray.

of R.   
 
John Mellen,Commission Merchant,Cary st., below Shockoe Slip,Richmond, Va., 


Will give his attention to the purchase and sale of all kinds of Merchandize and Produce.  


 oc 26--3m   
 
Goods for Servants' Wear. 


 --We have on hand a large and varied stock of Goods suitable for male and female servants' wear, manufactured in the South, which we will sell low.  


 Johnson &amp; Harwood.   
 
Cloaks, Cloaks. 


 --We respectfully invite the Ladies to call and examine our stock of Cloaks, of the latest designs, and at prices that will please the most economical buyer.  


 Johnson &amp; Harwood.   
 
The Rat Killer. 


 --Use the Rat Killer, if you wish to exterminate all rats and mice on your promises.

It is only 25 cts. per box. For sale by L. Wagner, Druggist.  


 Corner 6th and Broad sts.   
 
 


12 Boxes supr.

Sugar — Cured Beef Tongues, for sale on consignment, by  


Bridgford &amp; Co.     
 
Educational. 
 
French night Schoolfor young Gentlemen. 


 Rev. J. Tirion will open a night School on the 5th of November, for teaching the French Language.  


 The School will be open four times a week, from 8 until 10 o'clock at night.  


 For further particulars inquire at Mr. Tirion's residence, corner of Broad street and Brooke Avenue, or at Mr. Francis Delarue's on Broad st, near 6th, or at Mr. John Reinhardt's Broad, near 21st.

no 1--6t   
 
Southern Waverley Institute,on 5th St., between Clay and Leigh, Mrs. Peter P. Mayo. Principal.commencing 1st October, 1860. 


 The Principle begs leave to offer this Institution as one designed to elevate female education to the highest grade, and one in which no pains or expense are spared for facilitating this object, and affording the very best opportunity for a thorough and practical acquisition of the Modern Languages, (French is the household language.) Music, Drawing, Painting and every accomplishment appertaining to the most polished education of young ladies.  


 For terms, references or a prospectus of the plan of study, apply to  


 oc 5--1m Mrs. Peter P. Mayo.   
 
Southern Female Institute,Richmond Va. 


 The 11th session of this Institution will commence on the 1st of October next, and close on the last day of June, 1861.  


 The Principal will be aided by eleven thoroughly qualified instructors, and every effort will be made to maintain the high reputation and select character of the School.  


 The advantages offered in the departments of Music and the Modern Languages are unsurpassed, while especial attention is given to the study of History.

English Literature, Rhetoric and Reading.  


 For further information, or for catalogue giving course of study, terms, regulations and full list of patrons, to which attention is invited, address the Principal.

D. Lee Powell.  
 se 17--ts Box 31, Richmond, Va.     
 
 
 
Sewing Machines. 
 
The Willcox &amp; Gibbs' Sewing Machine 


 received the highest premium at the State Agricultural Fair, October 27th, 1860, and is well worthy the attention of those in want of a good Family Sewing Machine Price $35 to $80. John A. Belvin.  


 Belvin's Block, on 12th and Governor sts.  


 oc 31--1m   
 
The Singer Sewing Machines. 


 --The marked and ever extended popularity of Singer's Sewing Machines, both in America and Europe, is such as best to establish their superiority over all others in the market.

Sewing Machines, so called, may be bought, it is true, for a smaller amount of dollars, but it is mistaken economy to invest anything in a worthless or unreliable article, and those who will do so must abide the consequences.  


 Singer's New Family Machines.  


 In order to place the very best Family Machines in the world within the reach of all, we have reduced our Letter A, or transverse Shuttle Machines, beautifully ornamented, to fifty Dollars.  


 Singer's No. 1 and 2 Standard Shuttle  


 Machines.  
 Both of very general application and capacity, and popular both in the family and the manufactory.

Prices reduced respectively from $135 and $150 to $90 and $100.  


 Singer's No. 3 Standard Shuttle Machine,  


 For carriage-maker and heavy leather work.

Price, complete, $125.  


 Also, to complete the list, an entirely new article, unequaled for manufacturing purposes, noiseless, rapid, and capable of any kind of work.

Price, including iron stand and drawers, $110, cheaper at that, in view of its value, than the machines of any other maker as a gift.  


 All of Singer's Machine make the interlocked stitch with two threads, which is the best stitch known.

Every person desiring to procure full and reliable information about Sewing Machines, their sizes, prices, working capacities, and the best method of purchasing, can obtain it by sending for a copy of "L. M. Singer &amp; Co.'s Gazette," which is a beautiful pictorial paper, entirely devoted to the subject.

It will be supplied gratis.  


 Needles, Thread, Cottons, Silk, and all necessary articles used with Sewing Machines, kept constantly on hand for sale.

Also, a practical machinist, who is ever ready to attend on our customers.

if required.  


 Messrs. Singer &amp; Co.'S office being conducted on the most thorough business principles, by an entirely new set of hands, we feel confident of doing our share of the business, as we have always done heretofore.

I. M. Singer &amp; Co.,  


 240 Main street, Richmond.  


 B. Trott, Agent.

au 28--3m    
 
Boarding. 
 
Boarding. 


 --The subscribers, having taken the house of Jos. H. Crenshaw. Esq, on Main street, between 6th and 7th, inform their friends and the public that they will be prepared to receive boarders on the 1st of October.  


 The house is in excellent repair, and fitted up with every convenience for the comfort of its inmates.

It is pleasantly situated, and convenient to the business part of the city.

Several day boarders can be accommodated.  


 R. B. Murray,  
 se 18--3tawts M. J. Murray.   
 
Boarding. 


 --One or two desirable Rooms vacant at the Edgemont House, between 6th and 7th streets. oc 12--ts    
 
Coal, Coke, Wood, &amp;c. 
 
Coke 


 --The prices of Carbon Hill Coke, until further notice, will be as follows:  
 
 
Lump Coke, $5.50 per load.

 
Stove Coke. $5 per load.

 
Hail Coke, $5 per load.

  
 oc 29--ts Jno. J. Werth, Agent.   
 
Wood,Wood,Wood. 


 300 cords seasoned Oak and Pine Wood on hand, and for sale by Philips &amp; Coleman,  


 oc 10--1m South side Dock.   
 
Coal. 


 --C. B. Lipscomb.  
 (Office 14TH St., opp. Mayo's Warehouse.)  


 Dealer in Midlothian, Lump, Hail and Smith's Coal.  


 Also, Red and White Ash Anthracite Coal, sold by weight.

au 27--3m.   
 
Oak and Pine Wood 


 --Seasoned and under shelter, for sale at Coke Yards.  


 de 12--ts Jno. J. Werth. Ag't.   
 
Important to Gas Consumers.Chas. H. Langley 


 Gas Fitter, Tinner and Coppersmith,  


 Would inform the public that he is sole agent for the sale of  


 Hawley's Improved Cylinder Gas  


 Burners.  
 and is prepared to put them up at the shortest notice, and on the most reasonable terms.

The advantages of these Burners are: To prevent blowing and waste of gas, to give a more clear and uniform light, to regulate the quantity consumed with the full head turned on to any desired amount, and thus to save at least twenty-five per cent. over the ordinary Burners.  


 Mr. J. F. Brown, in charge of the Washington City Gas Works, has certified that they are unhesitatingly the best Burners he has seen during his connection of twelve years with those works; and the Superintendent of the Richmond Gas Works asserts that the has tried them, and that they save at least twenty per cent. over other Burners.  


 Thankful for past favors, the subscriber invites orders for all work in his line, feeling assured that he can give entire satisfaction as to quality and price.

Chas. H. Langley,  
 oc 4--ts 13th st., between Main and Cary.   
 
Stocks for sale. 


 30,000 Roanoke Valley Railroad 1st Mortgage 8 per cent. Bonds connecting with the Richmond and Danville, and Raleigh and Gaston Railroads, 53 miles long, costing over one million of dollars, with a mortgage of only $460,000. For a minute description of the present condition and future prospects of the company pamphlets can be had at our office.  


 Also  


 6,000 Virginia and Tennessee 3d Mortgage Bonds.  


 3,000 York River 8 per cent. Bonds.  


 6,000 Virginia 6 per cent. Stock.  


 50 shares Richmond Fire Association Stock.  


 50 shares Virginia Fire and Marine Stock.  


 40 shares Bank of the Commonwealth Stock. C. W. Purcell &amp; Co.  


 se 22--ts   
 
Co-partnership.-- 


 Walter D. Blair.  
 John H. Munford, and  


 Robert Heth,  


 Have entered into a co-partnership, under the style of  


Walter D. Blair &amp; Co.,  


 or the purpose of carrying on, with increase facilities, the business heretofore conducted by W. D. Blair, and they hope by diligence and promptness to merit a continuance of the patronage so long and so kindly extended to their senior partner.

oc 1--1m   
 
Steam last and Boot Tree Factory 


 --Main street, between 7th and 8th, adjoining Simm's Steam Planing Mill.

Lasts made to order, of well seasoned persimmon wood.

Lasts accuracy made for tender, diseased and deformed feet.

To secure a comfortable and neat fitting boot, every one should have his own lasts.

Boot Trees made. We are prepared to turn Bonnet Blocks, Gun Stocks, Axe Helves, or Hammer Handles.  


 Orders solicited at the only establishment of the kind south of the Potomac.  


 oc 8--1m C. S. Wharton &amp; Co.   
 
Grates, Fenders — fine Sets of Tongs, Shovels and Pokers. 


 --I have for sale a large and elegant assortment of all kinds of Enamelled Grates, with Fenders; Summer Pieces of every style; handsome and plain sets of Shovels, Tongs, Pokers, Coal Scuttles, Cinder Shovels, Blower Stands, handsome stands for Shovels and Tongs, Brass and Iron Footmen, Fire-Brick Slabs and Jams.

All kinds of Church and Tavern Bells, Brass Brick Moulds, all kinds of Grates, Fenders, &amp;c., made to order at the lowest Northern prices.  


 S. D. Denoon.  
 No. 225 Main street, between 8th and 9th,  


 oc 13--3m West side.   
 
Virginia Savings Bank.--;Chartered by the Legislature of Va. 


 Capital. . . . . . . . . .$100,000.  


 money received on deposit in sums of Five Dollars and upwards, on which interest at the rate of six per centum per annum is paid for sums remaining six months or longer; for shorter periods.

interest at the rate of 5 per centum.  


 The whole joint stock bound for the deposits.  


 Deposits received and certificates issued by the Cashier.

T. B. Starke, at the store of E. B. Spence, corner of Main and Governor streets.

Richmond, Va.  
 Samuel S. Cottrell. Pres't.  
 T. B. Starke, Cashier.  
 oc 24--12m David Baker Jr.,Secretary.   
 
Light for everybody. 


 --I have the best Oil for Coal 1L Lamps in the city of Richmond, and if on trial it in not so. I will return the money and pay you for your trouble.--Give it a trial.

Price for single gallon, $1; five gallons and upwards, 90 cts. per gallon.  


 Enoch G. Rex,  
 oc 3--dlm 1 Governor st.,     
 
Amusements. 
 
New Richmond Theatre. 
 
 
Kunkel &amp;Moxley  
Lessees and Managers.

 
Thos. L. Moxley  
Acting Manager.  
L. B. Phillips  
Stage Manager.   
 Fourth night of the engagement of the American  


 Prima Donna.  


 Miss Caroline Richings,  
 And her father.  


 Mr. Peter Richings.  
 Thursday Evening. November 1st.

Will be performed a new domestic sketch entitled  


 Household Fairy.  


 Katherine, (with songs.)......Miss Richings.  


 Overture......Orchestra.  


 To conclude with the Operatic Drama of.  


 Home, Sweet Home.  


 Madame Germance......Miss Caroline Richings.  
 Valour......Mr. Peter Richings.   
 
Union Trottingcourse.TrottingThursday.

1st Nov., 1860. 


 A Trot for a Silver Cup will come off over the above Course on Thursday, 1st November, 1860.  Mile heats — best 3 in 5.  


 Wm. Walls enters a. m. Fanny.  


 Thos. Duke enters b. h. Baby Bob.  


 C. Wagner enters s. h. Spitfire.  


 Trot to come off at 3 o'clock P. M.  


 Omnibuses leave the Dime House at 2£ o'clock.  


 Gate fee 25 cents. C. Wagner.  


 oc 31--2t Proprietor.   
 
A Grand Ball! 


 Will be given at Schad's Hall, on Broad  


 street, on  


Thursday Evening. Nov. 1st, 1860.  


 Refreshments to be had at the hall.  


 Tickets, admitting a gentleman and two ladies.

$1. Thos. W. Golding.  
 oc 30--3t Manager.    
 
Runaways. 
 
Left the City Quarter. 


 on Marshall street, near the jail, on Thursday last, a Negro Boy named Beverly, who was hired of Mr. H. B. Holmes.

of Fredericksburg.

I know of no reason for his absenting himself.

He had a sore on the forefinger of his right hand, and was staying about the premises when he mysteriously disappeared.  


 The usual reward will be paid on returning him to me, or being secured so that I can get him again.

R. H. Biggins.  
 oc 31--cod3t Overseer of the City Hands.   
 
Seventy-Five Dollars reward. 


 --I will pay $75 00 for the apprehension of my Negro Girl.

Peggy, who absconded about three weeks ago. She is a low, thick set mulatto, with short curly hair, and is about sixteen years old. Her dress cannot be described, as she has been seen several times in this city since she left, and had on a different dress each time.

E. L. Chinn.  
 Richmond, Oct. 25. 1860. oc 26--ts.    
 
 
 
Headq'rs Governor'sMounted Guard.Richmond.

Oct. 31st, 1860. 


Parade at the old Fair Grounds, Thursday Morning. Nov. 1st, at 10 o'clock, precisely, fully equipped with Gauntlets, to drill in squadron exercise with the Henrico Troop.--Arms in order for inspection.  


 Sergeants will summon their squads.  


 By order of Capt. J. G. Cabell  


 oc 31--2t F. W. Chamberlain.   
 
Henrico light Dragoons. 


 Parade in full uniform at the Central Fair Grounds.

on Thursday next, the 1st of November. to drill in squadron with the Governor's Guard.

The roll will be called at 11 o'clock, and absentees fined according to regulations.

By order of Col. Davis.  


 oc 30--3t J. F. Huffman, O. S.   
 
Ladies' Gaiters. 


 --We have now in store, 5,000 pairs of Ladies' Gaiters, comprising a general assortment, from $1 to $4 per pair, both single and double sole, with or without heels.

We have all sizes from 1 to 7, of all widths, to suit all as well in price as in fit.  


 Marcus Harris &amp; Bro.,  


 175 Main street.   
 
Gentlemen's Boots and Shoes. 


 --Our assortment of the above is now complete, of both single and double soles — we sell the best French Calf Sewed Boots at $5; we sell the best French Calf Congress Gaiters at $4; we sell the best French Calf Sewed Oxford Ties at $3. All other goods in proportion.  


 Marcus Harris &amp; Bro.,  


 Next to the American Hotel.   
 
Louis J. Bossieux, 


 Manufacturer of Double Refined  


 Steam Candies,  
 And Wholesale Dealer in  


 Domestic and Foreign Fruits.  


 French Candies, Cigars,  


 Tobacco, &amp;c., &amp;c.  


 the best Goods,  


 the cheapest Goods,  


 and  


 the largest stock,  


 Can always be found at the  


 Five Story Building.  


 No. 80 Main st., opposite Richardson &amp; Co.,  


 Richmond, Va.   
 
Paraffin Candles. 
 --These Candles are made of Prepared Paraffin, a product from the distillation of coal, having the same chemical constituents as gas. They give a flame clearer and more brilliant; burn ten per cent. longer; are more transparent and beautiful; produce a softer and more agreeable light than the best wax or sperm, and being harder are particularly suitable for warm climates, 50 cases of the above for sale by L. &amp; G. B. Davenport.   
 
Peruvian Syrup 


 --A permanent solution of Peroxide of Iron.--The Peroxide of Iron is a most valuable form of iron for all diseases in which iron is necessary, but is very difficult to be maintained in that state.

In the Peruvian Syrup the difficulty has been overcome, and physicians, &amp;c., can rely on having the preparation in its most efficient form.

For sale by  


 A. Bodeker &amp; Co.,  


 Apothecaries, No. 10 Main street.   
 
Havana Cigars 


 --direct importation — The subscribers have just received the following choice brands of genuine Havana Cigars; Cabanas.

Ziguros, Conchas, Operas, Panetelas; also, Eagle Extra Principe.

A few lbs. of splendid Turkish Smoking Tobacco.  


 P. Johnston &amp; Bro. Druggists.   
 
Hull Calls attention  


 to his new shape Sack Coats and his Fancy Cassimere Suits, his new styles of Cassimere and Velvet Vests.

He keeps constantly on hand some samples of Coatings, which he will measure for and get them up at short notice.

You will and his terms moderate.

Irving Hull, Ag't.  


 94 Main st., cor. 14th next to Pairo's Ex Office.   
 
Prepare for Winter. 


 --Street Fire Sets; Brass. Wire, Nursery and Pierced Fenders; Coal Rods; Coal Sifters; Foot Stoves; Plate Warmers; Buckwheat Cake Dishes; Grate Guards; with other useful and desirable goods for winter use, for sale by Thos. A. Bulkley &amp; Co.  


 137 Main st.   
 
The Richmond Ground Pepper 


 is the best that can be bought; it is free from all dust and dirt all the pepper being well sifted before it is ground, and consequently is much stronger and purer Half pound of it goes as far as a pound of the other.

Best English and American Mustard, for sale by L. Wagner.

Druggist.  
 Cor 6th and Broad sts.   
 
Pure Bermuda 


 Arrow Root; fresh Heeker's Farina; Dupuy's Biscotine; Pear Tapioca, Barley and Sago; genuine French Racahout des Arabes and all other dietetics, for sale at  


 Joseph Laidley's Apothecary.  


 Sign of the Red Mortar 5th and Main sts.   
 
Dissecting Cases. 


 --A full assortment of Dissecting Cases, of the best manufacture.

We will warrant these instruments equal to any made.

For sale at low figures.

by  


 W. Peterson &amp; Co., Druggists.  


 155 Main street.   
 
White Coffee Sugar. 


 Refined in Richmond.  


 First Sample offered.  


 Retailing at 10 cents per pound.

by  


 Wm. T. King.  
 6 and 8 Franklin street.   
 
Prime Leaf Lard. 


 --Just received 30 packages of the above.

weighing from 12 to 14 pounds, which we are selling low for cash.  


 Minnis &amp; Co.,  


 Corner 2d and Main streets.   
 
Southampton Bacon. 


 --We have now in store 600 pounds superior Virginia Bacon.--Consumers would do well to give us a call.  


 Minnis &amp; Co.,  


 2d and Main streets.   
 
Glass Ware and Crockery. 


 --50 doz. Decanters, assorted; 25 doz. gallon and half-gallon Jars; 150 doz. Tumblers, from 50 cts. to $2 per doz.; 25 sets handled Tea Cups; Plates, Dishes, Pitchers, &amp;c., at very low prices.  


 Alex. Nott.   
 
Coal Oil Lames. 


 --Coal Oil of the best quality, at $1 per gallon; Coal Oil Lamps of every variety; $1 per Shades; Coal Oil Wicks; of every Paper Shades.

For sale at  


 Stebbins, Pullen &amp; Co.'S.  


 101 Broad street.   
 
Acorn Coffee; 


 Pat. Meal. Cox's sparkling Gelatine; Cooper's Isinglass and refined spread Isinglass; Chocolate; Cocoa; prepared Corn Starch; Tapioca; Sago; Arrow Root, &amp;c.  


 L. Wagner. Druggist.  
 Corner 6th and Broad sts.   
 
Medical Students 


 are invited to examine our Dissecting Cases and Surgical Instruments.

Meade &amp; Baker, Druggists,  


 186 Main st., cor. above Post Office.   
 
Wedgwood, LignumvitÆ 


 and Tinned Iron Mortars and Pestles, for hotel, family and druggists' use, for sale by  


 T. A. Bulkley &amp; Co., 137 Main st.   
 
Light for all 


 --Kerosene Oil--The cheapest and most brilliant light in use. Remember this is not the common coal oil.

For sale by J. W. Frayser, Druggist.

17th street.   
 
Cheese. 


 --500 boxes Cutting and E. D. Cheese, daily expected by schrs.

Marshall and Crenshaw, for sale, to arrive, by  


 Massie &amp; Pleasants.   
 
Virginia Coal Oil 


 --Burning Fluid. Sperm. Solar, and Lard Oils--fresh supplies just received by  


 P. Johnston &amp; Bro. Druggists.   
 
Butter. 


 --Choice Orange County Butter, received regularly twice a week for sale by  


 Massie &amp; Pleasants.   
 
Pure Old Palm Soap. 


 --A large lot of this choice Soap just received, and for sale by  


 Dove &amp; Co., Wholesale Druggists.   
 
A. White Coffee Sugars, of Prime quality 


 --100 bbls for sale by  


 I. &amp; G. B. Davenport.   
 
Cox's Gelatine 


 --For making Blanc Mange, Jelly, --c.; for sale by  


 A. Bodeker &amp; Co.   
 
Trusses 


 --A full assortment of the most approved patents, for sale by  


 Dove &amp; Co., Druggists.   
 
Sugar. 


 --20 hhds good to prime Porto Rico, landing, for sale by  


 Lewis Webb &amp; John G. Wade.   
 
Hay. 


 --300 bales New York, Philadelphia, and Baltimore Hay, for sale, to arrive by  


 Bridgford &amp; Co.   
 
Bacon. 


 --30 hhds. Sugar-Cured Shoulders; 10 hhds. Baltimore Sides, for sale on consignment.

by Bridgford &amp; Co.   
 
Plate Warmers 


 --For warming plates before the fire — a useful article for winter; for sale by T. A. Bulkley &amp; Co.      
 
 


 Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume 18, Number 105, page 3.     
 
 
 
Telegraphic news. [Reported for the Richmond Dispatch.] 
 
[Special Dispatch to the Richmond Dispatch]Storm on the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad. 


 Twelve Bridges Swept Away — Miles of Road Washed Off — Lost $150,000--Stages  Placed on the Line.   
 
  Lynchburg, Va.,Oct. 31.   


 -- The storm of the  two days has greatly damaged the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad. Twelve bridges were swept away, and numerous land slides occurred.

The road bed is washed up and destroyed for miles.

The full extent of the damage is not known, but the lose cannot be less than $150,000. Some weeks must elapse before it can be repaired sufficiently for the passage of trains, and passengers are now returning to take other routes.

Preparations are making to run a stage line along the railroad route.   
 
Arrival of the Fulton.  New York, Oct. 31.   


 --The steamer Fulton (news telegraphed from Cape Race,) has arrived here.  


 An insane man had attempted to shoot the Queen of Spain.  


 Garibaldi's Neapolitan Ministry had resigned.  


 The departure of French troops for Rome had been suspended.  


 [Second Dispatch]  


 Sheridan Knowles, the author, was lost in the steamer Arctic on the voyage from Hull to C ladt.  


 The fortifications of Cherbourg and Algiero will be strengthened.  


 A number of steel-cased frigates are to be built for France.  


 The garrison at Marseilles is to be reinforced.  


 The French fleet has been recalled from Naples.  


 Advices from Syria state that the French had established a provisional municipality at Decralkaishner, and had reinstated the Christians in houses built by the French soldiers.  


 The Paris flour market was high, under rainy weather.   
 
Political. Augusta, Ga., Oct. 31.   


 --A dispatch from J. J. Seibels, E. A. Banks, A. Elmore, L. D. Hollengulet and W. Garrett, of Montgomery, Also, says, "The Breckinridge Minute Men held a disunion meeting last night, and openly avowed their preference for Lincoln's election, in order to break up the Union.

Mr. Mitchell, a seceding delegate from Charleston, came out and declared boldly for disunion.

Resolutions were passed, declaring in favor of immediate dissolution in the event of Lincoln's election."   
 
Reception of Senator Douglas in the South.  Augusta, Oct. 30.   


 --Senator Douglas was hailed enthusiastically on his route through Upper Georgia. Thousands greeted him at Atlanta.  


 Macon, Ga., Oct. 31.--Senator Douglas arrived here last night.

He was welcomed with firing of guns, and great enthusiasm was exhibited by the people.   
 
From Havana and Mexico.  New Orleans, Oct. 31.   


 --The steamer De Soto, from Havana on the 27th, reports the Havana sugar market unchanged.

The growing cane crop is in excellent condition.  


 An arrival from Vera Cruz says the $400,000 seized in the specie conducta by Delgado had been returned to its owners.   
 
Financial Disasters.  Baltimore, Oct. 31.   


 --Josiah Lee &amp; Co., Brokers, have closed their Banking House sad made an assignment.

Appleton &amp; Co. have also closed.

There are rumors that others have suspended.   
 
Suicide.  Boston, Oct. 30.   


 --Southworth Barnes, a leading merchant and well known citizen of Plymouth, committed suicide yesterday, by drowning.

Cause, mental depression.   
 
Northern Markets.  New York, Oct. 31.   


 --Cotton unchanged.

Flour heavy — Southern $5.60@5.95.

Wheat 1 higher--Southern white 5c, higher, Corn steady — mixed 68 @6 . Pork — mess $19 : prime $14.75@14.75.

Whiskey dull at 22 Sugar steady.

Turpentine dull at  Rosin dull.

Rice steady at 4 3/8@4 3/4.  


 Skies in New York, Oct. 30th. of $4,000 Va. 6's st  $26.000 Tenn.

6's at 88, and $15.000 do. at $ ..  


 Baltimore, Oct. 31. --Flour dull — Howard and Ohio $5.50; City Mil's $5.37. Wheat dull — while $1. @1.55; red $1.25@5.15.

Corn steady-- yellow ; white 65@ 71.

Provisions steady-- mess pork $19.75. Coffee steady at 14 ¼@15 ¼. Whiskey dull $12.    
 
 
 
Save your Dimes. 


 --The United Savings Bank will receive at their Office, No. 93 Main street. Deposits in sums of Five Dollars and upwards, upon which will be allowed interest at the rate of 6 per cent per annum, if allowed to remain 6 months, and 5 per cent, for a shorter period.

Interest payable semi-annually.  


 Jno. C. Page. Jr... Treasurer,  


 oc 8--tlstJan. No. 93 Main street.   
 
Railroad Iron. 


 --Three hundred tons, "T" pattern, weighing fifty-two pounds to the yard, at City Point.

For sale by. James Dunlop,  


 au2 — ts Petersburg.   
 
Winter under Clothing. 


 --Cashmere, Saxony, Merino, Lamb's Wool, Shaker, Buckskin, Silk, Canton Flannel, Red Flannel, and Waterbury Shirts and Drawers; Cashmere, Lamb's Wool, Merino and English Hosiery; Furnishing Goods of every description, new, seasonable and cheap.  


 Shafer, Halsey &amp; Co., 110 Main st.   
 
New Clothing. 


 --We have just received a large stock of superior Ready-made Clothing, suited to this and the approaching season, made of the best materials and latest styles, which we warrant equal to any sold.

Call and examine our stock.  


 Darracott. Harris &amp; Co. 112 Main st.   
 
Old Dominion Double Refined Candy Manufactory. 


 --I am now ready to receive orders from the country or city merchants for my Double Refined Candies, made expressly for transportation, at New York prices.  


 A. Antoni. next door Exchange Bank,  


 and opposite Kent, Paine &amp; Co.   
 
At R. W. Powers' Drug Store 


 physicians and others will always find a well-selected stock of Instruments, Medical Saddlebags, Improved Trusses, Pharmaceutical Preparations, Chemicals, and everything generally kept in a first class Drug Store.  


 just above St. Charles Hotel,  


 Corner Main and 15th streets.   
 
Kerosene. 


 --Just to hand, the finest supply of Kerosene ever brought to the city.

It is almost entirely without any smell, burns beautiful and is of a light, clear lemon color.

For sale low. L. Wagner, Druggist,  


 Corner 6th and Broad sts.   
 
New crop Malaga Raisins 


 --First of the season.--New crop Layer Malaga Raisins, just received by steamer, being from the first cargo received in the United States this season; just received, for sale by  


 Louis J. Bossieux. No. 80 Main st.   
 
Virginia Buckwheat. 


 --Those who love this article can be accommodated at the corner of 2d and Main, where they should also supply themselves with our choice Southern Kiln dried Hominy.

Minnis &amp; Co.,  


 Corner 2d and Main streets.   
 
Flour, Buckwheat, &amp;c. 


 --Good Family Flour, in barrels and bags; Buckwheat Flour, superior fresh ground; Bolted Meal; Todd and Schooley's Hams; No. 1 MacKERELerel; Prime Bacon Breasts, &amp;c.;for sale by F. McCARTHY.   
 
 


 another supply of Ladies' Heeled Morocco and Goat Boots, at $1 and $1.25 per pair, just received at  


 G. Heller &amp; Co's, 181 Broad st.,  


 Between 5th and 6th sts.   
 
Gas Chandeliers. 


 --We have for sale, at very low prices, a large and beautiful stock of Gas Chandeliers.

Those in want would do well to call.

T. A. Bulkley &amp; Co., 137 Main st.   
 
Superior Fruit, superior Fruit. 


Receiving, and for sale in store — Extra Eating Pears; Black Hamburg, Isabella and Malaga Grapes; also, Peaches and Oranges.  


 A Antoni, next door to Exchange Bank.   
 
Superior Coal Oil. 


 --Just received, a lot of the prettiest and clearest Coal Oil that we have ever offered to the market.

We solicit a call from those who use this Oil, feeling confident that they will be pleased.  


 Dove &amp; Co., Wholesale Druggists.   
 
 


 A full assortment of Baldwin's Premium Bench and Moulding Planes; Annealed Wire, for baling hay, cut in suitable lengths; for sale by Van-Lew, Taylor &amp; Co.,  


 No. 74 Main street.   
 
Beef Tongues. &amp;c. 


 --No. 1.

Beef Tongues and Smoked Beef; No. 1 Corned Beef, in half and quarter bbls, put up for family use; Smoked Salmon, Pickled Salmon, &amp;c., for sale by  


 Burton &amp; Greenhow.   
 
Trimmings, Trimmings, 


 --Will open this morning, a full line of different styles of Dress and Cloak Trimmings, at low rates.  


 E. Goldsmit. 176 Broad st.   
 
Superior Fruit. 


 --Receiving this day per steamer, Black Hamburg, Isabella, and Malaga Grapes, Sycle and Duchess Pears, for sale by Andrew Antoni's   
 
Chamois Skins 


 --Washing and Shaving Soaps, a large variety; Combs; Hair, Clothes and Shoe Brushes; best Tooth Brushed, hard and soft.

L. Wagner. Druggist,  


 Corner of 6th and Broad streets.   
 
Burnett's Coconut. 


 --This contains a large proportion of Coconut Oil, and is the best and cheapest hair dressing in the world.

For sale by W. Peterson &amp; Co.,  


 Druggists, 155 Main street.   
 
Shingles, Shingles, Shingles. 


 --150.000 No. 1, all heart, Cypress Shingles, the best that can be made, for sale on accommodating terms by Truman A. Parker.   
 
Flower Pots, flower Pots, flower Pots 


 --Of all sizes, for sale cheap at Keesee &amp; Parr's Pottery,  


 Corner of 12th and Cary sts.   
 
Varnishes 


 --Coach, Copal, Black, Asphaltum, Japan, Damar, &amp;c., for sale by  


 Dove &amp; Co., Druggists.   
 
Abby's Gold Foil 


 --For dental purposes, for sale by Fisher &amp; Shepherd,  


Druggists.   
 
Mitchell's superior Hydraulic Candles 


 --500 packages for sale by  


I. &amp; G. B. Davenport.   
 


50 Bags Prime Laguayra Coffee;50 bbls. Extra Sugar; daily expected, for sale by Potts.

Farley &amp; Co.   
 
25 tubs Orange county Butter 


 --For sale by Massie &amp; Pleasants.     
 
Dry Goods, Carpeting, &amp;c. 
 
 


I have just received 200 Fancy Worsted Counterpanes, which I will sell cheap; and, also, a good assortment of Silks, black and colored, and a great variety of Dry Goods, Boots, Shoes and Clothing, all of which I shall sell very cheap.

Give me a call.  


 L. Rose, 256 Broad st., bet'n 2d and 3d.  


 Don't forget the place.

oc30--#   
 
AdditionalSupplies ofDress GoodsCloaks, Shawls, &amp;c. 


 We are offering great inducements in  


 Carpets and Rugs.  


 Swords &amp; Thaw, 115 Broad st.,  


 oc 80--4w Between 8th and 9th.   
 
Second large supply ofFall and WinterDry Goods! 


Breeden &amp; Fox, Broad Street,  


 Will open this day (Friday, 12th of Oct.,) their  


Second supply of Goods.  


 We would call special attention to a splendid assortment of  


 Dress Goods!  
 At greatly reduced prices, bought during the past week at the immense  


 Auction Sales in New York.  


 Most of them will be found to be at prices much below those of the opening of the season.  


 We are making large additions to our stock of Staple Housekeeping Goods.  


 Negro Clothing,  
 And every other class of  


 Domestic and Heavy Goods.  


 We have received during the past week, our own importation of  


 Negro and Bed Blankets,  


 English Prints,  


 White Goods,  
 English and Welsh Flannels, &amp;c, &amp;c., In all of which we feel sure we can offer great inducements to the trade.  


 We invite the attention of  


 Wholesale and Retail, Buyers  


 To our present stock, with the confident assurance that they will find it larger and more attractive than it has ever been in any former season.  


 Breeden &amp; Fox.  


 oc 12--20t (if) 217 Broad street.   
 
Ladies' Dress Trimmings!Ladies' Dress Trimmings! 


 I am now in receipt of a splendid assortment of the very latest and most fashionable styles of  


Ladies' Dress Trimmings.  
 which will be kept complete during the whole season, as my arrangements are such that every new style will be sent to me at once.  


 Particular attention is called to my fresh imported stock of  


 Berlin Zephyr Wools,  
 in all existing kinds and colors, which I am able to sell at the very lowest prices.  


 Worsted Jackets, Talmas, Hoods, of my own direct importation, and far superior in quality and style to any of the Germantown goods usually kept in other stores.  


 Stamping, Embroidering, and Knitting done on the shortest notice, and most accommodating terms.

C. Boettcher,  
 oc 1--1m 175 Broad street.   
 
Richardson &amp; Co. 


 Deal Exclusively in,  


 And keep for sale in quantities to suit purchasers,  


 at their  


 Ware-Rooms, no. 95 Main street,  


 Richmond, Va.,  
 all kinds of  


 Carpeting,  


 Mattings,  


 Floor Oil Cloths,  
 Rugs, Mats,  


 Curtain Goods,  
 Window Shades,  
 Table Oil Cloths,  
 Piano and Table Covers, &amp;c., &amp;c.  


 They will have made to order,  


 Carpets, Oil Cloths,  


 Window Curtains and Shades.  


 We have opened a splendid lot of Carpeting of our own importation, and are now prepared to exhibit the latest styles in every grade.  


 Our assortment of Curtain Goods, with Trimmings, &amp;c., is unsurpassed, and our stock is complete of Window Shades, Floor Oil Cloth, &amp;c.  


 Buyers are invited to examine our goods, which will be sold on accommodating terms.  


 se 17--2m* Richardson &amp; Co., 95 Main st.   
 
Window Shade Depot-- 230 Broad street 


 My stock of Window Shades being very large.

I am determined to run them off cheaper than ever.

The following is my list of prices:--Dark Landscapes, 31 cents, worth 75; Plain Gold Shades 75 cents, with fixtures complete; Gold, with Centre, $1. worth at least $3; Gold and Velvet, $1.50, worth $4; beautiful Bouquets, 75 cents, cheap at $1.50; splendid Vase Shades, 90 cents, can't be bought elsewhere for $2; Gothic style, Dry Landscapes.

Pleasure and Hunting Scenes; in endless variety; German, English and American Oil Cloths, all widths, very cheap; Table and Stand Covers; Hearth Rugs, very low and all wool; Carpeting only 50 cents, a great bargain; 150 large gilt framed Parlor Pictures.

rich scenery, at the astonishing low price of $2, worth $6; also, a large line of Dry Goods, cheap for cash.

Call soon at the established cheap Dry Goods and Window Shade Store of M. Golden, 230 Broad street.  


 P. S.-- I keep no traveling agents.

sc 19--3m   
 
Dry Goods 


 --Fall; 1860.--Kent.

Paine &amp; Co., Importers, Jobbers and Manufactures.

Nos. 163 and 165 Main street, Richmond, respectfully announce to the merchants of Virginia and adjoining States that they have in store a magnificent and well assorted stock of Foreign and Domestic Dry Goods, adapted to, and specially gotten up for, the Southern trade.  


 Their stock of Imported Goods was purchased for cash, by one of the partners in person, in the leading European markets, during the past summer, were shipped direct to this port, and comprises an elegant and complete assortment in all the departments.  


 They are also prepared with a large and complete stock of American Fabrics, bought on the best terms, embracing every variety, and of the best styles.

In the Clothing Department they are much better prepared than here before, with a very large and handsome assortment of all grades wanted in the trade, and on the most favorable terms.  


 Having every facility for getting up a stock on the best terms, we confidently ask an examination of our goods by Southern Merchants, to convince them that a more complete and well assorted stock, suitable to their trade, cannot be found in this country.

And to cash and prompt paying buyers we are determined to offer it at prices that will compare with those of any market.  


 Orders solicited and promptly and faithfully executed.

Kent. Paine &amp; Co.   
 
Grand opening of a large well-selected stock of Dry Goods, Shawls and Cloaks 


 --On Monday morning, October 22d 1860, at M. Mitteldorfer's, No. 225 Broad street. I have just received from auction some of the greatest bargains in Dress Goods that were ever offered to the ladies of this city, such as Silks, Poplins, Brocatelles, Velours, &amp;c., and to which I ask the particular attention of all in want of any to give me a call.

I have just received and will continue daily to receive, all of the latest styles of Cloaks and Mantles, such as Arabs, Japanese, Zouaves, Bournons.

Shawlettes. &amp;c. The attention of the ladies is again called to my stock of housekeeping Goods, of all and every description.

All kinds of Virginia makes of Cloths, Linseys, &amp;c., of men and women's wear.

Give me a call before purchasing elsewhere.

M. Mitteldorfer.  
 No. 225 Broad street.   
 
Very important to know 


 --That Joseph Strause is selling, astonishing low. Dry Goods, Shoes and Carpeting.

All colored Merino at one shilling and higher; fine Mouslain De Laine at 12 ½c.., one shilling, &amp;c; Alpacas 18; fast-colored Calico 8; Stella Shawls and Heavy Double Shawls at all prices.

The greatest bargains in Bed and Servants' Blankets, Sheeple Grey, Satinets, Cassimeres, Jeans, Ticking, Linseys, Black and Colored Silks at half the value; Ladies' Cloth Cloaks cheap; Flannels, Knitting Yarn, every color, at $1 per pound; Extension Skirts from 18 up; 3,000 Linen Bosoms at 18 ¾c. and higher, worth twice the money.

I invite everybody in want of goods to call, without delay, at Joseph Strause's, No. 27 Main st.   
 
Second supply — Rich and beautiful Goods. 


 --We are opening, by steamer, which makes our stock still more attractive, Rich Printed Paris Merinos; Rich Printed Velours de Paris Plain Velours and Solferinos; Rich Black and Colored Silks; Velvet and Cloth Cloaks, in new patterns and very beautiful styles; Children's and Misses' Cloaks.

Our stock of heavy Woollens, for Servants, comprises 3.4 and 6.4 Virginia Fulled Cloths and Jeans; S G. Satinets; heavy Plaid and Striped Linseys; Blankets; Flannels and Bed Blankets. Carpet Department--Extra Ingrain Carpets; extra Three-ply Carpets; Rich Velvet and Brussels Carpets; Kegs.

Floor Cloths, Mats, &amp;c. Purchasers are invited to examine.  


 Christian &amp; Lathrop, 99 Main st.   
 
Splendid bargains, and no mistake Chas. A. Gwatkin, 


 8th and Main streets, nearly opposite the Spotswood Hotel.--$25,600 at and under cost for cash only.

Ladies and gentlemen from the country will do well to give us a call, as such a chance in rarely offered in fine and useful Dry Goods, Ladies' Dress Goods of all styles; Ribbons, Men and Boys' Wear, Umbrellas, Merinos Silks, Collars, Bands, Ruches; also, a large lot Plaid French Merinos at 62 4/3 cts. exactly half the regular price.  


 Chas. A. Gwatkin.   
 
Dress Goods. 
 --We have this day opened a full and fine assortment of Dress Goods, consisting of splendid Silks of all qualities and prices; Delaines, all wool; Valentias, &amp;c. We have bought the above at a great sacrifice, and are, therefore, enabled to offer such inducements that cannot fail to give entire satisfaction.

The particular attention of the ladies and public are invited to our unusual large stock of Dress Goods, which are too numerous to mention.

Call at the bargain emporium of Alfred Moses,  


 63 Main street.   
 
Servants' Clothing-- Servants' Clothing. 


 --Our assortment of Servants' Clothing was never so good as it is now, consisting of all the usual varieties — say, Heavy 6.4 Virginia made Fulled Cloth; heavy ¾ do. do.

do. do.; Sheep's Greys, Jerseys, Cassinets, &amp;c, &amp;c.; Linseys and heavy Jerseys, for women; Blankets, Flannels, Stockings, &amp;c, &amp;c. All of which we offer for sale as low as goods of the same quality can be had in Richmond.  


 Chiles &amp; Chenery.   
 
Bargains in Silks. 


 --Solferino Plaid Silks, Magenta Plaid Silks, Blue and Black, Green and Black Silks, for sale at 52 ½ cts. per yard; new style Dark Ground Silks and Embroidered Figures; Printed Foulard Silks; Plain Black Silks in great varieties of widths and qualities, all new and for sale at very low prices.  


 Chiles &amp; Chenery.   
 
Millinery Goods, Millinery Goods.-- 


 Flats, Bonnets, Ruches, Uncut Velvets, Satins, Flounces, Bonnet Ribbons, Chenille Nets, Feathers; Laces and Edgings, rich white Sash Ribbons; Plush, Black Velvet Ribbons, and all styles of Millinery Goods, at low prices.

E. Goldsmit, 176 Broad st.   
 
Black Alpacas 


 --only A nine Pence 500 yards Black Alpaca to be run off at a nine pence. Now is the chance for cheap Mourning Dresses at Ezekiel's Cheap Store,  


 41 Main st., Mailert's Old Stand.   
 
The best Kid Gloves. 


 --Levy has just received a fine assortment of Coupe Jouvin, White, Black and Colored Kid Gloves.

These Gloves are of a superior quality, and are considered by many to excel the most celebrated makers Price $1.   
 
 


Another Invoice of those rich Arab Cloaks at $8, just received and an assortment, of different styles, at very low prices.

Call early if you want to secure the greatest bargain in a Cloak.

E. Goldsmit, 176 Broad st.   
 
Shawls and Dress Trimmings--Great bargains. 


 --We have a large lot of Dress Trimmings which we are offering at half the usual cost.

Ladies, call and see them.  


 Chas. A. Gwatkin, 8th and Main sts.     
 
For sale and Rent. 
 
A rare opportunity.--for Rent 


 --A most desirable House on West 17th streets near Main, opposite the Old Market.

The House has nine rooms besides store and cellar.

Gas all through the premiers.

A first rate location for any business, particularly a restaurant and boarding-house.

Rent reasonable, and terms for possession moderate, and can be had immediately.

Apply to  


 oc 31--ts Jacob Ezekiel, 41 Main st.   
 
Rooms for Rent 


 --Four desirable Rooms over my store, on Broad street, between 2d and 3d streets.  


 oc31 — 2t* A. Hardingham.   
 
For sale or Rent. 


 --The new brick Dwelling now occupied by Daniel Hunt, Esq., on 6th, between Cary and Canal streets, containing eleven rooms, a large bathing room and coal cellar, and all the modern improvements; also a kitchen with four rooms, and a double stable, fronting on a private alley 14 feet wide.

The yard is large and convenient.

This is one of the most desirable dwellings in the city, situated in a very healthy and excellent neighborhood.

Would suite either a medical man or merchant, being in ten minutes walk of the business portion of the city.

Any person wishing to purchase, can do so much below cost.

Information maybe had of Mr. Hunt, on the premises, or at my office.  


 E. A. J. Clopton,  
 Corner Wall and Franklin streets,  


 oc 30--eod2 Opp. Dickinson, Hill &amp; Co's.   
 
The valuable property at the Corner of Broad and Ninth streets, known as the "Broad street Hotel," for sale. 


 --The above property is for sale, and will, if required, be divided.

It is fully regarded as among the most valuable real estate on Broad street. Liberal credits will be given, or, if preferred, City or State, or Bank Stocks will be taken in payment, at par.--The lot has a front of 131 feet on Broad st, and a depth on 9th st, of 130 feet to a wide paved alley.--The property, in its present condition, pays a more than nett interest on $15,000. Apply to  


 oc 30--6t Goddin -- Apperson.   
 
A beautiful Market Farm for Rent. 


 --On the 1st day of January next, that beautiful market farm "Sherwood" will be for rent.

It lies between the Brooke turnpike and new road by the Fair Grounds by each of which it is bounded; one mile and a quarter from the city, contains seventy three acres. The accommodations upon it are sufficient for a small family.

It may be rented for one year or more.  


 R. B. Haxall,  
 oc 29--ts Jas. Lyons.   
 
For Rent. 


 --On the first day of January next the Central Hotel will be for rent for one or more years, with all the Furniture in it. Apply to  


 oc 29--ts James Lyons.   
 
For Rent — and possession given immediately 


 --The large Room formerly used as a Pistol Gallery, on the corner of 14th and Main streets, Rent $300. Apply on the premises.

[oc 26--6t] M. G. Whitman.  
 
Room for Rent 


 --A large comfortable Room over my store, suitable for a doctor's office or lodging-room  


 J. W. Frayser. Druggist, 17th st.,  


 oc 23--ts Near corner of Broad.   
 
Room for Rent. 


 --The large and comfortable Room, lately occupied by the York River Railroad Company, over the store of the subscribers is now for rent.  


 P. Johnston &amp; Brother.  


 an 16--ts 115 Main street.    
 
Real estate for sale 
 
Desirable Tract of Land for sale containing 480 Acres. Excellent improvements and superior orchards 


 --We will sell, to the highest bidder, upon the premises, on Thursday, the 15th day of November next, at Jennings' Ordinary, in Nottoway county, a valuable Tract of Land, belonging to the estate of Nathan Ward, dec'd, situated on the Richmond and Danville Railroad one mile from Jennings' Ordinary Depot.

The improvements are very fine; the orchards of apple peach, pear and plum, are large, and as well selected as any in the State of Virginia.

The crop of wheat seeded will be charged to the purchaser.  


Terms--$250 in cash; the balance on a credit of one, two and three years interest added, bonds and approved security, and title withheld until the payment of the purchase money.

Mr. Levisee who resides on the land, will show the premises to any desiring to view them.  


 Address, Petersburg,  


 Campbell &amp; Pegram,  


 Com'rs of the Circuit Court of Nottoway.  


 oc 30--d6t &amp; cwtds.   
 
Small Farm for sale. 


 --Intending to remove from where I now reside.

I will offer for sale, privately, my little Farm, on the Brooke Turnpike, 3 ½ miles distant from the city, containing 17 ½ Acres of highly improved land.

This place is admirably situated for a Market Garden, having at this time a good many Fruit Trees in full bearing — The neighborhood is very good, and in a very short distance of two churches.

The Buildings are full sufficient for the place, having a very good Dwelling-House with seven or eight rooms, with Kitchen.

Barn, Stables, &amp;c. besides a Blacksmith's Shop and Smith House, with a good run of custom to the shop, and two Wells and a Spring of good water on the place.

If not disposed of by the 31st of the present month, of which due notice will be given, I will on that day sell it at public auction, to the highest bidder, with all my Farming Implements, crops of Corn, Fodder, Shucks, and Straw; also, all the growing crops of Vegetables.

Horse. Wagon and Carts, &amp;c.; also, all my Household and Kitchen Furniture.

Persons disposed to purchase, will please call on me, on the place, or to Mr. J. W. Bevridge, Richmond, Va.  


 oc 9--1aw4w R. G. Walton.   
 
For sale, most valuable property in the county of Elizabeth City--"little Scotland." 


 --The subscriber having recently purchased a large farm in another county, with a view of devoting his entire attention to agriculture, offers for sale his most valuable estate in the county of Elizabeth City, known as "Little Scotland." "Little Scotland" is most beautifully situated at the mouth of Hampton river; its health unsurpassed; the soil high and rich; scenery the most beautiful in tide-water Virginia, commanding a view of Hampton River, Old Point Comfort, the town of Hampton, and the splendid roadstead.--The town of Hampton is most rapidly extending in this direction, and the locality of "Little Scotland" presents every facility for building purposes.

From the demand or building lots, the subscriber has seriously contemplated the division of his Farm into lots, confident the scheme would prove most profitable.

Should be not dispose of "Little Scotland" before the 1st of January next, he will then offer it in small and suitable parcels.

Chesapeake College adjoins "Little Scotland" on the one side, and handsome residences connect it on the other with the rapidly growing town of Hampton --The improvements are all new — new Barn and out — Houses, a large and commodious Brick Residence, with all the necessary conveniences, one--fourth of a mile from Hampton and two from Old Point.

This place offers rare inducements — all the luxuries of the salt water, health, good society, fine schools and churches "Little Scotland" contains about 185 Acres, excepting "Mill Point" of six acres, on which there is a new and valuable Brick Steam Mill, capable of grinding twenty barrels of flour, or one hundred bushels of meal per day, for all of which there is an active demand.

Experience has demonstrated "Mill Point" to be an excellent location for a ship"yard, and the purchaser of the Mill could easily attach a Saw Mill and Railway.

The Mill will be sold separately or with the Farm, as the purchaser may desire — the subscriber reserving two acres for a summer residence, upon "Mill Point," which he would not dispose of on scarcely any consideration.

He would most respectfully invite all who may wish to purchase to visit the premises, as he cannot pretend to give the many advantages possessed by "Little Scotland." Its inducements are many and rare, either to the capitalist or to one who may desire a beautiful home, combining all that is necessary for pleasure and comfort.  


 The subscriber would also offer for sale, another valuable Farm, containing one hundred and fifty acres, situated opposite the town of Hampton, on Hampton river, and known as "Oakland," with most superior facilities to the best markets.

The soil is highly productive.

There is an active demand for everything capable of being produced on a farm.

It is one fourth of a mile from Hampton, and three from Old-Point.--The beauty of location, its health, the productiveness of the soil, together with its proximity to good schools and churches, render it a most desirable place.  


 If not sold privately before, the subscribers will offer at public auction, the Mill Property and Oakland, in Hampton, on Thursday, the 22d November, 1860.  


 Term--Accommodating.  


For further information, address,  


 William E. Wood,  
 oc 26--d1m Hampton; Va.   
 
Land and Slaves in the county of Amelia, for sale privately. 


 --The devisees of John H. Steger, decide, offer for sale privately a valuable Tract of Land, lying on the Appomattox river, in the county of Amelia, five miles from Mattoax Depot, on the Richmond and Danville Railroad, containing, by estimation, 1,000 acres. The land is admirably adapted to the production of Corn, Wheat and Tobacco, and the tract is regarded as one of the best in the county.

If desired, it will be divided into two tracts.

The neighborhood is most excellent.

Possession will be delivered at once; the devisees reserving the right to cultivate and gather the growing crops, if a satisfactory arrangement cannot be made with the purchaser to take them.

The purchaser of the land, if he desires them for his own use, can also purchase a large number of valuable Slaves.

The terms will be made accommodating.

Apply to William E. Meade or John S. Hardaway, Chula Depot, Amelia; or to R. W. Steger, Mattoax Depot, Amelia.

an 29--tf    
 
Horses, &amp;c., for sale 
 
For sale 


 --A stylish dark bay Horse, nine years old, gentle and sound; has been used in harness, but is specially recommended for the saddle — would suit cavalry service.

Also, a United States Saddle, with Equipments, Bridle, &amp;c. Enquire of  


 oc 31--4t* Peyton Johnston, Main st.   
 
Fine Harness and Saddle Horse for sale. 


 --For sale, a full size Bay Horse, very handsome, well broke to double or single harness, and rides well under the saddle.

As the owner has no use for him, he will be sold for less than his value.

Apply at the office of  


 oc 30--3t Goddin &amp; Apperson.   
 
For sale 


 -- A fine, thoroughbred, Grey Horse, raised by Major Doswell, who will give his pedigree to any one wishing to purchase.

He was 5 years old last June, and is about 16 hands high; is a remarkably fine harness horse, and goes well under the saddle; can easily walk five miles an hour, and sound in every particular.

T. B. Grundy,  
 oc 13--ts 5th and Cary sts., or at Haxall's Mills.    
 
 
 


The City of Richmond being about to introduce Steam Fire Engines, have on hand three hand Fire Engines, which will be sold on reasonable terms.

Apply to the Principal Engineer.  


 oc 22--ts Lewis L. Barnes.   
 
 


Improve your Sight, M. J. Franklin &amp; Co., Opticians, offer to the public their improved Crystal Periscopic Spectacles, for preserving and restoring the impaired vision to its prime vigor.  


 Crystal inserted in old frames.  


 A very fine assortment of Microscopes, Telescopes, Marine and Opera Glasses, Mathematical Instruments, Stereoscopes and Stereoscopic Views, always on hand.

No. 148 Main St., Richmond, Va.     
 
Steamboats, Shipping, &amp;c. 
 
For Lynchburg 


 --To leave Thursday Evening.--The Canal Boat Merchant will leave as above.

For freight, apply to  


 Wm. P. Cox.  
 oc 31--2t At the Shed, Dock st.   
 
Daily line on the James River.

By the Steamers Glen Cove and Curtis Peck. 


 --The Steamer Curtis Peck will, on Thursday Morning next, the 18th instant, commence the regular run between Richmond, Portsmouth and Norfolk, leaving the wharf at Rockets every Thursday, Saturday and Tuesday Morning, at 6 o'clock.  


 The Glen Cove will leave the wharf at Rocketts, every Monday, Wednesday and Friday Morning, at the same hour. (6 o'clock.) and each boat will return each alternate day (except Sunday) Thus making a daily line between the above places, unsurpassed for speed and accommodations by any other line.  


 The Boats will touch at all the regular Landings going and returning, and take freight as usual; but all freight to be landed on the river must be paid for when sent down, and we will not be responsible for it after it is landed on the wharf for which it is marked.  


 Passage to or from Norfolk or Portsmouth, $2.  


 Meals, each, 50 cents extra.  


 oc 17--ts R. O. Haskins.   
 
Fall and Winter Arrangement. 


 --three times A week between Richmond and New York — only $10 Passage, State Room and Meals Included.--The U. S. Mail Steamships Yorktown, Jamestown and Roanoke will leave Richmond for New York, as follows, stopping at Norfolk both going and returning, viz:  


 The Yorktown, Capt. Parrish, every Tuesday afternoon, at 4 o'clock.  


 The Jamestown, Capt. Skinner, every Friday afternoon, at 4 o'clock.  


 The Roanoke, Capt. Couch, every Sunday afternoon at 4 o'clock.  


 Returning from New York every Tuesday, Thursday and Saturday, at 3 P. M.  


 Steerage Passage to New York only $5.  


 Passage to Norfolk the same as by the river boats.  


 Excursion Tickets discontinued until the next season.

Ludlam &amp; Watson,  


 oc 1--ts Opposite Steamers' Wharves.   
 
For Liverpool. 


 --Richmond and Liverpool Packet line.--The first ship of this line, the Virginia Dare, Captain J. M. Cole, will load at this port for Liverpool on or about the 20th of next month.  


 Shippers will bear in mind that, by special act of the Legislature, flour can be shipped on this ship, owned in Virginia, without inspection.  


 A large part of her freight is already engaged -- For balance of freight apply to  


 oc 29--ts David &amp; Wm. Currie.   
 
For Charleston, S. C. 


 --The superior fast sailing Schr. Minnehaha, Young, Master, having the greater portion of her cargo engaged and going on board, will have dispatch.

For remainder, apply to  


 oc 27--6t W. D. Colquitt &amp; Co.    
 
Millinery &amp; Dress"making. 
 
French Millinery. 


 Madame Son will receive, by Monday's steamer, a large and select assortment of Millinery, of late importation.  


 Great inducements will be offered to City and Country buyers.  


 Orders executed at short notice.  


 My store is closed on Saturdays and Sundays.  


 oc 27--5t* Madame Son, No. 55 Main st.   
 
New and fashionableMillinery 


 214 Broad Street.  


 Mrs. Davis &amp; Sister beg leave to inform their friends, patrons, and the ladies generally, that they are now opening their Fall and Winter Stock of Millinery Goods, consisting in part of Silk, Straw and Velvet Bonnets, Plumes, Ribbons, Flowers, Wreaths, Head Dresses, Dress Caps, &amp;c, &amp;c. Also, Lace Capes, Berthas, Infants' Hats, Caps and Ruches, of every style.  


 The ladies of Richmond, and those visiting the city, are most respectfully solicited to call and examine these goods, as they feel confident that they will be able to please, both in style and price.  


 opening day.  


 We will open our Winter Fashions on Tuesday, the 23d inst. oc 4--ts   
 
Miss V. A. Templeman 


 Will open, on Saturday Morning, Oct. 18 at No. 212 Broad St. Fall and Winter Millinery, Bonnets, Hats, &amp;c., with a splendid assortment of Ribbons, Flowers, and Head-Dresses.

Also, a beautiful assortment of Embroideries, Veils, Belts, &amp;c., and will take great pleasure in showing them to all who may favor her with a call.

oc 11--1m   
 
Madame grade, French.Milliner and Dress maker 


 175 Main St., corner of 11th st., informs the ladies that she will open her rooms for the sale of Millinery Goods, viz: Bonnets, Hair Nets, Ribbon, Feathers, Illusion Goods, Sleeves, Real Lace Sets, etc. Also, Perfumery, Embroidered Yokes, Infants' Robes.

Particular attention to Children's Clothes, Pinking, Stamping and Fluting.

Will open Tuesday, 16th October.  


 Wanted, a Milliner.

oc 11--1m*   
 
A Card 


 --to the Ladies and Gentlemen of Richmond and its Vicinity.--Miss Rebecca Semon would respectfully inform the ladies and gentlemen that the has just received her stock of Fall and Winter Patterns, comprising the Zouave Jackets, for ladies; Japanese Walking-Coat and Cape, for little boys; Garrick Coat, Spanish Dress, Zouave Coat, Lennet Coat and Dress Jacket, and a number of Apron Patterns, for little boys.

Also the Lulu and Victoria Walking Dress, for little girls; Zouave and Cleopatra Aprons, and a number of Dress Sleeve Patterns.  


 Miss Semon is now ready to Braid and Embroider the Zouave Jackets, for ladies and children, Also, Ladies' and Children's Flannels; Sacks and Wrappings for Infants; Suits Embroidered for Little Boys.

Also, pinking, Drawing and Stamping done at the shortest notice, in her room, at her father's residence, 2 doors below St. Charles Hotel.  


 oc 9--1;m Miss Rebecca Semon.   
 
Madame Fauche,French Milliner,233 Broad street, Richmond, (twodoors above Mr. Quarles' Store.) 


 Would announce her return from New York, with the latest styles of Bonnets, Flowers, Caps, Head-Dresses, &amp;c. Confident in her good taste.

Ladies will be supplied with the choicest articles.

She would also call attention to her French importation received by last steamer: Bonnets, Flowers and Coiffures.  


 will be open October 9TH.  


 In consequence of the non-arrival of my French Bonnets, my opening will not take place until October 13TH.

oc 4--1m   
 
Millinery 


 --Fall Trade.  


 I desire to call attention to my extensive stock of Millinery Goods, consisting of Head-Dresses, Ladies' Caps, Furs and Cloaks, the latest and most desirable styles.  


 Bleaching, Pressing and Dyeing done in the best style.

Mrs. J. Demelman,  
 Main, between 17th and 18th sts,  


 N. B. --Four to five good Milliners wanted immediately.

oc 2--1m*   
 
Millinery--Fall Trade. 


 -- I desire to call attention to my removal from 242 Broad street, to 246, two doors west of my old stand, where I am prepared to exhibit a larger stock of Millinery Goods, of all kinds, and will continue to keep throughout the season Goods of the latest and most desirable styles.  


 Mrs. A. McCONNAL,  
 sc 22--;2m* 246 Broad st.    
 
Boots, Shoes, &amp;c. 
 
Just received. 


 We have just received our second supply of Fall and Winter stock, consisting of a large and well selected assortment of Ladies' Gent's, Misses' and Children's Boots, Shoes Gaiters, &amp;c., which we are prepared to sell as low as any house in the city, at wholesale or retail.

A call is respectfully solicited.  


H. Stern &amp; Bro.,  


 oc 17--1m No. 87 Main st.   
 
Boots and Shoes. 


 Great Reduction in prices.  


 Chas. Behle, Broad street, between 2d and 3d, keeps a large stock of Ladies', Gentlemen's and Servants' Wear constantly on hand and defies anybody in Richmond to compete with him in his line, as he manufactures to order, and superintends himself.

Great bargains in Ladies' and Misses' colored Gaiters, Morocco Bootees, Slippers and Buskins; Gentlemen's city-made Patent Leather Gaiters, Oxford Ties and Slippers.--I will sell my Summer stock of Goods at and below cost.

Call soon, if you wish to get a good bargain.   Chas.  Behle.   
 
Strangers visiting the City 


 in want of Boots, Shoes and Trunks, are respectfully invited to call and examine our large and well selected stock.

Doing exclusively a cash business, it enables us to sell our goods at such extremely low prices as to satisfy the closest buyers.   Marcus  Harris &amp; Bro., Next to the American Hotel.   
 
Gents' Broad-Tread Boots 


 --Very superior and cheap, at No. 43 Main st., sign of the Big Boot, by Wm. Walsh.   
 
Just received, 


 500 pairs of those splendid Plantation Brogans, at the unprecedented low price of $1 a pair, at  


 G. Heller &amp; Co.'S, 183 Broad st.   
 
To Farmers--Negro Shoes 


 -- Farmers and others wanting Negro Shoes are invited to call at No. 93 Main street, where will be found the largest and best assortment ever offered in Richmond.

My assortment embraces, 2,000 pairs of heavy Sewed Brogans, of my own make; Men's Army Brogans; Men's high cut do., very thick, nailed with hob nails; Dane's best thick pegged Brogans; Herrick's best thick pegged Brogans; Planters' and Dutch, Boots for women, together with all other grades, suitable for servants, men, women and boys.

Farmers will do well to give me a call, at No. 93 Main st.  


John C. Page Jr.   
 
 
Another Lot of those fine quality Ladies' Gaiters, with heels, at $1.25 and $1 a pair, just to hand at  


 G. Heller &amp; Co.'S. 183 Broad st.   
 
Gents' Broad-Tread Shoes 


 --Very high cut, for winter, and Double Sole, very superior and cheap, at No. 43 Main street, sign of the Big Boot, by  


 Wm. Walsh.   
 
G. Heller &amp; Co. 


 have one of the largest stocks of Trunks, Bonnet Boxes, Valises, Carpet Bags, &amp;c., of the best manufacture, and are selling them at prices to please all who examine them.  


 come one, come all,  


 To the great Trunk Hall.  


 G. Heller &amp; Co, 183 Broad st.   
 
Great Reduction in the Price of Hats and Boots. 


 --From 15 to 20 per cent. saved by buying from J. H. Anthony,  


 Columbian Hotel building.  
 Moleskin Hats of best quality, $3.50; do. second quality,  .00; fashionable Silk Hats, 2.50; fine calf skin sewed Boots, 3.50; Congress Gaiter Boots, 3. ; fine calf skin sewed Shoes, 2.25.  


 J. H. Anthony has made arrangements with one of the best makers in the city of Philadelphia to supply him with handsome and substantial calf skin sewed Boots, which he will sell at the unprecedented low price of three Dollars and A half oc 25--d&amp;wts.   
 
Rice 


 --15 tierces fresh, for sale by  


 Lewis Webb &amp; John G. Wade.     
 
Auction Salesfuture days.by Goddin &amp; Apperson, Auct's. 
 
Commissioner's sale of the beautiful country Seat called "Mount comfort," half mile Northeast of Richmond. 


 --As Commissioner appointed by the decrees of the Circuit Court of Henrico, rendered on the 20th October, 1860 in the case of Moncure, &amp;c., against Daniel's Ext, &amp;c., I shall, as special Commissioner thereby appointed, proceed to sell, at public auction, on the premises, on Monday, the 12th November, 1860, at 11 o'clock A. M., (If fair; if not, the next fair day,) the beautiful Country Seat of which Judge Peter V. Daniel died seized called "Mount Comfort," containing about 90 acres, more or less.

A plat and survey of the land will be exhibited at the time of sale, showing the sizes of the different subdivisions.

There is on the place a comfortable Brick Dwelling, and the usual out-buildings, together with an excellent Orchard, and many handsome Shade Trees, and several excellent Springs.

The lots will vary in size from 10 to 20 acres, each according to their relative position.

Taking into consideration its beautiful and elevated position, its noted healthfulness, and nearness to the city of Richmond, it is believed that few if any more desirable places have been brought into market for a long time past.  


 Terms--One-fourth cash; balance at 6, 12 and 18 months, for negotiable notes, interest added, and title retained till all the purchase money is fully paid, and a conveyance ordered by the Court.  


 Peter V. Daniel, Jr.  


 no 1 Special Commissioner.   
 
Auction sale of eighteen valuable Slaves, at Ashland, Hanover county, Va. 


 --At the request of the Richmond and Fredericksburg Railroad Company, we shall sell at public auction, at Ashland, Hanover county, on the said Railroad, 16 miles north of  Richmond, 18 valuable Slaves, conveyed to said Company by Mr. Edwin Robinson.

These Slaves are in families and are not only likely, but are of excellent character.

They are all young, embracing Cooks House Servants, Washers, &amp;c. Farmers and other persons disposed to purchase Servants for their own use, would do well to attend the sale : and to accommodate such, and to enable the Servants, as far as practicable, to obtain owners in this State, they will be sold on a credit of 4 months, for approved, endorsed negotiable paper, interest added.

The sale will take place at Ashland, on Wednesday, the 14th November, 1860, at 10 o'clock A. M. Persons leaving Richmond in the morning cars can attend the sale, and return the same day by 2½ o'clock P. M.  


 no 1 Goddin &amp; Apperson, Auct'rs.   
 
Two valuable Tenements on the East side of Valley, between Richard and Balding streets, for sale at Auction. 


 --Will be sold at auction, on the premises, on Wednesday, the 7th November, 1860, at 4 o'clock P. M., a very excellent Brick Tenement, now in the occupancy of Mr. Adams, and a new Framed Cottage Dwelling on the north occupied by --. The lot has a front of 100 feet, and a depth of 165 feet. The property is in good repair, and rents to good tenants at fair rents.  


 Terms.--One-third cash; balance at 4 and 8 months, for negotiable notes, interest added and title retained till last note is paid.  


 no 1 Goddin &amp; Apperson, Aucts.   
 
By E. B. Cook, Auct'r. 


Genteel Household Furniture at Auction.--On Monday, Nov. 5th at 10 o'clock, I will sell at the residence of P. W. Dudley, Esq., on Leigh, between 6th and 7th sts., all his Household Furniture, consisting in part of--  


 Sofas, Divans, Mahogany and Rosewood Chairs.  


 Marble-top Tables, Brussels Carpets.  
 Hat Backs, Floor Oil Cloth.  
 Wardrobes, Bedsteads,  


 Feather Beds, Mattresses.  
 Looking-Glasses, Washstands.  
 Cane and Wood seat Chairs.  


 Dining and other Tables.  


 Refrigerator, safe.  


 The usual variety of China, Glass and Crockery Ware, together with many other housekeeping articles too numerous to mention, all of which is in good condition.

E. B. Cook,  
 no 1 Auctioneer.   
 
Valuable Farm and ten likely Slaves, for sale, in the county of Hanover. 


 --As Commissioner appointed by the Circuit Court of Hanover county, by a decree rendered on the 6th of October, 1860, in the suit of Talley, &amp;c. vs. Talley, &amp;c, I will sell on the 29th of November next (if fair; if not, the next fair day,) on the premises, the Tract of Land on which John Talley, dec'd. lately resided, containing 252 acres, within 13 miles of Richmond, and 3 miles of the Old Church, and adjoining the lands of R. R. Horn. B. W. Talley and others.

It has upon it a Dwelling with six rooms, and all necessary outhouses.

It lies well for improvement, and is well suited for marketing, as well as farming purposes; is in a good neighborhood and convenient to churches, schools and mills.

Mr. Loving, on the premises, will take pleasure in showing it. Also, on the same day, on the premises, ten likely Slaves, most of which are good field hands, and a No. 1 Cook, Washer and Ironer.  


 Terms--For the Slaves, cash.

For the Land, one-third cash; one third in one year, and the remaining one third in two years, the deferred payments carrying interest from day of sale, and the purchaser executing his bonds with good and sufficient security, and the title retained until the whole of the purchase money is paid, and a conveyance directed by the Court.  


 T. W. Talley, Commissioner.  
 At the same time and place, will be sold all the Household and Kitchen Furniture, crops, stock and Farming Implements of every description, belonging to the estate of John Talley, dec'd.  


 Terms--On day of sale.

B. W. Talley,  
 no 1--1m* Administrator.   
 
By Richard Cauthorn, Auct'r. 


Dry Goods, Clothing, Shoes, &amp;c. On Friday, 2d day of November, at 10 o'clock, at my store, I will sell at auction, a lot of Goods, consisting in part of Ready made Coats and Pantaloons, Woollen Hose, Beached and Unbleached Cotton Hose and Half-Hose. Shoe Laces, Umbrellas, Blankets, Shoes, Slippers, &amp;c  


 no 1 R. Cauthorn, Auct.    
 
Life Insurance, &amp;c. 
 
Old Dominion Insurance Company.--Capital $200,000! 


Office--No. 42 Main street, under St. Charles Hotel.  


 This Company is now prepared to receive applications for Fire and Marine Insurance on favorable terms.  
 
Directors: 
Gab. Wertham, John H. Greanor,  
John Enders, Geo. S. Palmer,  
Samuel M. Price, Wm. S. Triplet,  
B. F. Ladd, S. C. Tardy,  
Jno. Stewart Walker, Wm. Currie,  
Luther R. Spilman, Jas. R. Crenshaw,  
Peter C. Warwick, John H. Williams,  
Jas. S. Kent, Mark Downey,  
Horace P. Edmond, Thomas Jones,  
James M. Talbott, Edwin A. Smith,  
Griffin B. Davenport, Ro. A. Paine,  
Geo. W. Yancey, Ro. F. Williams,  
Jos. Brummel, Wm. P. Ragland,  
Wm. Brent, Henry C. Cabell,  
Ro. H. Maury Geo. W. Royster,   


 Isaac Davenport, Jr. Pres't.  


 Chas. E. Wortham, Sec'y. my 19--ts   
 
Fire Insurance.Marine Insurance(Incorporated 1832.)the Virginia Fire and Marine Insurance Company. 


 Office No. 131 Main Street, Richmond.  


 Capital and Surplus, $230,000!  


 This Company has the advantage of twenty-seven years experience in the Insurance business, and having enjoyed the favor of the public during all of that period needs no special recommendation to the citizens of Virginia.  


 It effects Fire Insurance in city and country, and Marine Insurance to all parts of the world.  


 Its cash capital and surplus are as above, and its affairs are managed prudently, but liberally, and its rates are as low as those of any other good institution.

Directors:  


 W. L. Cowardin, J. E. Wadsworth, Patrick Cullen,  


 Joseph Allen, Wm. Beers, Geo. W. Smith,  


 Horace L. Kent, Thos. Samson, B. L. Winston,  
 Wm. Palmer, Chas. W. Purcell, Jno. N. Gordon,  
 Alex. R. Parker, Jos. P. Winston, Arch. Thomas,  


 Jas. A. Inloes, H. A. Claiborne,  
 Apply to the President or Secretary, in person or by letter.

W. L. Cowardin, President.  
Wm. Willis. Jr., Secretary.--ts   
 
A Card. 


 --We very earnestly request customers and others, who have our Bags, to send them to us full of grain, if ready to send it, or empty, by the next train.

We are suffering great inconvenience for want of our Bags that are idle in various hands who have neglected to return them.

In a short time we must make up bag accounts and charge the holders with them.

When we send bags to any person, they should be returned promptly.  


 Much of the wheat we receive is damp.

Farmers ought to dry it at home.

Barns, granaries and "all out of doors" are big enough to spread it in. Farmers lose immensely by inattention to this point.  


 We have fallen on perilous times, when debt is fearful.

Filling orders for guano, &amp;c., on the faith of growing crops, won't do for those who have to buy them on time.

A safe principle of individual economy is to make money before we spend it.  


 se 19--ts Maddux &amp; Co.   
 
Read this!Special notice. 


 I have not discontinued business on account of the falling of my store.

I am how located Five Doors above my old stand, next door to C. W. Purcell &amp; Co.'s Brokers' Office, and near Governor; on Main street, No. 126, where I would be pleased to meet my old customers, and the customers generally.

Those in the habit of giving me their orders for Fall Clothing, will do me a favor to wait until I can call on them, or leave word at my store when to call on them, and all orders in my line will be as promptly attended to as heretofore.

I have not, and don't intend to discontinue business for any such cause.

Call and see me, at 126 Main street. [an 23--ts] Wm. Ira Smith.   
 
Manchester scale Works. 


 --We have on hand from the above factory, Platform Scales, weighing from 400 to 2000 lbs.-- Also, Counter Scales of every variety, and is agents for the manufacturers are prepared to take orders for railroad track, depot and ware house Scales, &amp;c., which for neatness, durability and accuracy cannot be surpassed.  


 Van-Lew. Taylor &amp; Co.,  


 l 24--1v No. 74 Main street.   
 
Hosiery.

Hosiery!! 


 --Just landed, of our own importation:  


 7,000 doz. Ladies' Cotton Hose, all qualities  


 1,000 doz. Misses' Cotton Hose, all sizes and qualities;  


 1,000 doz. Gents' Cotton half-Hose, all qualities;  


 Also, 1,000 doz. L. C. Hdkfs., all grades.  


 All of which we offer to the trade at a small advance upon cost of importation.  


 Ginter, Alvey &amp; Arents,  


  2--ts Importers and Jobbers, Main st.   
 
 


As Agent of several first class Fire Insurance Companies, the undersigned is prepared to issue.  


 short-term Policies.  


 to protect increased stocks of goods during the coming season.  


 Merchants desiring additional insurance are solicited to call on J. H. Montague,  


 se 1--3tawta Merchants' Insurance Co.   
 
Office of R. H. Maury &amp; Co 


Richmond, August 23, 1860.  


 Stocks and Bonds for sale.--Virginia six per cents.  


 Orange and Alexandria Railroad six per cents.  


 Shares Bank of Commonwealth stock.  
 Shares Farmers' Bank stock.  


 Shares Bank of Virginia stock. au --ts     
 
Auction Salesfuture days.by Goddin &amp; Apperson, Auct's. 
 
Omnibus and Harness for sale at Auction 


 --Will be sold at auction.

at the American Hotel Stables, corner of Cary and 10th streets, on Saturday, the 3d November. 1860, at 12 o'clock, one light two-horse Omnibus and an excellent set of Harness.

The said Omnibus and Harness will be sold at the rises and costs of the purchaser, at a former sale made on the 29th September, 1860, he having failed to comply with the terms of sale.  


 Terms.--Four months credit, for approved endorsed negotiable no  s  


 W. Goddin. Trustees.  
 J. L. Apperson, Trustees.  
 Goddin &amp; Apperson, Aucts oc 31   
 
140 Acres of valuable Wood Land, near to Branch's meeting House, 4½ miles from Manchester.

For sale at Auction 


Will be sold at auction, at Branch's Meeting-House, on Monday, the 5th November, 1860, at 12 o'clock, 140 acres of valuable Wood Land, located as above, adjoining the tract on which Dr. D. C. Winfree now resides.

It is partly in original growth, and mainly in secondary growth of pines, which is admirably adapted to the brick business.

Two loads can easily be made daily to Manchester.  


 Terms.--One-third cash; balance at 6 and 12 months, for negotiable notes, bearing interest, and title retained till all the notes are paid.  


 oc 25--td Goddin &amp; Apperson, Aucts   
 
Commissioner's sale of a Lot in the town of Sydney, on the West side of Plumb, between Elmwood and Dover streets. 


 --As Commissioner appointed by a decree of the Circuit Court of Henrico, pronounced on the 8th November, 1859, in the case of "Degenhardt, &amp;c., against Thacker, &amp;c.," I shall proceed to sell at public auction, on the premises, on Monday, the 5th November, 1860, at 4 o'clock P. M., (if fair; if not the next fair day,) the Real Estate purchased by Joseph Saunders, at a sale made on the 13th August, 1858, by Messrs. P. Roberts and W. W. Crump, Commissioners, and which he has failed to pay for, viz: A Lot, located as above, fronting 55 feet on the west side of Plumb street, running back 70 feet.  


 Terms.--One-third cash; balance at 6 and 12 months, for negotiable notes, interest added, and title retained till all the purchase money is paid.  


 W. Goddin, Com'r.  


 Goddin &amp; Apperson, Aucts. oc 16--tds   
 
Valuable Farm in Henrico, Five miles above Richmond, Slaves and stock, for sale. 


 --Having determined to remove to Richmond to reside I will sell at public auction, on the premises, on Thursday, the 8th November, 1860, at 11 o'clock A. M., (if fair; if not, on first fair day thereafter,) the Farm on which I now reside, lying on the Richmond and Fredericksburg Railroad, five miles above Richmond, containing 170 acres of land.

After the sale of the land, I will sell, in like manner, my Slaves.

Milch Cows, Horses, Mules, Corn, Oats, Fodder, Household and Kitchen Furniture one Rockaway, and two Carts, and whatever else there may be on the farm for sale.  


 Terms.--For the land, a credit of 1, 2, and 3 years, bearing interest, secured by personal and real security.

For the slaves, a credit of 6 months, interest added, for negotiable notes and approved endorsers.

For the resident of the personal property, cash for all sums under $50; over that amount, 6 months credit, for bonds with good security.

Joseph Bernard.  


 Sale by Goddin &amp; Apperson, Aucts. oc 30   
 
Commissioners' sale of House and Lot on Church Hill, on the West line of 25th. Between Broad and Marshall streets. 


By virtue of two decrees of the Circuit Court of Henrico, in the case of Jones against Kirkmeyer's adm'r, pronounced, the one on the 8th Nov., 1858, and the other 27th Oct., 1860, the undersigned commissioners will proceed to sell at public auction, on the premises, on Friday, the 9th Nov., 1860 at 4 o'clock P. M., (if fair; if not, the next fair day,) the real estate of which Frederick Kirkmeyer died seized, consisting of a House and Lot, located as above, fronting about 50 feet on the west side of 25th street, running back 120 feet to an alley.  


 Terms.--One-third cash; balance at 12 and 18 months, for bonds, bearing interest, with good personal security, and title retained till all the purchase money is paid.  


 Thomas P. August, Comr's.  
 Jno. B. Young, Comr's.  
 oc 30--10t Eaton Nance.

Comr's. 
 Sale conducted by Goddin &amp; Apperson.   
 
Commissioner's sale of Lot. In the county of Henrico, in the town of Sydney. 


 --As Commissioner appointed by a decree of the Circuit Court of Henrico, pronounced on the 1st November, 1859, in the case of Drummond, Trustee for Ayres, against Keins, I shall proceed to sell at public auction, on the premises, on Saturday, the 10th November, 1860, at 4 o'clock P. M., (if fair; if not the next fair day, except Sunday,) the following real estate, belonging to Jno. W. Reins.

as appears by the Commissioner's books and referred to in the plaintiff's bill, viz: "half-Acre", adjoining Richard Reins, two miles from Court House.  


 Terms.--One-third cash; balance at 6 and 12 months, for negotiable notes, satisfactorily endorsed, and title retained till all the purchase money is paid.

George W. Randolph.  
 oc 30--td Commissioner.  


 Sale conducted by Goddin &amp; Apperson.   
 
By James M. Taylor &amp; Son, Auct'rs. 


Trustee's sale of 18 3-4 Acres of Land on the Old Deep run Turnpike, Henrico county.--By virtue of a deed of trust from Christopher Worbinton and wife to the subscriber, dated the 2d day of August, 1859, and of record in Henrico County Court Office, I shall, at the request of the beneficiary, and with the consent of the said Worbinton, proceed to sell at public auction, upon the premises, on Monday, the 12th day of November, (if fair; if not the next fair day thereafter) commencing at 4 o'clock P. M., the real estate conveyed in said deed, viz: A tract of land containing 18 ¼ acres, lying on the Old Deep-Run Turnpike, in Henrico county, 5 ½ miles west of the city, and now occupied by said Worbinton.

Also, one Mule, two Carts, and all the Household and Kitchen Furniture now in the possession of said Worbinton.  


 Terms.--For the real estate, enough in cash to defray the expenses of this trust, and a negotiable note for $206, with interest thereon from 5th of February, 1860, till paid; the further sum of $350 on the --day December, 1861, and the remainder upon such terms as will be fixed upon by said Worbinton.

For the personal property, cash will be required.

A. R. Courtney, Trustee.  
 Jas. M. Taylor &amp; Son Auct's oc 24   
 
A very desirable Brick Residence on Grace, between 28th and 29th streets, Church Hill, for sale at Auction. 


 --We will sell, upon the premises on Thursday, the 15th day of November, commencing at 4½ o'clock P. M., the very desirable Brick Residence, now occupied by Mrs. Rebecca C. Brett, on Grace, between 28th and 29th streets, Church Hill.

It has seven good rooms, is very convenient, and extremely pleasant, besides a Brick Kitchen.  


 The Lot Fronts on Grace street 31 feet, and runs back 157 feet to an alley 16 feet wide.

Mrs. Brett, residing upon the premises, will take pleasure in showing the same to those desiring to purchase.  


 Terms.--One-fourth cash; the balance at 4, 8, and 12 months, for negotiable notes, with interest added, and secured by a trust deed.  


 oc 31 Jas. M. Taylor &amp; Son, Aucts.   
 
By Edmond, Davenport &amp; Co., Auct's. 


Cargo sale of Liverpool fine and Ground Alum Salt at Auction. On Friday, November 2d, at 11 o'clock A. M., we will sell at auction, at our Warehouse, head of the Dock, the cargo of Salt per ship Pioneer. direct from Liverpool, consisting of--  


 4,500 sacks fine Salt, Worthington Brand.  


 500 sacks Ground Alum Salt.  


 Edmond, Davenport &amp; Co., Aucts.  


 P. S.--The Salt will be sold deliverable at City Point or Richmond at the option of the purchaser  


o c 29 E., D. &amp; Co., Aucts.    
 
 
 
Prepare for Cold weather. 


 --All persons in want of Clothing, will find at 103 Main street, every article of wearing apparel to suit the approaching season.

Our goods are stylish and durable.

Call and see for yourselves.  


 Noah Walker &amp; Co.,  


 103, corner Main and 14th, or Pearl sts.   
 
Toilet Mirrors, 


 Toilet Soaps of all kinds.

Toilet Waiters, Combs, Brushes, Colognes, Handkerchief Extracts, Pomatums, and all other Hair preparations, Cosmetics and Toilet requisites, for sale at  


 Joseph Laidley's Apothecary,  


 Sign of the Red Mortar, 5th and Main sts.   
 
35 hhds. 


 prime Bacon Sides and Shoulders; 100 boxes Cutting and E. D. Cheese; 300 boxes Adamantine Candles; 100 boxes Jackson's Candles; 200 boxes Altmeyer's Candles, 200 boxes Brown Soap; 100 bags Java Coffee, in store, for sale by Massie &amp; Pleasants.   
 
Overcoats, Overcoats 


 --Of every style, quality and shape-Black Sack Overcoats, Black English style surtout Overcoats, Black Rib Sack and Frock Overcoats, and every other style to suit the taste of all. Noah Walker &amp; Co.,  


 103. cor. Main and 14th or Pearl sts.   
 
Genuine Meerschaum Pipes 


 and Cigar-Holders, a large variety of handsome styles, for sale at  


 Joseph Laidley's Apothecary,  


 Sign of the Red Mortar, 5th and Main sts.   
 
1,223 bales Hay 


 --A prime article, and perfectly dry, discharging from schr. Claremont.

Send in your orders to  


 R. H. Whitlock &amp; Son.   
 
Glycerine, 


 Honey, Low's Genuine Brown Windsor Soap, and all other fine Toilet and Shaving Soaps, for sale at  


 Joseph Laidley's Apothecary,  


 Sign of the Red Mortar, 5th and Main sts.   
 
Something New--Solidified Milk. 


 Dried and granulated from pure Milk, and warranted to contain nothing but Milk and Sugar.  


 Meade &amp; Baker, Druggists,  


 186 Main st., corner above Post-Office.   
 
Havana Cigars. 


 --I have just received a fresh supply of Havana Cigars, of superior and choice brands.

Also, a first-rate article of Smoking Tobacco, in pound and half pound boxes.  


 W. L. Waring, No. 107 Broad st, above 9th.   
 
Chewing Tobacco. 


 --A small lot of Booker &amp; Halsey's celebrated "Lecompte" brand; also, a variety of other favorite brands.

For sale by W. Peterson &amp; Co, Druggists,  


155 Main street.   
 
Patent Starch 


 --Which requires no boiling, and can be prepared in a few minutes.

It is especially adapted to fine goods, For sale at  


 Joseph Laidley's Apothecary,  


 Sign of the Red Mortar, 5th and Main sts.   
 
Fine Toilet Soaps. 


 --Old Brown Windsor; English Honey and Glycerine Soaps; Taylor's and Colgate's Soaps; a great variety at low prices, at Powers' Drug Store,  


 No. 43, corner Main and 15th streets.   
 
Premium Butter. 


 --I have in store the fresh Butter made by Mrs. Lou. J. Hansburger, which took the premium at the late fair Call and get some.

Wm. G. Dandridge,  
 No. 105 Broad st.   
 
Coal Oil Lamps. 


 --New and beautiful patterns of the above Lamps, together with extra Chimneys.

Wicks, and the best Coal Oil, for sale at the China Store of  


 Thos, A. Bulkley &amp; Co. 137 Main st.   
 
Gents' Double Sole Gaiters 


 --Also, Single Sale that cannot be excelled for durability and beauty and cheap, at No. 43 Main street, sign of the Big Boot, by Wm. Walsh.   
 
Pure Medicinal Wines, 


 Brandy and Whiskey, warranted Pure, for sale at  


 Joseph Laidley's Apothecary,  


 Sign of the Red Mortar, 5th and Main sts.   
 
No. 1 Chocolate.-- 


 For sale by  


 Dove &amp;Co., Wholesale Druggists,     
 
Auction Sales.this day.by J. H. Digges, Auct'r. 
 
Closing sale of balance Japanese Goods at Auction — this Morning. 


  Nov. 1st, at 10 o'clock, at Auction Room 86 Main street, consisting of some valuable goods, viz: Work Boxes. Table Trays, Cups, Tureens, &amp;c. &amp;c. Also 1 fine Gold Hunting Case American Lever Watch used but very little, together with a lot of new and second-hand Gold and Silver Watches, to close a consignment and cover advances.

Terms.--Cash.  


 J. H. Digges, Auct'r.  
 D. F. Booth. Salesman.

no 1   
 
Fine Gold and Silver Watches.

Jewelry, Fancy Goods, &amp;c. 


 --Will be sold at auction, every night this week, at Auction Room 86 Main street. Also a lot of Blankets Undershirts, Drawers fine Table Cutlery, Plated Spoons, Forks, &amp;c., &amp;c. Sale will commence at 7 o'clock, P. M. J. H. Digges, Auct.  


 D. F. Booth, Salesman.

oc 23--ts   
 
By Alex.

Nott, Auct'r.Furniture, Clothing, Dry Goods, &amp;c. 


 --Will be sold at auction, at my store, on Thursday,November 1, commencing at 10 o'clock, a lot of Furniture from a family leaving the city, consisting of Hair and Shuck Mattresses, edate ds, Tables, Carpets.

Bureaus, Chairs, Stoves, Crockery and Glassware.  


Also — A large lot of Ready-Made Clothing, consisting of Coats, Pants, Vests, &amp;c ; Cloths, Cassimeres, Satinets, &amp;c.  


 Groceries.--Whiskey, Brandy, Soap, Candles, Tobacco, Cigars, &amp;c. Alex. Nott.  


oc 31 Auctioneer.    
 
 
1860.

Fall Trade.

1860.direct importation. 


Clarkson, Anderson &amp; Co., No. 106. Main Street. Richmond, Va., Importers of Hardware, Cutlery, Guns, and Anchor Belting Cloths, have received, per ship "Susan Hinks," direct to this port, their Fall importation of fine and heavy Hardware; and from the manufacturers in the Eastern States their goods of American make, to which they invite the attention of the merchants of Virginia, Tennessee and North Carolina, guaranteeing to sell as cheap as can be bought in any city, North or East, They are also agents for "Fairbank's" very celebrated Scales, which they sell at manufacturers' prices.  


 N. B.--Orders shall receive their prompt and careful attention.   
 
Cheap Dry Goods at Levy's Famed Store of bargains 


 --Grass Linen Handkerchiefs at 25 cents worth 50 cents; Yard wide unbleached Cotton at 8½ cents, worth 10 cents; White Cotton Diaper, for Bed Spreads or Table Cloths, at 25 cents, well worth 33 cents; Fine Embroidered Collars at 50 cents, worth 75 cents; White and Colored Marseilles Shirt Bosoms at 12½ cents, worth 25 cents : Superfine Irish Linen Cambric Handkerchiefs at 25 cents, worth 37½ cts; Hemstitched Embroidered Linen Handkerchiefs at 50 cents, worth 75 cents; Linen Handkerchiefs (warranted pure and full size) at 6½ cents worth 8½.

Bleached and unbleached Cottons sold very cheap.

By all means, go to Levy's, for there you can find Dry Goods at prices that cannot fail to please.   
 
Will open this Morning! 


 --At Ezekiel's, 41 Main street, 500 yards 5-4 Heavy White Goods, for Counterpanes; 6 yards make a Spread 12-4 square for only $1.50, to cover the largest bed. Come and see!

Also, 500 yards all styles Woollen Goods, for Men and Boys' wear; the greatest inducements offered; come and see.--Linen and Marseilles Bosoms, in Sets, 500 Superfine Linen and Marseilles Bosoms, with or without Collars and Cuffs to match.

These are gotten up splendidly, and will be sold, ready made, as low as the material can be purchased for. All styles new Dress Goods cheap, cheap, cheap, at  


 Ezekiel's, 41 Main street,  


 Mailert's Old Stand.   
 
Powers' Glycerin Balm 


 --An effectual cure and preventive against chapping or any roughness of the skin, occasioned by chafing, or exposure to heat or cold.

Its balmy effects is such that it renders the skin peculiarly soft, and may be applied with advantage to the most delicate infant.

This preparation combines the healing and the protective properties of Glycerin, with those of other bland and balsamic agents, which serve to restore primitive delicacy, after washing and drying the skin, apply the Balm with the hand and allow it to dry on the surface.

For any irritation produced by shaving, and for chapping of the skin, to which children are subject, it is peculiarly grateful.

No. 48, Cor. Main and 15TH sts.   
 
 


Visitors to the Fair will find at Meade &amp; Baker's Family Drug Store a full supply of the most reliable Medicines, Chemicals, Drugs, Pharmaceutical Products; popular Patent Medicines; pure Virginia Coal Oil; Spices, Cigars, Tobacco; the most select and finest French Pomades, Soaps, Perfumery, Combs, Brushes, Porte-Monnaies, Farina Colognes, Family Medicine Chests and Physicians' Saddle Bags, Surgical Instruments and Appliances, of every kind.  


 Meade &amp; Baker, Druggists,  


 186 Main street, N. W. corner 10th.  


 Just above the Post Office.   
 
 


The Wedding Ring is emblematic of the marriage relation.

Gold will wear out by friction, abrasion, &amp;c.; but never rusts — never tarnishes — is always bright.

Thus, with life, the Ring is without end; so likewise is the union without interruption or end, except by the death of the parties.  


The Wedding Ring being plain, shows that the fair one to whom it is given is, in the estimation of the giver the most perfect and loveable of her sex, needing not the foreign aid of ornament to render her just the woman for him to love and cherish all his days.  


 A good assortment of plain Gold Rings, suitable for Wedding Rings, just finished, can be found at 96 Main street, where will be found Watches, Jewelry, Silver Ware, Silver plated Ware, Spectacles, &amp;c, &amp;c. Watches, Jewelry and Spectacles repaired in the best manner.   
 
 


L. Wagner, Druggist and Apothecary, keeps on hand a general and well assorted stock of Drugs, Medicines, Paints, Oils, Varnish, Brushes, Glass, Putty, genuine Patent Medicines, Medicinal Liquor and Wines; Imported and Domestic Cigars; Turkish and American Smoking Tobacco; Hair, Tooth, Nail, Cloth and Shoe Brushes; Combs, Pocket-Books, Ports-Monnaies, Cologne, Hair Oils and fine Extracts.

The best article of Coal Oil, and Burning Fluid always on hand.

Cor. 6TH and Broad sts.   
 
 


Lubin's Genuine French Extracts for the Handkerchief; Lubin's Soaps, English Honey, Brown Windsor, and other choice Toilet Soaps; Toilet Mirrors; Hair Preparations of all kinds; genuine Tortoise Shell Combs; Ivory, Horn and India Rubber Combs; Hair Brushes; Tooth, Nail and other Brushes, in store, and having all been bought for cash, will be sold cheap, at Jos. Laidley's.  


 Family Medicine Store,  
 Sign of the Red Mortar 5th and Main sts.   
 
Cough Remedies. 


 --Bodeker's Pulmonary Balsam, Ayer's Cherry Pectoral, Wistar's Balsam of Wild Cherry, Mrs. Gardney's Balsam Liverwort, Mrs Daws' Cough Elixir, Thompson's syrup Tar and Naphtha, Hasting's Syrup Naphtha, Jayne's Expectorant, Rose's Cough Syrup, Dr, Butler's Syrup Tolu, Bryan's Pulmonic Wafers, Brown's Bronchial Troches, for sale by  


 A. Bodeker &amp; Co., Apothecaries,  


 Main street, near Old Market.   
 
Silver Plated Ware. 


 --Thomas A. Bulkley &amp;Co.

are now receiving a fresh stock of rich Plated Tea Sets, Tea and Coffee Urns, Butter Dishes, Candlesticks, Ice Water Pitchers, Cake Baskets, Goblets, Mugs, Spoons and Forks, Castors. &amp;c. The above goods are made expressly for our sales, and we warrant them to be of the best quality, and worthy the attention of purchasers.  


 T. A. Bulkley &amp; Co.   
 
Holloway's worm Confections 


 --The most pleasant and effectual worm medicine ever discovered.

It is a remedy that no child will refuse, but rather crave, as it possesses none of those nauseous ingredients of which other worm destroyers are composed.

It is put up in the form of beautiful sugar plums.

For sale by  


 A. Bodeker &amp; Co., Druggists,  


 Main street, near Old Markets.   
 
 


Meade &amp; Baker's "Elixir Calisaya Bark" is made in the most careful manner, from the best species of Peruvian Bark, (that from which Quinine is made;) is very palatable, and highly recommended by our own physicians, for loss of appetite and to prevent a relapse after chills and bilious fevers.

Prepared only by  


Meade &amp; Baker, Pharmaceutists,  


 186 Main st., corner above Post Office.   
 
Glycerine 


 --Honey and Poncine Soaps, Cold Cream, Otto Rose Lip Salve, Glycerine Lotion, Church's Lotion for the skin; also, Rowland's Kalydor, Bay Rum, Colognes, Handkerchief Extracts, all colors, and many other indispensable Toilet Articles, in store for sale by  


 P. Johnston &amp; Bro., Druggists.   
 
Fancy Cassimere Pants--500 pair 


 --Embracing every variety, style and quality, French, English and American Cassimere, in latest patterns, all qualities, fashionable out, low prices; Black Cassimere Pants, single and double milled; Tricot Waved Face, French Twill, and plain, all prices.

110 Main street.  


 Shafer, Halsey &amp; Co.   
 
 


Extra quality Coal Oil and Burning Fluid.

Also, Cox's Gelatine; pure ground Pepper for family and Restaurant use; old Castile Soap; Gales' superior American Shaving Soap; Window Glass and Putty.

For sale by  


 L. Wagner. Druggist.  
 Corner 6th and Broad sts.   
 
Dissecting Cases at Northern prices! 


 --Dissecting Cases at Northern Prices!!--Dissecting Cases at Northern Prices!!!-- Medical Students invited to call and examine our assortment before purchasing.  


 Meade &amp; Baker, Pharmaceutists,  


 186 Main st., corner above Post-Office.   
 
Guns, Guns. 


 --A full assortment of double and single Guns, of this seasons' importation, very desirable patterns.

Fine English Bridles and superior hard Solder; Snaffle, Curb Bits and Stirrup Irons; for sale by  


 Van-Lew, Taylor &amp;Co.,  


 No. 74 Main street.   
 
Buffalo Tongues. 


 --Just received, a small lot of fine Buffalo Tongues, Smoked Salmon, very fine; Sugar-Cured Hams of fine quality and flavor; for sale by  


 Brooke Pleasants, Agent,  


 No. 2 Main street, corner 17th.   
 
Look at this! 


 --2,000 yards more cheap Carpeting, opening this morning, only 24 cts, the yard, a first-rate article for chambers, &amp;c., beautiful fast colors.

Call soon and select before the prettiest are picked out. Only think, a large room 18 feet square can now be carpeted for $6.--Call soon at Ezekiel's Cheap Stores,  


 41 Main st., Mailert's Old Stand.   
 
Paints, Oils, and Brushes 


 --White Lead; Lewis' pure best White-Zine; Chrome, Green and Yellow, dry and oil; Paris Green; Verdigris; Umber, burnt an dry; Linseed Oil, raw and boiled; Paint Brushes, Sash Tools; and everything in the painter's line, for sale cheap at the New Drug Store corner Main and 15th sts.  


 R. W. Powers.   
 
Breakfast Cigars 
 --A very excellent, veritable Havana, very cheap, and well flavored Cigar, for sale at  


 Jos. Laidley's Family Medicine Store,  
 Sign of the Red Mortar., 5th and Main sts.   
 
Oyster, Vegetable, and Beef Steak Dishes 


 --All sizes of the above Dishes, of the best English Block Tin, of our own importation, recently opened, and for sale by  


 Thos. A. Bulkley &amp; Co.   
 
Flavoring Extracts, 


 all colors; Cox's Gelatine; Sheet and Shred Isinglass; Vanilla Beans; Celery Seed, and Pickling Spices, all kinds, for sale by P. Johnston &amp; Bro., Druggists.   
 
Cutting Cheese 


 --100 boxes prime Cutting Cheese, just received per schr. Danville, for sale by Wm. Wallace Sons.      
 
 


 Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume 13, Number 105, page 4.     
 
Richmond Dispatch 
 
Thursday Morning......nov 1, 1860. 
 
The Horror in the Housein two parts.part II.--concluded. 


"On the point of leaving, Mawry turned round, and carelessly observed: 'I take it for granted, my dear madam, that you have an excellent watcher in your husband; but you need some care.

Who may I ask, is your principal attendant?'--Mary smiled. 'Who, for example, makes your tea?'  


 "'The housemaid, Hepzibah, generally; but sometimes old Oh'--Mary checked herself.  


 "'I beg your pardon--who?'  


 "'I was about to name an old woman we have taken into the house to help the housemaid, but, for some reason I have not inquired, she does not wish it to be known.'  


 "'Old Charlotte!' ejaculated Mawry.  


 "'Such is her name,' replied Mary, astonished at his astonishment.  


 "Mawry, who had sat down again, got up with a face white as ashes.  


 "'I — I have a word to say to Mr. Ainsley,' he said, and took a hasty leave.  


 "Charles was reading medicine in the Angel-room.  


 "'Good Heavens, sir!' exclaimed the little doctor, bursting in, 'do you know what you have got in your house?'  


 "Horrid visions of his Mary in typhus fever — in small-pox — a lunatic — flashed like lightning across Charles's mind.  


 "'What--what ?' he gasped out.  


 "'Moll Murder!'  


 "'Moll what?'  


 "'The old bag to whom the boys in the town have given that title, for her strange association with every death that has occurred in this unhappy house since it became your uncle's. The very worst suspicions cleave to her. For mercy's sake, Mr. Ainsley, get rid of this old wretch before you are an hour older!'  


 "Charles stood aghast. 'Is it — possible that'--  


 "'I know not what is possible; but do it, sir — do it,' said the eager apothecary; and Charles, infected with his earnestness, promised compliance.  


 "That night Charlotte was dismissed, this time taking her pattens with her, as though her work were done.  


 "'Touched and took!' was Charlotte's benediction, looking back and shaking her finger as she passed the door.  


 "Let me pass quickly over these sad details, The young wife was indeed doomed.

Drooping gradually, like the preceding victims, she slowly but certainly followed them to the same bourne.  


 "Ainsley would have left the house, but nothing could induce Mary to consent.

His uncle would be vexed; would think them careless, ungrateful — besides, they had no other home.

Most of all she earnestly desired, if die she must, to breathe her last in the Angel-chamber, with those glorious eyes and protecting arms above her.  


 "She had her wish; and, in a few short weeks, the fourth victim to the mystery of that house slept in the village churchyard.  


 "The popular feeling against old Charlotte had by this time attained such open expression, that it became absolutely necessary to investigate its grounds.

She was accordingly given into custody.

Some examinations took place; but the doctor being compelled to certify to a case of natural death, and no direct inculpatory evidence being adduced, the prisoner, on the very day of poor Mary's funeral, was restored to liberty, and immediately disappeared.  


 "It was now imagined that the house would be finally closed.

The next-door neighbor on one side had already quitted; he on the other had given notice.

Mr. Archbold himself felt his mind infected by the prevailing superstition; and, moreover, seeing the cause of misunderstanding removed, was ready enough to give indulgence to his returning kindness towards his nephew, to whom he accordingly wrote, desiring him to quit without delay the scene of his bereavement, and resume the place he had formerly held in his uncle's home and affection.  


 "Charles refused.  


 "He considered that his uncle, in placing them in a house under this notorious ban, had been actuated by less disinterested motives than he had imagined, and had been even in some degree instrumental in the fatal misfortune that had befallen him. Besides, he had a duty to perform, to which it was his fixed determination to devote every energy he possessed — nay, if needful, life itself.

He would find out the mystery of the haunted house.

And no knight, in quest of the holy grail, ever started on the doubtful way with more resolved purpose than Charles, when, returning from his Mary's funeral, he re-entered the desolate mansion.  


 "He was alone, absolutely alone; for poor Hephzibah, though attached to her master, and pitying him with all her honest heart, had evinced such unmistakable symptoms of aversion to sleeping another night in the house, that Charles, unshaken in purpose, judged it best to dismiss her at once to her friends.

So the door closed behind the sobbing Hephzibah, and Charles was alone, absolutely alone.  


 "For hours he sat musing by the melancholy fire, undisturbed by a single sound.

Evening at length approached, and still he sat, as though Memory had chained him hand and foot to the place where he had passed so many happy hours.

Gradually, he got into a train of recollection that conducted him through the entire history of his lost love, from the first chance meeting when he had stopped, a lost, benighted hunter, to inquire the road, and Mary's azure eyes glittered in the starlight, as if they belonged to it, while she stepped forward to his horse's side, and raised them in directing him. He had arrived at the evening when they had come, with their modest baggage and rustic henchwoman, to the magnificent house, had examined its alarming glories, had dined merrily, and were reclining in their deep velvet chairs, their laughing faces reflected grotesquely in the polished stove, up to the moment when old Charlotte, like an evil genius, appeared at the door.  


 "At that moment a sound struck Charles's ear — it was like a distant footstep somewhere within the house.

The door of the room in which he sat was wide open, and presently he was aware of a slow soft step ascending the stair.  


 "To say that Charles's heart did not accelerate its usual pace by a pulse or two, would be to deny a feeling that might have so far assailed the most collected.

An idea that the bold resolution he had formed was about to be met half-way, that the mysterious Horror of the House was actually approaching him in an incarnate shape, struck the listener with an appalling sense of being suddenly called upon to deal with what one cannot comprehend.--Charles involuntarily griped the velvet arms of his chair, and half rising, slowly turned his face to the door, where the step had halted.  


 "There stood old Charlotte!  


 "His fear melted into rage.  


 "'Wretched old hag!--accursed murderess!' he exclaimed, forgetting for the moment his own doubts of her guilt--'dare you'--  


 "'Charles Ainsley,' said the old woman, walking up to him, 'it is you who should not dare. I warned you — I warned your mother — I warned Mrs. Callender--I warned every one of you, young and old, of the danger hidden in this fearful house.

Yet I loved and served them all when they would let me, and to do so ran the same risk with them.

For reward, you have put the murderer's mark on me. I am the devil's mate, Moll Murder, the old poisoning witch.

My life is nothing; they might as well have hanged me. I hoped they would, for the Lord keeps justice for the innocent, and He knows that I never willingly harmed a living creature.

They were all touched and took, poor dears!

but not by me. I know you are come back to find out who killed your darling, and old Charlotte's come to help you.'  


 "'You!'  


 "'Like enough in some things,' said the old woman steadily. 'You've no more pleasure in life — no more have I.

You'have one object — mine's the same, only my reason's the best.--Find out what you may, you can't bring back the dead.

But I wear Cain's black brand, and that's an ugly mask to die in; I won't, If I can help it.?  


 "Charles stood looking at her with an amazement he did not care to hide; something in the woman's altered manner impressed him favorably, despite himself.

His thoughts held a rapid council; If the hag were guilty, and were really a prey to that fearful form of mania which could alone account for such cruel crimes, he had no fear for himself, and might even, by examination and analysis, obtain some clue to her alleged practices.

If she were innocent, she might afford him important aid in his investigations.

Some attendant he absolutely required.

In fine, he acceded to her proposal, and directed her to take up her residence in the house as before.  


 "A feeling he could not well define determined Charles to sleep that night in the Angel-chamber.

It was there that his Mary had experienced the first mysterious visitation — there, on his bosom, breathed her last gentle sigh.  


 "As he lay down, though with little hope of rest, he could not resist uttering a fervent prayer that the terrible influence might reveal itself to him; also — no matter with what peril accompanied — so that he might but analyze its fearful features, and gauge its destroying power.  


 "His desire was fulfilled.

It must have been about two o'clock when Charles woke, with a start, under the impression that a hand had been laid upon his face.

But such a band!

It could have belonged to no living human thing.

Horrible as it seems, it was like that of a putrid corpse.

His mouth, his nose, his eyes, his throat, were choked and smarting with some fearful effluvia, his pulse went irregularly — his very soul sickened within him!  


 "Ainsley was a man of cool, in trepid nature, and the strongest nerves.

Despite his confusion, he rose and wrestled with the Terror, as if it were a living foe that had nearly mastered him — a moment, and the victory was won.--Slowly and reluctantly, as though baffled in its assault, the horrible fear, whose presence be had almost felt,  relaxed its hold, and quitted him. Charles instinctively staggered forward, as in pursuit, reached the window, and throwing it up, gazed forth into the calm, cold night.   


 "'Whence, whence, O Horror!"he gasped.  


 "The next moment, with a countenance deadly white, he reclosed the window, and returned to his bed.  


 "In that instant, the Horror, the Ghost, had revested itself to him, as be had desired.  


 "But Charles would have further proof, and witness too.  


 "The following morning, after pretending to eat some portion of the breakfast he found comfortably prepared for him in the library, Charles summoned old Charlotte to a conference.  


 "She came, so changed, that her master could scarcely recognize, in the hale, respectable-looking matron before him, the wretched old outcast of the previous day. But I have said that Charlotte had, in common with other humble creatures I have met with, a way of brightening and expanding under certain influences, which revealed qualities hitherto wrapped in shade.

The troubles she had undergone, above all, the foul stigma under which she labored, had had a purifying and vivifying effect, so apparent in her manner and language, that Charles secretly congratulated himself on his ally.  


 'He began by tracing as minutely as possible the history of the later illnesses and deaths, beginning with that of his mother, which event occurred during his absence abroad.

In this he received most material assistance from Mr. Mawry, for whom he sent during the morning, and who, after overcoming his astonishment at finding old Charlotte a member of the council, entered with all zeal into the inquiry.  


 "The result proved that the same extraordinary symptoms had been evolved in every case — namely, severe nervous, semi-cataleptic attacks, prostration of strength, mental depression, decay of the vital powers, and death — Mawry declaring himself utterly unable to account either for the origin of the disease, or for the rapidity and certainty with which, once conceived, it hurried the victims to their end.  


 "On receiving the information he had gathered, Ainsley was struck with one singular feature in the case — the predilection evinced by every patient in turn for the Angel-chamber.

It seemed a fatal fancy; for, certainly, whatever soothing influence it might exercise on the minds of the invalids, was not reflected in their bodies.

On the contrary, every one became rapidly worse, and the mysterious Terror — though its recurrence grew more and more frequent — seemed gradually to lose its intensity, in proportion as physical health declined, till it left the last days of the sufferer wholly undisturbed.  


 "'Now,' said Charles, as with a deep sigh he raised his pale face from his hands, after a minute's meditation, 'come with me, and I will show you the Horror in the House.'  


 "He walked, followed by the others, straight to the Angel-room.

There it shone, with its regal couch, its superb mirrors, its glowing cabinets, its purple curtains.

Charles threw up the window, admitting the soft fresh breeze.  


 " 'Does this,' he asked, 'look like a pestilence palace — a house of pain and death?'  


 "He struck upon one of the gilded panels as he spoke; it returned a hollow sound, like an echo of the last word, 'death !'  


 "The next moment, Charles caught up a poker from the fireplace, and dashed in the panel.  


 " 'Stoop down,' he said to Mawry.  


 "The latter did so, but started back in horror, as a sickening, loathsome odor pervaded the apartment, as from a newly-opened grave.  


 "There lay indeed the secret of the Horror.--Out of that panel crept the unseen destroyer that had sucked away the breath, the life of no less than five victims.  


 "From the Angel-chamber, which had been originally intended as a luxurious bath-room, a pipe had been prepared, the other extremity of which had vent in the sloping bank of the adjacent cemetery, long since become one mass of corrupting human clay.

Thus, this fatal conduit, itself decayed, winding among broken vaults and mouldering mausoleums, gathered up the noxious exhalations, and poured them into the golden room.

By what atmospheric changes, or movements in the earth, the amount of miasma thus transmitted was governed and modified, cannot of course be known; but that the poison varied in quantity and strength, was sufficiently proved by the fact, that attention was never attracted to the vitiated atmosphere of the spacious and seemingly well-ventilated room.  


 "The panel which concealed the mouth of the pipe was low down — exactly on a level with the head of one sleeping in the Angel-bed, and probably distant from it but three or four feet. An almost imperceptible crevice in the thin panel must have projected that baneful breath into the sleeper's face as certainly, and, as it proved, as fatally, as the 'juice of cursed Hebron' dropped from the phial of the Danish regicide.

No marvel that the end was rapid ! To turn the face to that wall, was indeed to bid adieu to life, its hopes, its troubles, and its cares.  


 "Those most remarkable symptoms I have had to relate, can only be referrable to nervous temperament, or to the mysterious trouble acting almost in the nature of disease, until disease was positively engendered.  


 "When, on the previous night, Charles threw up the window, some slight odor eliminated from the burial-ground, connecting itself with the loathsome sense from which he had just escaped, at once revealed to him the latter origin.  


 "I gave you to understand, children, that this story was true; I now repeat that it is based on actual and melancholy fact.  


 "Many a child's banquet have I shared in that fatal chamber with my pretty May."       
 
 
 
Professional Cards. 
 
Cropper &amp; Dunbar, Attorneys at Law, 


Office No. 6 Law Building,  
 Corner of 12th and Franklin Sts., Richmond, Va.  


 oc 1--1m*   
 
C. G. Griswold. J. G. Griswold.Griswold &amp; Griswold, Attorneys at Law, Richmond, Va., 


 Will practice in all the Courts of the city of Richmond, and in the counties of Henrico and Hanover, and in the Circuit Courts of Essex and King and Queen counties.  


 Office on Ross street, two doors from Richmond House.

se 5--3m   
 
A. Ascoli, M. D., 


Member of the  


 New York C. Of K.'S HomŒPathic  


 Medical Society.  
 Office and Residence on Franklin st., corner of 4th,  


 Richmond, Va.  
 Office hours till 11 A. M., and from 4 to 8 P.M.,  


 (Sundays excepted.) se 1--3m*   
 
Shockoe Hill General Agency. G. W. H. Tyler, 


Office on Marshall, between Sixth and Seventh  


 Streets,  


 Continues to Rent out Houses, Hire out Negroes, sell Real estate, sell Negroes, and act as a General Agent.

He returns his thanks for the liberal patronage bestowed upon him for three years past.

se 3--6m   
 
Cupping and Leeching. 


 --Mrs. Woolhouse, over Samuel Sutherland's Gun Store, 132 Main street, Richmond, will wait on all those requiring her services.  


 Constantly receiving, per steamers, fresh Leeches.  


 All orders for Leeches carefully packed and sent by Express to all parts of the State.  


 N. B.--A new style of Ladies' Bandages.

that are much liked, made to order.  


 au 20--3m   
 
Lawrence S. Marye, Attorney at Law, 


Practices in the Courts of the City of Richmond and the Counties of Henrico, Hanover and Caroline.  


 He is also Notary Public and Commissioner of the United States Court of Claims.  


 The partnership between Mr. Chastain White and himself being dissolved, his office is now on 11th street, just below Goddin's Hall.

fe 13--1y   
 
Samuel T. Bayly.

Chastain White. Bayly &amp; White, Attorneys at Law, 


 Practice in all the Courts held in the city of Richmond, the counties of Hanover, Henrico, Caroline, Goochland and Chesterfield.  


Samuel T. Bayly, Commissioner of Deeds for all the States and Territories.

Office corner of 12th and Franklin streets, near the State Court-House.

jy 6--ts   
 
 


Dr. Z. S. McGRUDER, of Henrico, having taken an office on Franklin street, first house above Metropolitan Hall, tenders his professional services to the public.  


 jy 30--6m   
 
John W. Green, Attorney at Law, 


 Will practice in the Courts of the city of Richmond and county of Henrico.

Strict attention will be given to all business entrusted to him.  


 Office, for the present, with his father, William Green, southwest corner Main and 7th streets.  


 je 27--6m   
 
Henry Hudnall, Attorney at Law and Notary public. 


 Practices in all the Courts held in the city of Richmond.  


 Also, practices regularly in the County and Circuit Courts of Chesterfield.  


 As Notary, will take Depositions and Acknowledgments, Administer and Certify Oaths, and perform whatever other duties pertain to the office of Notary.  


 Office at the corner of Bank and 11th streets, just below the Custom-House.

ja 31--ly    
 
Business notices. 
 
To Merchants. 


 --The advertiser is in want of permanent employment as Book-Keeper in some good house.

In the mean while, would like to accept an engagement to write up and adjust the books of any gentlemen who may need such service.  


 Refers to Messrs. Massie &amp; Pleasants, the Messrs.

Walker, tobacco merchants, and Messrs. Quarles &amp; Sons, Broad street.  


 oc 16--1m W. H. Mitchell.   
 
 


The Annual meeting of Stockholders of the White Sulphur Springs Company will take place at the Exchange Hotel, Richmond, Wednesday, 7th November, 1860.  


 oc 15--td E. Warren, Sec'y.   
 
 


for the purpose of Facilitating the Trade of this city from and after this date, we, the undersigned, will require paper payable to the order of purchasers for all goods sold at auction on credit.  
 
 
Edmond, Davenport &amp; Co.,  
Crenshaw &amp; Co,  
Dunlop, Moncure &amp; Co.,  
Chas. T. Wortham &amp; Co.  
Richmond, Va., October 11, 1860, oc 12--ts      
 
Business notices. 
 
Bowers' ArchitecturalFoundry 


 Manufactures  


 Iron Fronts, House Castings, Railings, &amp;c.,  


 Corner of Cary and 9th streets, Richmond, Va.  


 ie 2--6m A. J. Bowers, Proprietor.   
 
Davis, Deupree &amp; Co., 


 will give their entire attention to the  


 sale of Negroes,  


 Publicly and privately.  


 Odd Fellows' Hall,  
 Corner Mayo and Franklin streets,  


 Richmond, Va.  
 Ro. H. Davis.  
 Wm. S. Deupree,  
 S. R. Fondren.  
 Rufus G. Maddux. Clerk. je 1--1y   
 
Wood, Eddy &amp; Co'sLotteries! 


Authorized by the States of  


 Delaware, Missouri and Kentucky,  


 Draw daily, in public, under the superintendence of Sworn Commissioners.  


 The Managers' Offices are located at Wilmington, Delaware, and St. Louis, Missouri.  


 Prizes Vary from  


 $2.50 to $100,000!  


 Tickets from  


 $2.50 to $20!  


 Circulars, giving full explanation and the schemes to be drawn, will be sent, free of expense, by addressing Wood, Eddy &amp; Co.,  


 Wilmington, Del.,  
Wood, Eddy &amp; Co.,  


 jy 10--1y St. Louis, Mo.   
 
Potts, Farley &amp; Co., 


Grocers, Commission and Forwarding Merchants,  


 Nearly opposite the Columbian Hotel, Cary st.,  


 Richmond, Va.  
 Special attention given to the sale of Tobacco, Wheat, and all kinds of Produce, and liberal advances made on consignments.  


 Frank Potts, Late of Petersburg.  


 Richard D. Farley, Late of Petersburg.  


 Jas. B. Marshall, Late of Petersburg.   
 
Edwin Wortham &amp; Co., 


Grocers, Commission Merchants,  


 and  


 Dealers in Iron and Steel,  


 Solicit consignments of Tobacco, Wheat, Corn, Flour, &amp;c., to the sale of which Edwin Wortham will give his personal attention.  


 Advances made on consignments.  


 Bags furnished when required.   
 
Alfred S. Lee,for Warding andCommission Merchant,and Dealer inPlaster, Salt, Lumber, Coal, &amp;c. 


In addition to my Forwarding Business, I would inform my friends and the public that I have a Lumber Yard opposite my warehouse, and directly on the line of the York River Railroad, where may be found a general assortment of Virginia Lumber, Shingles, &amp;c.  


 Mr. T. W. Peers will attend to sales of Lumber on my account.  


 Consignments of Lumber solicited, on which liberal advances will be made.

A. S. Lee.   
 
Marble Works. 
John W. Davies,  
 Marble Mason,  
 Mechanics' Institute, 9TH street,  


 Richmond Va.,  


 Monuments, Tombs, Head Pieces,  


 Mantles, Fonts, &amp;c.  


 First Premiums awarded by the Virginia Agricultural Society and Mechanics' Institute.   
 
Hector Davis, 


Auctioneer,  


 for sale of Slaves, Richmond, Va.,  


 gives particular attention to selling Slaves, both publicly and privately.  


 R. D. James has an interest in the business from this day. e28 — 6m   
 
Marble Works.-- 


Jacob Vincent,  


 Manufacturer of  


 Italian and American Marble Monuments, Tombs, Head-Pieces, &amp;c., of every style and design.  


 The public are respectfully invited to call at my Yard, between 5th and 6th sts., on Main, (adjoining Rogers &amp; Miller's Marble Yard,) and examine my work, which cannot be excelled by any other establishment, North or South; which I will sell as low as any establishment in this city or else where.

au 9--3m   
 
1860.

Stoves — Stoves.

1860. 
Wm. Sears Wood,  
 No. 6 Main street, near the Old Market.  


 Manufacturer. Wholesale and Retail Dealer in  


 Stoves. Ranges and Furnaces,  


 Mott's Agricultural Boilers,  


 Tin and Sheet Iron Ware,  


 Copper Lightning Rods, &amp;c., &amp;c.,  


 Plumbing and Gas-fitting, in all its branches  


 Jobbing promptly attended to,  


 Repairs for all kinds of Stoves, always on hand.  


 Roofing and Guttering  


 done in the city and country, in the best manner and at shortest notice.

se 26--ts   
 
Geo. S. Lownes. Wm. B. Cook.Lownes &amp; Cook--PhŒNix Foundry andIron Railing Manufactory. 


8th st., 3d door east of Main, Richmond, Va.  


We have recently rebuilt and made large addition to our Works, with the modern improvement in tools.

We flatter ourselves that we can supply Castings, Plain and Ornamental Railing, Verandahs, Window Caps and Sills, Columns, Iron Fronts, and general Iron Work, at prices to suit the times.

Give us a call, and examine designs, &amp;c. se 26--3m   
 
Bridgford &amp; Co., 


General Commission and  


 Forwarding Merchants,  


 On the Dock, Richmond, Va.  


 D. B. Bridgford.  
 N. Tinsley Pate.   
 
Green &amp; Davis.practicalGranite Cutters, 


Sixth Street, near the Armory, Richmond, Va.  


 every description of  


 Granite Work  


 Executed at short notice and in the best manner.  


 mh 12--12m   
 
Jas. B. MacMURDOurdo, 


Agent Manhattan life Insurance Company, of New York.

Office at the Insurance Agency of Thos. M. Alfriend, on 11th street, nearly opposite Goddin's Hall, where applications will be received.  


 au 13--1y   
 
 


 P. Weilbacher, of Richmond, Va.  


Wm. Paul, of Baltimore, Md.  


 Weilbacher &amp; Paul,  


 manufacturers and Importers of  


 Havana and Domestic Cigars, and dealers in  


 Leaf Tobacco.  
 je 13--1y No. 21 German st., Baltimore Md.   
 
Robert Wendenburg, 


ship Broker, Commission and  


 Forwarding Merchant,  


 Rocer and ship Chandler,  


 Richmond and City Point, Va.,  


 is prepared to take Goods on Storage at City Point on the most reasonable terms, without charge of drayage either to or from store.  


 ap 27--1y   
 
 


C. M. Bosher, Successor to Wilson &amp; Bosher, Wholesale and Retail Grocer, has for sale the following articles, to which he asks the attention of his friends and the public: Rio, Laguayra, Java and Mocha Coffees; Brown and Refined Sugars, of different grades; Loaf, Pulverized and Crushed Sugars; Smoking and Chewing Tobacco, of different brands; Old Dominion Nails, of all sizes; country cured Bacon Hams; Western Sides and Shoulders; Cotton Yarns, a good assortment; H. Ott's Old Rye Whiskey, old and good; D. T. Clenner's Rye Whiskey; old and good; A. W. Sherman's Rye Whiskey; A. N. Wood's Rye Whiskey, old and good; F. Stearns &amp; Co.'s Old Rye Whiskey, two years old; Common Whiskeys, in variety; French Brandy, Madeira Wines, and other articles, too numerous to mention.

Call and examine, at No. 1, cor. 17th and Main sts., opposite Old Market.   
 
John N. Gordon &amp; Son, 


14th Street, Near The Exchange Hotel, Offer for sale a large and full assortment of Iron, comprising Swede's, American Hammered, Peru Hammered, English and English Refined, English, American, Russia and Imitation Russia Sheet Iron, Hoops, Band and Scroll Iron, Refined Plow Iron and Plow Plates.

Also, Tin-plate of various sizes, for tinners and manufacturers; Sheet and Bolt Copper, Sheet Zinc, Spelter, and the Metals usually sold in this market.

ap 1--ts   
 
Wm. S. Royster,Merchandize BrokerandGeneral Commission Merchant,Corner Cary and Virginia streets, Richmond, Va., 


 Offers his services for the sale and purchase of Merchandize generally; also, Flour, Wheat, Corn, Tobacco, and all descriptions of Country Produce.  


 Refers, by permission, to Lewis Webb, Esq., Messrs. Dunlop, Moncure &amp; Co., Messrs. Edmond, Davenport &amp; Co., Messrs. Bacon &amp; Baskervill, Richmond; Messrs, Bryant, Tinsley &amp; Holmes, Messrs. Spence &amp; Reid, Baltimore; Messrs. Twells &amp; Co., Philadelphia; Thos. Monahan, Esq., New York.

au 9--ts   
 
 


The undersigned have formed a copartnership for the transaction of a Commission business, under the firm of Lewis Webb &amp; John G. Wade.

They will give particular attention to the sale of Flour, Wheat, Corn and Tobacco.

They occupy the store and lumber-house No. 58 Main street, long occupied by Lewis Webb.

Lewis Webb,  


John G. Wade.  
 Richmond, Va.,, Nov. 1, 1859. ne 7--dcw&amp;swts   
 
James D. Browne'sOrnamental Iron Works, 


 9th street, next to the Mechanics' Institute,  


 Iron Railings, Verandahs, Balconies, Chairs, Settees, &amp;c.; also, Grating, Vault and Cellar Doors, and every other kind of Iron Work for ornamental and building purposes, manufactured at short notice.  


 Particular attention given to enclosing Burial Lots in the city and country.

ja 24--12m   
 
Maddux &amp; Co., 


 (Successors to Smith &amp; Maddux,)  


 Produce Commission Merchants,  


 Cary street, opposite Columbian Hotel,  


 Richmond, Va.,  
 Jas. F Edwards, of King William, Assistants,  


 W. H. Howard, of York, Assistants,  


 W. M. Marshall, of Lunenburg, Assistants,  


 Guarantee to their friends faithful attention to all consignments, and orders for goods from produce customers.  


 Mr. F. V. Sutton, Jr., is admitted to a interest in our business.  


 fe 1--dt#&amp;cw4t Maddux Co.   
 
Alexander Nott,Auctioneer and CommissionMerchant, 


 Will attend regularly to the sales of Horses, Mules, wagons, &amp;c., at the Horse Lot, every Saturday Morning, at 10 o'clock.  


 Stock intended for sale will please be entered before the mornings of the sale.   
 
Andrew Antoni 


--Wholesale and Retail Dealer in Foreign and Domestic Confectionery, Fruits, &amp;c., Importer of French Candies, Cordials, &amp;c., and Manufacturer of Double Refined Candies; also, parties and weddings, in town or country, supplied with Ornamental Confectionary, Ice Cream, Cakes, &amp;c., No. 156 Main street, next door Exchange Bank, Richmond, Va.,     
 
Medical Hospitals. 
 
 


Infirmary of St. Francis De Sales, Brooke Avenue, Richmond Va.--Conducted by the Sisters of Charity.

Patients of all denominations, not having small pox or any other contagious disease, are received.

White persons, in private rooms, pay from $7 to $13 per week, and in wards $6. Colored persons $5 per week.  


 Physicians And Surgeons.--Doctors St. G. Peachy. D. Thomas, J. S. Dorsey Cullen.

se 5--ts   
 
Infirmary of the Medical College. 


 --This Institution, situated at the corner of Marshall and College streets, in fully provided for the accommodation of both White Persons and Negroes, requiring medical treatments.  


 White Persons who desire it, can be furnished with private Rooms, where they will enjoy every comfort and convenience.  


 The accommodations for Slaves, as heretofore, are ample, and the attention of owners of negroes, both in the city and country, is again invited to the great advantages afforded by the Infirmary for the Medical and Surgical treatment of this class of patients.  


 Lying-in women are also received and carefully attended to.  


 All patients are under the care of the Professors of the College, who visit the wards daily, aided by an efficient corps of assistants.

In cases of difficulty, a consultation of the Professors is held, without extra charge to the patient.  


 The charges for Medical Attendance, Board, Nursing and Medicine are as follows:  


 White Persons...$6 per week.  


 White Persons in private rooms...$7 to $15 per week.  


 Slave and other colored patients...$5 per week.  


 For less than a week, (except in private rooms.) $1 per day — provided that the aggregate shall not exceed the charge for a full week.  


 For Surgical Operations, by agreement with the proprietors of the Bellevue Hospital, a small extra charge will be made, varying from $2 to $30, according to the difficulty and importance of the operation.  


 All charges payable on the removal of the patient.  


 no case of small Pox, or any other infections disease, nor any case of Insanity, will be admitted.  


 Attending Physicians--Profs. Tucker Conway and McCAW.  


 Attending Surgeons--Profs. Gibson, Peticolas and Wellford.  


 Resident Physician--Dr. Thos. L. Hunter.  


 Steward — F. M. Parrish.  


 President--Dr. L. S. Joynes.  


 Persons in the country, desirous of sending patients to the Infirmary, may address the President, Steward, or any of the Professors of the College.  


 ja 12--1y   
 
Main street Hospital for Slaves. 


 --This Hospital is situated near the corner of Main and 26th streets, and is admirably adapted in airiness, privacy and healthfulness of position, to the purposes for which it has been instituted, namely: For Medical, Surgical and Obstetrical treatment of Slaves.--The rules and regulations governing this institution have already been published.

A circular containing full particulars will be furnished those who may desire further information.  


 Terms.--Patients per week, $5 less than a week, $1 per diem; but the aggregate shall not exceed the charge for a full week. Patients attending the daily examinations (not fit subjects for Hospital Confinement,) charged the regular fee adopted by the profession at large.--The above charges include board, medicine, medical attendance and nursing.

Surgical operations charged according to rules of other Hospitals of the city.

For further information apply to the Physician resident at the Hospital, or to either of the undersigned Physicians and Proprietors.  


 Frs. W. Hancock. M. D.,  


Main st., bet. 3d and 4th.

or No. 130 Main st.  


 St. Geo. Peachy. M. D.,  


 Exchange Hotel, or Grace st., bet. 5th and 6th.  


 R. S. Vest, M. D., Franklin st.,  


 Near Ballard House, or cor. Main and 7th sts.  


 Philip S. Hancock. M. D.,  


 Resident Physician,  


 Cyrus Brooks,  


 ap19 — 1y Resident Assistant.   
 
Bellevue Hospital. 


 --This Institution, which has been in successful operation seven years, is situated on Church Hill, Richmond, Virginia, in a delightful, airy position, and is furnished with every convenience conducive to the comfort of patients and the successful treatment of medical and surgical diseases.  


 Rooms have been nicely furnished, suitable to the accommodation of gentlemen who may find it inconvenient to be treated at their private lodgings.  


 Particular attention will be paid to the lying-in wards, which are very commodious.  


 Having been heretofore liberally patronized by owners of slaves, both in the city and country, we can, with increased confidence, call their attentention to the great advantages afforded by our "Hospital," for the medical and surgical treatment of Slaves, and promise to spare no pains to furnish them proper accommodations and every necessary attention.  


 terms:  


 (Payable on the removal of the Patient.)  


 White Patients, per week...$6  


 White Patients, in Private Rooms, per week...$7 to $15  


 Slaves per week...$5  


 (For fractions of a week, after the first week, at  


 the same rates, i. e. 71 cents per day.)  


 For less than a week, (except in private rooms,) $1 per day, provided that the aggregate shall not exceed the charge for a full week.  


 This includes all charges for Board, Medical Attendance, Nursing and Medicine.

By an arrangement with the Infirmary of the Medical College, a small additional fee, ranging from $2 to $30, will be charged for Surgical cases.

The particular sum may be ascertained before-hand by application to one of the attending Physicians.  


 No Small-Pox admitted.  


 All patients are under our immediate care, one of us visiting the wards once a day, and oftener when necessary; and in cases of difficulty, a consultation of all the physicians is held, without extra charge to the patient.

A resident Physician, two Students and a Matron, have the patients under their immediate supervision, and personally administer all medicines ordered.  


 When requested, weekly reports will be given of the condition of patients.  


 Persons in the country, wishing to send patients to our Hospital, may address either of the Physicians, or the Resident Physician.  


 When desired, we will send a comfortable covered vehicle to any part of the city for patients.--For this purpose, a message left at the Hospital, or a Mr. Thos. Pemberton's, on Main, between 17th and 18th streets, will be attended to.  


 Attending Physicians and Surgeons:  


 James Bolton, M. D., Grace st., between 4th and 5th.  


 Thomas Pollard, M. D., Governor st., 1st door above Richmond House.  


 O. A. Crenshaw, M. D., opposite American Hotel.  


 Wm. W. Parker, M. D., Law Building, corner of 12th and Franklin sts.  


 C. M. Hunter, M. D., Resident Physician  


 Mrs. W. E. Perkins. Matron. ja 2--1y    
 
Medicines. 
 
The Great Virginia Remedy, and no Humbug.--Peters' Infallible Remedy for GonorrhŒa and all secret diseases. 


 --This great American remedy, containing no Mercurial or Balsamic properties, excels everything, heretofore offered the public, in its curative, restorative and renovating powers; and the medical world are astonished when told that the above remedy will cure the above diseases, and confounded when they have ocular demonstrations of the facts.--But the proprietor, who has known of the remedy for twenty-odd years, has known of a case of twenty years standing to be restored to perfect health, and all other cases of shorter duration to be restored, without a single exception, and therefore challenges any case of Gonorrhæa which the remedy will not cure, provided the directions are carried out with prudence on the part of the patient; and any one purchasing half a dozen bottles, and using accordingly, in his or her case, he guarantees a perfect cure; and in case of failure, will furnish additional medicine, free of charge, to complete the cure, through his agents; and a cure will be effected without inconvenience to the patient.  


 Sold by Apperson &amp; Dupuy, No. 201 Broad street, and O. A. Strecker, Main street, Druggists, agents for the city of Richmond.  


 oc 1--6m*   
 
Helmbold's Extract Buchu, 


Helmbold's Extract Buchu,  


Helmbold's Extract Buchu,  


Helmbold's Extract Buchu,  


Helmbold's Extract Buchu,  


 The Great Diuretic, The Great Diuretic,  


 The Great Diuretic, The Great Diuretic,  


 The Great Diuretic, The Great Diuretic,  


 The Great Diuretic, The Great Diuretic,  


 A positive and specific remedy for diseases of the  


 Bladder, Kidneys, Gravel, Dropsy,  


 Bladder, Kidneys, Gravel, Dropsy,  


 Bladder, Kidneys, Gravel, Dropsy,  


 Bladder, Kidneys, Gravel, Dropsy,  


 and all diseases of the  


 Sexual Organs, Sexual Organs, Sexual Organs,  


Helmbold's Extract of Buchu  


 Is a certain, safe and speedy cure, from whatever cause they may have originated, and no matter of  


 How Long Standing, How Long Standing,  


 How Long Standing, How Long Standing,  


 How Long Standing, How Long Standing,  


 It is taken without Hindrance from Business, and little if any change of diet,  


 Is pleasant in its taste and odor,  


 And immediate in its action.  


 If you are suffering with any of the above distressing aliments,  


 Procure the Remedy at Once,  


 Procure the Remedy at Once,  


 Procure the Remedy at Once,  


Helmbold's Extract Buchu,  


 As a medicine which must benefit every body, from the simply delicate to the confined and despairing invalid.  


 no Equal is to be found.  


 no Equal is to be found.  


 no Equal is to be found.  


 Price $1 per bottle, or six for $5; delivered to any address.

Prepared by H. T. Helmbold,  


 Depot, 104 South Tenth st., below Chesnut,  


 For sale wholesale and retail by  


 Fisher &amp; Shepherd,  


 Druggists and Apothecaries,  


 ja 17--1y 125 Main street.   
 
Medical Card 


 --Dr. Plume offers his services to the public in the treatment of all secret diseases.

Twenty years practice in the above branch gives Dr. P. a claim to public favor.--Office on Franklin street, near the Exchange Hotel, and third house below Trinity Church, same side.

A ways on hand, a supply of the "chemical Extract of Flowers;" one of the very best renovators for weakened parts now known.

Medicines sent to order.

All communications by letter or otherwise promptly attended to. Richmond, Va.    
 
 
 
Double Refined Steam Candies: 


My factory is now complete, and by far the largest establishment of the kind south of Philadelphia.

An experience of twenty years, aided with competent workmen, enables me to offer to the trade of  


 Virginia,  


 North Carolina,  
 and Tennessee,  


 As also the city Grocers, an article of city-made, Steam-Refined Crushed Sugar Candy, warranted to stand in any climate, much below the Northern price for an article of like standard.  


 Call and examine it at my Factory, No. 80 Main street. Louis J. Bossieux.   
 
New Clothing for Fall and Winter of 1860 


 --Darracott, Harris &amp; Co., 112 Main street.--Persons visiting the Fairs are requested to call and examine our stock of Clothing, consisting of Fine Black Dress Suits; Fancy Cassimere Suits; Fancy Nobby Suits; Velveteen Hunting Suits; Black and Brown T cot Suits; Beaver Paletoe Overcoats; Fine Cloth Overcoats; Whitney Paletoes and Sacks; Black and Fancy Velvet Vests; Fancy and Black Silk Vests; Golden Hill Shirts; Collars; Socks; Cravats; Suspenders; Handkerchiefs and Gloves; Boys' Clothing; which we are selling very low. For bargains, call on  


 Darracott, Harris &amp; Co., 112 Main st.     
 
Hats, &amp;c. 
 
Hamilton &amp; Seagers,manufacturers and Dealers.Hats and Caps. 


No. 45 Main street, opposite the St. Charles Hotel, have now in store a large and select stock of Hats, Caps, &amp;c., for the Fall and Winter trade, embracing every article in their line.  


 They would be pleased to have a call from those in want, believing they can give satisfaction in styles, quality and price.

oc 20--2w   
 
John Thompson,no 1, Ballard House, 


 Has on hand a select and fashionable assortment of Hats, Caps, Ladies' Furs and Gentlemen's Furnishing Goods, which he is disposed to sell at low prices.

I most respectfully solicit a call from purchasers.

oc 20--dtJ1   
 
National Guard Hat.National Guard Hat.National Guard Hat. 


 Something entirely new for young men, at  


 Ellett &amp; Weisiger's,  


 oc 8--ts No. 167 Main street.   
 
Hats, Caps and Furs.William T. Moore &amp; Co.,207 Broad street. 


 The subscribers respectfulty announce that they are now in receipt of a large and fine assortment of Hats and Caps, to which they call attention.

Visitors to the Fair would find a rare selection if they examine our stock before purchasing, as we will offer inducements that cannot fall to please; We have now received a full supply of Ladies' Furs, embracing all the latest styles, which we are selling at the lowest possible price.

Our stock of Servants' Hats and Caps cannot be beat, either in quality or price.  


 Dress Hats made to order.  


 Thankful for past favors, they hope for a continuance of the same.

Wm. T. Moore,  
 M. J. Leonard,  
 207 Broad street   
 
Fall Trade.

1860. 
Robert L. Dickinson, (successor to Binford, Dickinson &amp; Weisiger.) No. 78 Main street, Richmond, Va., thankful for the liberal patronage bestowed on him by his friends and the public generally, invites their attention to his large and extensive stock of Hats, Caps, Furs, &amp;c., comprising every style manufactured for the season, which will be sold at wholesale and retail to punctual customers on the most favorable terms.

Merchants of Virginia, North Carolina, and Tennessee, visiting the city, are respectfully solicited to call and examine for themselves before purchasing.

A liberal discount made to those who purchase for cash.    
 
Restaurants. 
 
Frank'sLager Beer Saloon andRestaurant,no. 76 Main street. Richmond, Va. 


At this first class Restaurant are at all hours served the best York River Oysters, in every style desired.  


 The Bar is always supplied with the choicest of Liquors, Wines, Cigars and Tobacco.  


 From to-day will be served a free Lunch to all customers at 11 o'clock  


 oc 11--1m* Frank Winge, Proprietor.   
 
Dime Hotel,on the European planno. 84 Main street,Richmond, Va. 


 The Dime Restaurant, on Main street, near Fourteenth or Pearl, continues to be famous as the very best Restaurant in Richmond.  


 Gentlemen visiting the city on business will find this house very conveniently located and comfortably arranged with lodging-rooms, by the day, week or month.  


 single Rooms, 50 cents per day.  


 Meals, as they may be ordered, in the spacious and convenient refectory, at all hours.

Private Rooms for dinner or supper parties.  


 Gentlemen visiting this convenient establishment will only be charged for what they may order.

[se 24--3m]W. H. Hayward.    
 
Watches, Jewelry, &amp;c. 
 
 


An Elegant and the largest assortment of Gold and Silver Watches and Jewelry ever offered in this city, wholesale and retail, at Lewis Hyman's, 98 Main street.  


 Gold, Silver and Steel Spectacles, Brazilian Pebble Glasses, to suit any sight, to be had at a reduced price from Lewis Hyman, 98 Main street.  


 Watches and Jewelry Repaired by skillful workmen at a low price by Lewis Hyman, 98 Main street. And the cheapest Watches and Jewelry in the State to be purchased at  


 se 4--3m Lewis Hyman's   
 
 


Charles Lumsden is the man who repairs Watches, Jewelry, Clocks, Spectacles, &amp;c., in the best manner and at reasonable prices.  


 Watches and Clocks repaired and warranted.  


 Jewelry repaired in the best manner.  


 Spectacles fitted with new glasses and warranted to suit, at 96 Main street, Richmond.    
 
Music Teaching. 
 
Musical Accomplishments. 


 -- Prof. C. T. DeCŒNiel is now ready, and offers his professional services to such as may be anxious to obtain a complete and thorough course of Musical Instruction, as pursued by all Collegiate Professors in Europe, on the Harp, Piano, Guitar, Organ, Singing, and in the Science and Art of Teaching Music.  


 For Card of Terms, Testimonials, &amp;c., apply to  


 Prof. DeŒNiel, at Mrs. P. Mayo's,  


 oc 26--2w* 5th st., bet. Clay and Leigh.   
 
Mr. F. Nicholls Crouch 


 --the Composer, Lecturer and Singing Master, from England, Author of "Kathleen Mavourneen"  and 2,000 Songs — late Musical Editor of Godey's Lady's  


 Book--  


 Respectfully announces to the musical community of Richmond that he will devote a few hours daily to pupils, intending to form their voices on the European schools.  


 Terms and Circulars to be had at the Music Stores.

oc 9--1m*    
 
Carriages, &amp;c.; for sale. 
 
Carriages, Buggies, &amp;c. 


 --The subscriber, intending to enlarge his present business, and requiring all the store room he can get to enable him to do so, offers his present stock of light Carriages, Buggies, (with and without tops,) Rockaways, &amp;c., at Greatly reduced prices.

All in want are invited to give him a call before purchasing.

John Does,  


 oc 17--1m* Next door cor. 9th and Broad sts.   
 
Carriages, Carriages. 


 --The subscriber has on hand, at his Coach Making Establishment, on Lombard Alley, between Main and Cary, (13th and 14th sts.,) near the Columbian Hotel, Coaches, Charioteers, Barouches, Buggies, with and without tops, and Sulkies — all of his own make, of the best material and workmanship — all of which will be sold as low as good work of the kind can be in the city of Richmond, and I respectfully ask a call from those in want of any article in the Carriage line, as I am determined to make to order and to sell at the lowest prices possible; and all work sold that is new, warranted.  


 fe 24--d9m Micajah Mangum.    
 
Tailoring, &amp;c. 
 
Read this! 


We have on hand an elegant and large assortment of  


 Gents' Furnishing Goods  
 and Ready-made Clothing; a fine stock of Merino Under Clothes; Pants of every size and quality, and Vests and Coats to correspond.-- We have as large and varied an assortment of fine over Coats as can be found in this market.-- All the Clothing that we sell is manufactured by Ourselves.

As our terms are cash, we are satisfied with small profits.  


 business and Dress Suits made to order in the shortest notice, and a neat fit guaranteed.

Come see for yourselves.  


 N. Stocksdale &amp; Son,  


 No. 144 Main street, 5 doors below Exchange  


 oc 10--1m Bank, Richmond, Va.   
 
Fall and Winter Clothing. 


 --The attention of the citizens of Richmond and the public generally is respectfully called to our large, varied, and complete assortment of Gent's and Youths' Clothing and Furnishing Goods, all of which were manufactured by us, with a view of pleasing the great diversities of taste in regard to dress.

We flatter ourselves that the style, fit, and durability of our garments are unsurpassed by any house in the city, and that our advantages in manufacturing clothing are such as to enable us to sell at such reduced prices as cannot be equalled.

Having made more extensive arrangements this season for the supply of the great demands for Clothing than ever before, we hope to receive a large support from all in want of articles in our branch of business, assuring them all that we will do them justice.  


 We are also prepared to make to order any article of Gent's Wearing Apparel, at short notice.  


 Noah Walker &amp; Co.,  


 (Branch of Baltimore House,)  


 103. corner Main and 14th or Pearl sts.   
 
Clothing, Clothing. 


 --Hull has gotten in and is constantly receiving (three shipments per week) his Fall and Winter stock of Clothing.

He has selected his whole stock and had it made up after the latest reported styles.--He makes it a point to have an odd, fine, stylish, durable, and good-fitting stock.

Mr. Groshong, his former partner, superintends the getting up of his stock, whose name is a sufficient guarantee of something pretty as well as good.  


Clothing made to order, in good style and at short notice.  


 The largest and best selected stock of Shirts, Drawers, Ties, Collars, Socks, &amp;c., kept in the city.

Shirts made to order.  


 Irving Hull, Agent,  


 (Late of Tupman &amp; Hull,)  


 94 Main, corner 14th street.    
 
Dentistry. 
 
Artificial Teeth. 


 --the Cheoplastic and Vulcanite Process.--G. W. Jones, Dentist, having the right for the above mode of making Teeth, and being satisfied of its absolute superiority over all other methods can with confidence commend it to those desiring full or partial sets of teeth, and especially such as may be dissatisfied with those they are now using.

The perfect adaptation of the plate to the mouth, and the suction thereby secured, enables him to insert one or more teeth without clasps.--This method having been adopted by those standing highest in the profession, North and South, testimonials will be given and specimens exhibited to those wishing to see them.

Sets of Teeth, on gold or any other plate will of course be made for those preferring them.

Filling, Cleansing, Extracting, and all other operations gently and thoroughly performed.

Teeth extracted by Electricity with out pain  


 Office on Main street, opposite Corinthian Hall no 21--1y   
 
F. A. Jeter,Surgeon Dentist, 


 Office on Main, below Pearl street, next door to P. Horton Keach's trimming store, and two door, above Messrs. Thos. M. Price &amp; Co.'s Dry Goods store.  


 Having returned to the city would be pleased to see these that I have engagements with.

All operations performed in the most approved and scientific style known to the Profession, and all work done by him warranted to give satisfaction.

[oc 1#--1y   
 
Rockbridge Rye Whiskey, 


 in store, for sale by Potts, Farley &amp; Co.     
 
Drugs Medicines, &amp;c. 
 
Fall Trade.

1860 
 W. Peterson &amp; Co., Wholesale Druggists and Dealers in Indigo, Spices, Madder, Logwood, Bicarb, Soda, Starch, Sal Soda, Tobacco, Snuff, Cigars, Nutmegs, Salad Oil, Sponges, Salt Petre, Saleratus, Flor, Sulphum, Copperas, Brimstone, Alum, Cochineal, White Lead, Zinc Paint, Linseed Oil, Colors, Paraffine Oil, Solar Oil, Lard Oil, Castor Oil, Tonqua Beans.  


 Invite the attention of merchants visiting Richmond, to an examination of their stock, which, in variety and price, is not surpassed in this or any Northern city.  


 Orders promptly attended to  


 W. Peterson &amp; Co.,  


 Druggists, 155 Main street, corner 12th.   
 
A. Bodeker &amp; Co., 


 Apothecaries and Druggists, No. 10 Main street, near Old Market, Richmond, Va., will keep on hand a general assortment of pure Drugs, Medicines, Chemicals, Oils, Paints, Window Glass, Putty, Dye Stuffs, Patent Medicines, Brushes of all kinds, Surgical Appliances, Burning Fluid, Alcohol, Soaps, Perfumery, Fancy Articles, Garden Seeds, Glue, Sand Paper, Tobacco, Cigars, Snuff, Medicinal Liquors, &amp;c.  


 Prescriptions prepared at all hours, with special care, by members of the firm alone.  


 Physicians' orders from the country executed promptly, and the most reliable medicines furnished.   
 
Fisher &amp; Shepherd,Wholesale and RetailDruggists, 


 Have on hand, and are continually receiving, supplies of fresh and Reliable Medicines, Drugs, Chemicals, Paints, Oils, low which they offer to cash customers at very and rates.   
 
&gt;New Drug Store.Robert W. Powers, 


Apothecary And Druggist,  


 Begs leave to inform his friends and the public that he has taken and re fitted in a new and handsome style, the store formerly occupied by J. B. Wood, and more recently by C. S. Dawson, No. 48, corner Main and Wall streets, one door above the St. Charles Hotel, Richmond, Va., and has just opened with an entirely new stock of Drugs, Medicines, Chemicals, Fancy, and Toilet Articles, Perfumery, &amp;c., Comprising every article usually kept in his line, selected in person by himself with especial reference to their freshness, purity and entire reliability.  


 Physicians will find his stock of Drugs, Chemicals, Standard Pharmaceutical Preparations, Surgical Instruments, &amp;c., very complete, embracing many new and desirable articles.  


 Prescriptions carefully compounded at any hour of day or night.  


 Orders promptly attended to.  


 oc 5--ts Robert W. Powers.   
 
E. T. Robinson, 


Graduate of the Philadelphia  


 College of Pharmacy,  
 (Successor to Laidley &amp; Robinson,)  


 Fourth and Franklin Streets, Richmond,  


 Has in store a large, resh, and well selected stock of Medicines, Chemicals, Perfumery, Fancy Articles, &amp;c., which he offers at low prices.

Strict personal attention will be given to all the departments of the business.  


 Orders for shipment will be promptly attended to and most carefully packed.   
 
Lead, Lead and Oil, at cost. 


 Pure White Lead ground in Oil, at only six cents per pound, warranted to be the cheapest in the world.

Also, Engine Machinery and Linseed Oils at cost.

Merchants, Painters and others that want to make money, are invited to call, under the Columbian Hotel, on Cary st.  


 oc 4--1m* Patrick Commins, Sole Ag't.   
 
Dove &amp; Co., 


 Wholesale Druggists,  
 No. 83 Main Street,  


 Having in store their Fall stock of Drugs, Medicines, Paints, Oils, &amp;c., offer them to the trade on the most accommodating terms.  
 
 
Indigo, (Spanish Float.)  
Sup.

Carb. Soda, (English.)  
Cream Tartar.  
Saltpetre.

 
Eps. Salts.  
Borax.  
Pepper.  
Ginger.  
Starch  
Window Glass, all sizes.

 
Spts. Turpentine,  
Coal Oil.  
Burning Fluid.  
Machine Oil.  
Tanners' Oil.  
Linseed Oil.  
Lamp Oil.  
Sweet Oil.  
Camphor.

 
Ext. Logwood.  
Soap, all kinds.

 
Cigars all grades.

 
Chewing Tobacco.  
Smoking Tobacco.  
Liquid Glue.

  
 All the Patent and Popular Medicines, Perfumery, &amp;c.  


 Particular attention to Packing and Shipping.   
 
&gt;First-Class Medicines.Meade &amp; Baker, 


 Pharmaceutists and Vendors of pure and reliable Medicines, Chemicals, Pharmaceutical Products, Surgical Instruments and Appliances; Medicine Chests for plantations, families and travelers; Physicians' Saddle-Bags; London Elastic Stockings, Trusses and Supporters: Porte Monnaies, Combs, Brushes, Toilet Mirrors; first quality Perfumery, Pomades and Soaps; Mineral Waters, bottled at the Springs; Medicinal Wares and Apparatus, Magnetic Machines, &amp;c., &amp;c., all of the best quality and at the lowest rates.

Meade &amp; Baker,  


 186 Main st., corner above Post-Office,  


 Richmond. Va.   
 
Purcell, Ladd &amp; Co.,Druggists, 122 Main street, Corner 13th street, Richmond, Va., 


Offer for sale in quantities to suit purchasers--  


 2,500 lbs. best Indigo, 50 bbls. Burning Fluid,  


 6 hhds. Prime Madder, 50 bbls. Coal Oil,  


 500 kegs Sup. Carb.

Soda, 25 bbls. Sperm Oil,  


 100 cases Sup. Carb.

in 1 lb. 15 bbls. Lard Oil,  


 papers. 4,000 gal. Lamp Oil,  
 25 casks Sal. Soda, 50 bbls. Machine Oil,  


 800 oz. Sulph.

Quinine, 200 cases Sweet Oil,  


 500 kegs Lewis Lead, in 40 bbls. Linseed Oil,  


 Oil, 150 cases Extract Log-  


 2,500 kegs Cream Tartar, wood,  


 100 bags Sifted Pepper, 25 bbls. Spts.

Turpentine.  
 30 bags Allspice,  


 60 bags Ginger, prime, 15 kegs Apto.

Emerys,  


 150 boxes Powdered 2,000 lbs. Ref'd Borax,  


 Spices, pure, 6 bbls. Camphor,  


 35 bbls. Castor Oil, 3,000 lbs. Pure Saltpetre,  


 prime, 25 bbls. Veneti.

Red,  


 25 bbls. Alcohol, 100 boxes Starch,  


 5 tons H H Zinc, in oil, 2,000 boxes French Win-  


 dow Glass, asst.

sizes,  


 With a full stock of other articles, and Patent, Medicines, Fancy Soaps, Perfumeries, Painters' Colors, Brushes, &amp;c., &amp;c., on our usual terms.  


Purcell, Ladd &amp; Co., Druggists,  


 122 Main street, corner 13th.  


 N. B.--Particular and prompt attention to packing and shipping orders.   
 
J. W. FrayserApothecary and Druggist-- 


17th street, between Grace and Broad,  


 Richmond, Va.,  
 Keeps constantly on hand a well-selected stock of Pure and Reliable Drugs, Medicines, Chemicals, Paints, Oils, Dye Stuffs, Window-Glass, Putty, Alcohol, Burning Fluid, Garden Seeds, Perfumery, Soaps, Combs, Brushes of every kind, Tobacco, Snuff and Cigars of various brands, all the popular Patent Medicines of the day — everything, in fact, usually found in Drug Stores-- which will be sold on the most reasonable terms.

Also, Pollard's Nerve and Bone Liniment.  


Physicians and others can rely on having their Prescriptions accurately and carefully compounded, at all hours of the day and night.  


 J. W. Frayser,  
 Apothecary and Druggist,  


 my 11--ts 17th, between Grace and Broad sts.    
 
China, Glass, &amp;c. 
 
&gt;O. B. Taylor, 


 117 Main St.,  


China, Glass and Earthen-Ware.  


 I am now in receipt of my Fail stock of Goods, larger than ever before, embracing nearly every article in my line of business.

I intend competing with the re-packing houses of the North, and will duplicate bills purchased of any of them within the past year.  


 Goods carefully packed and shipped promptly.

A call is respectfully solicited.  


 au 30--2m O. B. T.   
 
Richmond Potteries, 


 foot of Main street, Rocketts, and corner Cary and 12th streets, Richmond, Va. Keesee &amp; Parr, Proprietors.--The subscribers respectfully inform the merchants of Virginia, North Carolina and Tennessee, that they are manufacturing the best quality of Stone-Ware, which they will sell at the very lowest prices, with a liberal discount for cash.  


 All ware sold by us will be delivered in any part of the city free of charge.  


 Thos. W. Keesee,  
 David Parr.   
 
We have some Great bargains again. 


 --look at our Price list.--Clear nice Tumblers from 37 cts. a dozen up; Goblets from $2 a dozen up; Preserve Dishes, 10 cts. and higher, worth a great deal more; Kerosene Lamps from 75 cts. up to some very rich patterns — the best burners out, worth most twice the money; all other Glassware in proportion; Dinner, Tea and Chamber Sets, bought at a great sacrifice from a New York importer, which we offer at an astonishing low figure.

Our Vases, Motto Cups and other Parlor Ornaments defy competition.

Whoever looks at our assortment of Britannia, Albata and Silver-plated Ware, as also Table Cutlery, says that we are hard to beat in that line.

All kinds of House-Furnishing Goods, in Wooden and Willow-ware, Brushes, Tinware, Waiters, Looking-Glasses, (which we make to order, any size required.) besides an immense variety in Fancy Goods and Toys. &amp;c.  


 Schaap &amp; Co., corner Broad and 3d sts.   
 
Just received and opened, Imported expressly for Retail Trade. 


 --We would call the attention of housekeepers and the public generally, to our large stock of fine decorated Maroon and Buff Dinner Sets, Tea Sets, Tete a Tete Sets, Chamber Sets, &amp;c. Also, a large stock of pure white French China, sold by the set or piece; Silver Plated Ware, Castors, Spoons, Forks, Goblets, Pitchers, Silver-Mounted Waiters of all sizes, Candlesticks, Cake Baskets, Card Baskets, &amp;c.--all of direct importation.

For sale very low at  


 Geo. J. Sumner &amp; Co.'S  


 Iron Front Buildings, Governor street.   
 
New Goods of direct importation. 


 --Rich China decorated Dinner Sets, of twenty different patterns; elegantly decorated and plain Tea Sets; White Granite Dinner Ware, Tea Ware and Toilet Ware; Fancy Goods; Rich Plated Ware; Cut and Moulded Glassware, Lamps, Chandeliers; House furnishing Goods; &amp;c.  


 Visitors to the Fair are respectfully solicited to examine our stock, which has been purchased exclusively for cash, and is therefore offered on the most liberal terms,  


 Stebbins, Pullen &amp; Co,  


 101 Broad st., cor. of 9th.   
 
To housekeepers. 


 --By late arrivals, we offer a splendid variety of French Dinner and Tea Sets; White Granite Ware, in sets or single pieces; Fancy Toilet Ware, of new designs; Glass Ware, of every description; Silver-Plated Ware; Ivory Handle and Common Knives and Forks; Bronze Iron Hat Stands; Tea Trays; Britannia Coffee and Tea Urns; O#ster Dishes; Fenders; Fire Irons; Coal Rods, Foot Warmers; Japanned Toilet Ware; Gas Fixtures; Mirrors; together with a magnificent stock of rich Fancy Goods, all of which we offer as low as each goods can be obtained.  


 T. A. Bulkley &amp; Co., 127 Main st.   
 
Portland Syrup; 


 New York do.; Bee Hive do.; for sale by  


 Potts, Farley &amp; Co.     
 
Railroads, Steamboats,&amp;c. 
 
Office Richard &amp;Petersb'g R. R. Co., Richmond, Va., April 2, 1860,April 2, 1860, change of hours. 


 --On and after Monday, the 24 last., the Trains on this rend will run as follows:  


 
 
Trains leave Richmond for Petersburg. 
Express, daily, (except Sundays,) at4.30 A. M.  
Accommodation daily,(except Sundays) at7.00 A. M.  
Mail daily, at2.55 P. M.   


 
 
Trains leave Petersburg for Richmond. 
Express, daily at3.45 A. M.  
Accommodation daily, (except Sundays,) at.7.15 A. M.  
Mail, daily, (except Sundays,) at.5.00 P. M.    


 ap --ts Thos. H. Wynne, Superintendent.   
 
Notice.

1860 
 to Passengers going North.--New Arrangement.--important to Travelers.--through Tickets and through Checks.--Great Northern Route — Carrying the great United States Mail.

Twice daily (Sunday night excepted) between Richmond, Alexandria, Washington, Baltimore, Philadelphia, New York, and all important points West, via Acquia Creek and Washington, over the Richmond, Fredericksburg &amp; Potomac Railroad, to the Potomac river, 75 miles, and by splendid and comfortable steamers thence to Washington; 55 miles, in all 1 miles in seven hours; being a comfortable and perfectly safe rate of speed.  


 Hours of departure: 6:30, A. M., and 7 P. M.  


 baggage, under charge of Special Agents, Checked through to Washington, Baltimore, Philadelphia and New York.  


 Through Tickets can be secured to the following points — viz : Baltimore, Philadelphia, Cincinnati, Columbus, Indianapolis, Cairo, Dayton, Jeffersonville, Rock Island, Zanesville, Washington New York, St. Louis, Chicago, Pittsburgh, Louisville, Decatur, Newark and Vincennes  


 Passengers breakfast and sup at Ashland and dine on board the comfortable steamer between Acquia Creek and Washington.  


 Persons wishing to obtain tickets for servants for Washington city and points further North, must, in all cases, be vouched for by some responsible white citizen of Richmond, in person, known to the officers of the Road, as no Tickets will be sold if applied for by letter.  


 For further information, apply at this offices, Broad street, Shockoe Hill.  


 Jas. B. Winston, Gen'l Ticket Ag't.Samuel Ruth, Sup't.   
 
Virginia Central Railroad.--Fall Arrangement. 


 --On and after Monday, the 1st of October, the Mail and passenger Train will leave Richmond daily, (except Sunday,) at 6:30 A. M., for Staunton and all intermediate way stations, connecting at Gordonsville with the Orange, and Alexandria Railroad Trains for Alexandria and intermediate stations, and at Charlottesville with their trains for Lynchburg and all points West and South-west of that place; and every other day, viz : Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays, for Jackson's River and stations West of Staunton.  


 Harman &amp; Brown's Stages connect with the train at Staunton on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays, and at Goshen on Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays, for Lexington.  


 Harman, Mason &amp; Co.'s Stages connect with the train on Tuesdays. Thursdays and Saturdays, at Millboro', for the Warm Springs; and at Jackson's River, for the White Sulphur Springs, Lewisburg, &amp;c. Returning, the Mail Train leaves Jackson's River on Mondays. Wednesdays and Fridays, at 3:15 P. M for Staunton.  


 A Freight Train, with a passenger car attached, will leave Waynesboro', at 7:45, and Staunton at 9:45 A. M., on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays for Jackson's River.

Returning, leave Jackson's River on Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays at 7:45 A. M., for Waynesboro'.  


 Through tickets for the Warm and White Sulphur Springs, Lexington, Lewisburg, &amp;c.; also, for Winchester, Lynchburg, Bonsack's, Salem, Shawsville, Christiansburg, Bristol, Knoxville, Dalton, , Nashville, Grand Junction, Memphis, Canton, New Orleans, and all important points in the Southwest, can be procured at the ticket office.  


 Oc 1--ts Thos. Dodamead,Gen'l Supt.   
 
Winter Schedule. 


Richmond and York River Railroad.--cheap and Attractive Route from Richmond to Old Point, Norfolk, Portsmouth, Eastern Shore and Matthews.--Fare $2--Breakfast Extra.  


 On an atte Tuesday, Oct. 9th, 1860, passenger trains will leave Richmond daily, (except Sundays,) at 6½ o'clock A. M., on Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays, stopping upon signal only at Meadow, Dispatch, Tunstall's, Cohoke, and Roanoke, and arrive at West Point at 8 A. M.  


 The fast and commodious Steamer West Point, Capt. J. C. Rowe, will leave King and Queen Court House Landing on Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays, at 7 A. M., connecting with the cares at West Point, and stopping upon signals only at Clifton, Water Fence, Shepherd's. Moody's, Cappahoosic, Bigler's, Gloucester Point, Yorktown, and arrive at Old Point at 12:45 P. M. and Norfolk and Portsmouth at 2 P. M.  


 Returning, the Steamer will leave Norfolk and Portsmouth on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays, at 6½ A. M., and Old Point at 7:45 A. M., landing only as above, and connecting with the cars at West Point at 12½ P. M., and arrive in Richmond at 2 P. M.  


 On Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays, the passenger train will leave West Point for Richmond at 9 A. M., and arrive at 11 A. M., stopping only on signals at Roanoke, Sweet Hall, Cohoke, Indian Town, Tunstall's, Dispatch, Meadow and Fair Oaks.  


 Passengers for the Eastern Shore can leave Norfolk on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays by the Steamer Northampton, Capt. McCarrick, and for Matthews Thursdays and Saturdays.  


 
 
 
Fare from Richmond or any point on York River to Eastern Shore$3.50  
To Matthews3.00  
Fare from Richmond to West Point, or West Point to Richmond and return next day2.50   


Freight received Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays until 4 P. M., at Richmond, and on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays until 2 P. M., at West Point.  


 Fare from King and Queen C. H., and other points on Mattaponi River to Norfolk or Richmond, $2.  


 Passengers for Williamsburg will take Stage at Bigler's, for Gloucester C. H., at Cappahoosic, and for Saluda and Urbana, at West Point.  


 Regular Sunday trains will leave Richmond at 8 A. M., and arrive at West Point at 10 A. M., Returning, leave West Point at 4 and arrive in Richmond at 6 P. M.  


 oc 3--ts R. H. Temple, Sup't.   
 
Richmond and Danville Railroad 


 --Express Freight and Accommodation Trains.--On and after Monday, Oct. 1st, an Express, Freight and Accommodation Train will leave Richmond daily (Sundays excepted,) for Lynchburg and intermediate points, leaving Richmond at 4 P. M., and arriving in Lynchburg at 3 A. M., in time to connect with the passenger train going west on the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad.  


 Returning, leave Lynchburg at 7:25 P. M., immediately on the arrival of the train from the west, and arrive in Richmond at 6:10 A. M.  


 se 29--ts C. G. Talcott, Supt.   
 
Travelers to the North.--Northern Central Railway. 1860 


 --Trains leave Calvert Station, Baltimore, daily, (except Sunday,) at 8:30 A. M., and at 5:30 P. M., for Niagara Falls, (fare only ten dollars,) Buffalo, Owego, Oswego, Toronto, Hamilton, all parts of Western New York and Canada, for Detroit, Chicago, Cincinnati, St. Louis, and all parts of the West, Northwest and Southwest.  


Travelers can go to Detroit, Chicago, Milwaukee, &amp;c., via Niagara Falls, at the same cost as by any other route.  


 A new route to New York is now open by this Road, via Harrisburg and Jersey City, with only one change of cars.

Fare $6. Take the 8:30 A. M. train and go through by daylight, over first-class Roads and through a beautiful country.

Try it.  


 Buy tickets only to Baltimore.  


 Jas. C. Clarke, Sup't.  
 John T. Rigney, Assistant Sup't. je 13--1y   
 
Cox's lines. 


 --Freight Boats to Lynchburg three times A week--Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays.  


 Tuesdays and Saturdays.  


 Boat Tempest,Capt.Thos. Emett.  


 Boat Merchant,Capt.Geo. C. Layne.  


 Boat Bristol,Capt.Chas. J. Johnson.  


 Boat J. J. Irby,Capt.Wm. F. Cleveland.  


 Boat Fame,Capt.Wm. H. Parsons.  


 Boat Olivia,Capt.J. J. Peters.  


 These Boats are all of the first class, commanded by careful and experienced Captains, and leave promptly as advertised.

The subscriber thankful for past favors, begs a continuance of the same.  


 Wm. P. Cox. Agent,  


 At the Shed, Dock st., in rear of old Gas Works.   
 
Notice to the public! 


 --New and important Arrangement, 1860.--The Adams Express Company respectfully announce to the public that they have arranged to run their Express Twice Daily from New York, Philadelphia and Baltimore to Richmond, thereby affording unusual facilities for obtaining their freight and packages in the shortest possible time.  


 Expresses leave New York at 1.5 and 6 o'clock P. M. Expresses leave Philadelphia at 8 A. M. and 11 P. M. Expresses leave Baltimore at 4.20 A. M. and 4.20 P. M., arriving in Richmond at 3.30 A. M. and 2 P. M.  


 Expresses leave Richmond for New York, Philadelphia and Baltimore, and all points North and West, at 6.30 A. M. and 6.30 P. M.  


 Freight and packages should in all cases be at our office one hour before the departure of the Trains.  


 Expresses for the South leave Richmond Twice Daily, at 4.30 A. M. and 2.45 P. M.  


 The Adams Express Company feel that they can guarantee to the public civility, attention and satisfaction in all their intercourse with their officers in Richmond, and nothing will be left undone on their part to meet the wants of their customers.  


 Freight and packages arriving by the Express from the North at 3 o'clock P. M will be delivered immediately, there by giving to our customers an advance of twelve hours over our arrangements heretofore.  


 Steamer Expresses, to and from New York, Semi-Weekly.

Freights delivered immediately upon the arrival of the ship.  


 Heavy and light Freights, packages, money, Bonds, Legal Documents, &amp;c., forwarded with safety and dispatch to all parts of the United States, Canada and Europe.  


 notes Drafts and Bills, with or without Goods, collected at all accessible points throughout the United States, and prompt returns guarantee.  


 Slaves forwarded by each of our Expresses, in charge of careful and reliable messengers.  


 Tobacco and other samples carried at unusual low rates.  


 All freights promptly called for and delivered without extra charge.  


 For Further information, please call at our office, 202 Main street.  


 "Adams Express Company."  


 au 7--ts W. H. Trego, Sup't.   
 
The Ashland Hotel. 


 --This popular resort, situated sixteen miles from Richmond, in the beautiful and thriving village of Ashland, on the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad, is now open for visitors, and is prepared to accommodate families with good fare, and everything desirable.

The head of the family will be furnished with a Free Ticket between Ashland and Richmond.  


 For further information, apply at Superintendent's office Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad, or address  


 Jno. L. Thompson, Proprietor,  


 tv 7--ts Ashland, Va.   
 
Cheese 


 --Goshen and English Dairy, carefully selected, for sale by  


 John N. Gordon &amp; Son.       
